{"data": [{"question": "Can you tell me anything about The Hand of Odd, other than that it is a multi-player game that is coming out after Munch’s Oddysee?", "answer": "Hand of Odd is about us using the technology of Munch, enhancing upon it, and bringing it into the multiplayer world of gaming. How many players will be able to interact at one time is still yet to be determined. If we can get 8 players at one time for Hand of Odd we will be happy. It will be enough. If we can get more we will be ecstatic. Hand of Odd will not be an online community in the way that Everquest or Ultima Online are. But we do plan to take advantage of features like downloadable units that will help to keep the world fresh even after it’s been out there awhile. Our most important function will be speed. We’ll take advantage of as much as we can until update rates become an issue. There as so many questions that relate to the multiplayer Internet capabilities that are yet to be answered technically, that we can’t lock down to the degree that we would like yet. ", "tags": ["Munch", "Hand of Odd"]},

{"question": "What can you tell us about the story and gameplay of Hand of Odd? ", "answer": "Think eco-extremists versus corporate greed. It’s Exxon vs. Greenpeace and you get to choose which one you want to be. There are three sides, or ideologies, wrapped into one playing field. You will be able to choose between one of three master characters for three different races. Each of these three characters will have the ability to control masses of their own kind. Each of the three has interests that conflict with the others. It can be played competitively, or cooperatively, or you can just exist and experiment while nurturing a particular world. You may choose to have full-scale conflicts, or just make a lot of moolah via destroying it. We are also out for something that can be left on and grow while you’re not even home. We’re after fully persistent universes that have a life of their own. Eco-system simulation is a big part of the next level for the Oddworld games. We really want you to take ownership of the world, and then deal with the inevitabilities that arise out of your behavior of your forces. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will you ever develop games for Macintosh? Dreamcast?", "answer": "There are currently no concrete plans to do so, but if it makes sense to us in the future we certainly will. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What will the PC requirements be for Munch’s Oddysee?", "answer": "At this time, it is too soon to be determined. We still won’t know for a few months. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Are you still planning on coming out with an Oddworld movie?", "answer": "We see the five stories of the epic of the Oddworld Quintology eventually becoming five motion pictures. However, there is no rush for us to produce the feature films. They may happen sooner than later, but we won’t compromise game development just to make movies. The game medium is too important to us. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Why did Abe go from having four fingers in the Abe’s Oddysee to having three in Abe’s Exoddus?", "answer": "Well, it’s a long story that needs to be told. So here it is… Japan has a strict discriminating policy against any simulated characters entering their country with four fingers. Historically, Japan has had a subclass of meatpacking workers that were typically looked down upon in their society. In later days, the blatant displaying of a four-fingered hand gesture, intentionally directed at another, came to mean that you were calling them a member of the meatpacking subclass. Which, we understand, was not at all a compliment. It appears that the four finger connection with the meat packing class was due to work-related accidents, but was so frequent that it came to symbolically represent the sub-class. It seems as though this is a part of the Japanese history that some groups within Japan would like to see forgotten. Therefore, it is at great risk that you publish four-fingered characters in Japan, as you may very likely end up in legal battles with a vociferous pressure group. This group claims that this type of representation is equivalent to and as degrading as the yellow star forced to be worn on Jews by the Nazi’s during the Second World War.That is, it’s offensive and degrading unless they can extort enough money out of you. Then it’s all okay. Case in point: We were told that the Walt Disney Corporation is charged five million dollars a year by this group so that Mickey Mouse may live in Japan and retain his original four fingered design. Otherwise, old Mickey would need to see a surgeon and have something done about that insulting forth finger. The moral of this story is… if you want to pay, then it’s ok. If you don’t want to pay, then it’s a horrible insult to our culture. In other parts of the world, we have a word for these types of two-faced tactics. We call it extortion. If it is truly offensive and degrading, then don’t allow it at all. But to allow it for a price… is to belittle the case altogether. It suggests that the real truth behind these groups is that they are using the darker moments in their own cultures’ history as an excuse to coerce money out of content providers. Well, being that this is Oddworld, we felt that this seemed like a perfect addition to the Abe story. We thought it was ironically perfect that he was being discriminated against for being who he was. As the message came from Japan, “They don’t like his kind here,” with the sincere suggestion, “Just chop off one of his fingers cause you don’t have the money to pay up…” caused us to feel that we indeed needed to allow Abe to go through the suffering that goes along with being a poor slob at the bottom of the Food chain. Yup, we chopped off his finger so that the Japanese wouldn’t get offended (or paid). He didn’t like it one bit, but due to the fact that there ain’t much he can do about it… we decided that he could donate his finger rather than us donating five million dollars. Such is life in Japan when you’re a four-fingered meatpacking worker. And that is how Abe lost his finger in Japan. He’s still pretty pissed off about it, but we convinced him that with the amount of games sold in Japan, he still might be able to get his message through to their culture someday. As a true believer in his cause, he felt that the sacrifice of a finger was but a small price to pay in hoping to shed some light on discriminations and injustices the world over. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Can you tell me what Lorne Lanning’s email address is so I can write him?", "answer": "No, we really can’t give that out. Lorne is a very busy man spending up to 80 hours a week creating the Oddworld games, and although he would love to respond to everyone, he doesn’t have the time. Most of the fan mail does come his way though, so he does read your encouraging words and sees the great fan art. This is what reminds him and all of us at Oddworld that all the hard work is definitely worth the effort. So, keep the letters and art coming! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I love all the artwork and renders on the site and in the games, does Oddworld have any plans to bring out an art book? I know several people who would buy one instantly!", "answer": "But do you know anyone besides the mothers of the OW staff that would buy one, too? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I have always wondered why Abe never cut the stitches from his mouth? I mean I can understand in Abe’s Oddysee but after he got out of RuptureFarms why didn’t he get someone to give him the snip? ", "answer": "Abe says the stitches are both a reminder and a badge of honor. Me, I think he’s been hit in the head too much. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "I have been reading through fact files of Abe, and it says he has no…manhood. HOWEVER, in Abe’s Exoddus, when he is shot out of the mines, he lands on a kind of pole. He acts as though he busted his u-know-what. Why??? ", "answer": "It’s not the size; it’s the motion. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "And since Abe has no sexual organs, does it mean Abe isn’t male or female? Why does Abe wear a loincloth then?", "answer": "Because otherwise, he couldn’t justify wearing a belt. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What I actually want to know is what part of your odd universe will become open to us in Munch’s Oddysee? ", "answer": "In Munch’s Oddysee you’re going to be seeing a lot of the Vykkers and their weird way of doing business. While the Glukkons were the natural resource barons of Mudos, the Vykkers are the scientists and doctors. The Vykkers have impeccable credentials, but are seriously lacking in any spiritual wisdom. They’re like those classic Harvard PHD’s that then go off to be vicious third world dictators or researchers for tobacco companies. Geographically speaking, the Oddworld Quintology takes place in the territory of Mudos. As we get closer to the end of the Quintology we get closer and closer to the heart of consumerism; which means the more densely populated areas of Mudos. For Munch’s Oddysee we’ll be visiting several places that we’ve yet to see before. Many of which are various types of factories scattered across the landscape. ", "tags": ["Mudos", "Glukkon", "Vykker", "Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Please.. gimme more info on the species of Oddworld (the ones coming out in Munch’s Oddysee). Oddworld Inhabitants still haven’t filled the ‘Oddworld Universe’ section up with ALL the characters. Like Queen Maggie, Khanzumers, Queen Skillya & Interns. ", "answer": "Well, the Interns are these kinda dopey guys with heads shaped like canoes. They file stuff, and kind of hover around. They’re a low-grade pain in the neck. The only thing I’ll say about Queen Margaret is that nobody—and I do mean NOBODY—calls her “Maggie” to her face. Not more than once, anyways. ", "tags": ["Margaret"]},

{"question": "How many employees at Oddworld Inhabitants sold their soul to the devil in exchange for this beauty? ", "answer": "We’ve had a full team of programmers working on this engine for a long time. It started with a tremendous amount of time being spent designing it on paper and working with the game design team to make sure we were building something truly special. We’ve also been working with an out of house team of programmers that build core technology (not a game company). When the game is fully running we’ll be talking more about this other team, but not before. The images that you see are really a result of an extremely talented real-time art team that is here at Oddworld. The databases that they’ve built have, in many ways, driven part of what the technological performances of the engine need to be. Always, the balance between art and programming is critical. The best engine in the world can easily look lousy if there are not creative artists building databases for it and constantly trying to push the image quality. The technology development for Munch’s Oddysee is the backbone for many games that Oddworld will build over the next several years. Squeek’s Oddysee will also benefit from this technology. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee", "Squeek"]},

{"question": "Fleeches have two heads, correct? And Slurgs eat Fleech dung, right? So my question is, if Fleeches don’t have an (ahem) anus, then where does the excrement that the Slurgs eat come from? Does one head puke, or what?", "answer": "I sent a guy to find out, but he never came back. Tell you what: if you get close enough to a Fleech to solve this one, let me know. ", "tags": ["Fleech"]},

{"question": "Who is Squeek? What kind of creature is it? ", "answer": "I can’t tell you. But I can give you a hint. It’s nothing you’ve seen before, and also nothing you haven’t seen before. Nyah-nyah! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Can you tell us more about the Khanzumers?", "answer": "Sure! But we don’t want to spoil the suprise and show much of the characters (species) that have yet to appear in games. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Yo, in Oddworld do you guyz listen to music like rock or rap?", "answer": "We can’t hear music over all the screaming. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "We were brave enough to visit RuptureFarms and feel the smell of Paramite pies, enter SoulStorm Brewery and drink a brew made of bones. What gourmet food or drink are we supposed to taste now? ", "answer": "The more games we get the scarier food or drinks become. Sometimes reality is far more strange than fiction. Processed food is definately one of these examples. We love using food as the backbone to reveal the corruption and greed of some of the forces of Oddworld. It’s very reflective of what’s happening today on earth. For Munch’s Oddysee there are a lot of new food items coming. There is Gabbiar, which is a delicacy of Gabbit Eggs (Munch is a Gabbit), there are Blitzpacker, Lungbuster, and Snuzi firearms… there are also Stoggies (cigars) and other goodies. Many of these new products will be in factories that you’ll have to deal with in the game. But this time, factories are something that are much more interactive than the backdrops that they’ve been for us in the past. This time you’ll be able to load a factory up with workers (or empty it of workers) and get it to actually start making goods and profit. ", "tags": ["Gabbit", "Munch’s Oddysee", "Munch"]},

{"question": "Will a Meech ever be shown in Oddworld like a flashback or anything? ", "answer": "I heard a rumor about a pack of Meeches being discovered on a lost plateau, but the Glukkons scooped ’em up and dumped ’em into one of their hunting preserves. There may be more, but I’m not sure. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "Does Shrykull appear in Munch’s Oddysee? ", "answer": "Oh, yes, and all sorts of other Mojo Mayhem, too! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "When can I expect to see the PC version of Munch’s Oddysee in the stores?", "answer": "We are currently concentrating on the Xbox version. It is yet to be determined if there will be a PC version. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will we be able to revisit some of the places Abe has been in Munch’s Oddysee? Are all those screens of the forest area Paramonia? Plus, can we go see the ruins of some of the factories Abe blew up?? ", "answer": "A return to the ruins of Rupture Farms figures in Munch’s Oddysee. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "I heard that in Munch’s Oddysee that Abe and Munch can travel together or seperately. What happens to Munch if Abe has to go on a solo mission? Does he just sit there, or start acting on his own?? ", "answer": "Munch is a very young creature, only recently reintroduced to the world after long confinement inside Vykkers Labs. Leave him alone and he has a tendency to hunker down and wait for someone to come get him. ", "tags": ["Munch", "Vykker"]},

{"question": "Whatever happened to SligStorm? I’d heard it was going to star an albino Slig larva, and run on the Abe’s Exoddus engine. I know it’s been scrapped, but why? Can you tell s’more details about it?", "answer": "SligStorm was briefly considered as a Playstation game, but publishing plans are always in flux, and we elected not to pursue that particular project. The SligStorm concept remains on our drawing boards and may see the light of day … and sooner than you expect. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Will there be a temple for Scrabs or Paramites or something like that? ", "answer": "Not in Munch’s Oddysee, no. But there will be plenty of new native structures that you’ve never seen before. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Is the sound team planning on putting some more-appeasing-to-the-teens kind of songs, or are you guys going to stick to the classic majestic feeling of Abe’s Oddysee and Exoddus? ", "answer": "Oddworld’s musical style is a signature element of the series, and I don’t anticipate it will change any time soon. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Why is Abe blue? ", "answer": "He’s depressed. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "In Abe’s Exoddus, who is the guy that is locked all alone in the brewery that gives Abe the power to heal the three he frees from the tear extractor?", "answer": "There are helper Mudokons scattered all through the Abe adventures. They’re friends of BigFace. ", "tags": ["Mudokon", "Abe"]},

{"question": "The Oddworld Universe has amazing images. Who does the art, who draws and paints these masterpieces? Also, I’ve noticed that in many pictures a Mudokon is holding a spear. Was this an early addition to the game, or just an artist’s conception?", "answer": "Oddworld has a staff of very talented Production Designers responsible for creating the Oddworld Universe the old fashion way (pencils, paints & paper)! The Mudokon-with-spear was early conceptual art, and never appeared in a game. ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "I read that the planet of Oddworld is ten times as big as Earth and that all the action has taken place in the region of Mudos. Will other regions be revealed in Munch’s Oddysee?", "answer": "The action of Munch’s Oddysee remains in Mudos … but you haven’t yet seen even a fraction of Mudos, let alone other areas of the world that will appear in future Quintology titles. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee", "Mudos"]},

{"question": "I was wondering on Oddworld if there are casinos, clubs, and amusement parks? I also want to know what type of religion does each species have? Also, you are sooo cute Alf!!!!", "answer": "The Glukkons love casinos, clubs, and amusement parks, and we have tentative plans to feature such venues in Munch’s Exoddus. As far as religion goes … well, Glukkons worship Moolah, while Mudokons keep their religious feelings to themselves. ", "tags": ["Mudokon", "Glukkon", "Munch"]},

{"question": "In Abe’s Exoddus(PC), the credits have a movie-like picture with mudokons all wired up to these “devices” by their feet. Is this a movie that I missed, or is it a cut-scene from Munch’s Oddysee? ", "answer": "Not sure, but it sure sounds like you missed the Bad Ending where Abe gets his butt fried! ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "What kind of role do vehicles play in Munch’s Oddysee? Are there any water-based vehicles, like boats and stuff? I’d also like to know if I get to control that awe inspiring blimp I’ve seen pictures of?", "answer": "We’re still evaluating the role of vehicles in Munch’s Oddysee. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Will the Munch’s Oddysee environments be more Outside or Inside? Will there be more small buildings, like guard towers or little homes? Or large buildings, like factories and stations? ", "answer": "All of the above! We have massive, sprawling indoor environments, and we also have smaller guard towers and such dotting our outdoor landscapes. We’re shooting for a balance of indoor and outdoor experiences. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I would seriously like to know how large the worlds will be in Munch’s Oddysee? Everquest size? Mario64? ", "answer": "We’re still exploring the maximum sustainable size for our outdoor areas. We feel there isn’t much point in having super-large areas if there isn’t anything to do in them. There are trade-offs involved between the size of areas, the number of characters in those areas, the complexity of the environments, the presence of facilities, etc. We haven’t quite yet arrived at the magic formula that will let us answer your question, but we’re getting close! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Does Abe get any new tattoos in Munch’s Oddysee? What about Munch, will he get tattoos or any more electronic equipment?", "answer": "Abe is a supporting character in Munch’s Oddysee, and he doesn’t go on the sort of quest that awards new tattoos. Munch does evolve over the course of the story, but his evolution has more to do with what he learns about himself and his race than any external change. Tattoos aren’t really Munch’s thing, but you never know … ", "tags": ["Abe", "Munch’s Oddysee", "Munch"]},

{"question": "What is the utility of the thing that Munch has in his head? ", "answer": "The jack in Munch’s head was installed by deranged Vykkers scientists for twisted reasons of their own. Little did they realize that Munch would find a way to use his jack to control robots, vehicles, and other machines. ", "tags": ["Munch", "Vykker"]},

{"question": "I heard that Mullock is coming back in Munch’s Oddysee and that you visit Rupture Farms…is this true? ", "answer": "I can neither confirm nor deny a role for Mollock in Munch’s Oddysee. A return to RuptureFarms does presently figure in the game. ", "tags": ["RuptureFarms", "Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Will Bigface appear in Munch’s Oddysee? Will Abe disappear in the next game (Munch’s Exoddus)? ", "answer": "Because this story is about Munch, Big Face does not appear (Bigface is Abe’s mentor). In many ways, Abe has moved beyond what Big Face can teach him, which is one of the reasons the Almighty Raisin chooses this time to reveal himself to our heroes. And don’t worry – Abe’s story is far from over. He isn’t going anywhere soon. An interesting evaluation, and largely accurate. Most of the working class that you mention live in Oddworld’s cities, which have yet to be seen … and those details will have to wait for a future game. You should also realize that the classes you mention aren’t monolithic. That is to say, while the majority of Sligs are part of a low paid soldier class, there are also middle-class Sligs. Likewise, not all Mudokons are slaves. Additionally, there are internal markets in each of the classes you mention … just because many Mudokons are part of a slave class doesn’t mean they aren’t enthusiastic consumers of Paramite Pies. Even Mudokon slaves have some discretionary bonus income to spend (earned for meeting production quotas, or snitching out their fellow slaves). ", "tags": ["Munch", "Raisin", "Mudokon", "Abe", "Slig", "Paramite", "Big Face"]},

{"question": "With businesses such as Rupture Farms and Soul Storm Brew, who exactly do the $$$-hungry Glukkons sell these products to? ", "answer": "Anyone and everyone! The Magog Cartel is always looking for new markets to exploit. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "In Munch’s Oddysee, will you show the different forms of Mudokons? Or Sligs in their many stages of life?", "answer": "You will certainly see a new twist on Sligs. We’re still working on some surprises for Mudokons. ", "tags": ["Slig", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "How come Sligs and Glukkons never come close to the Scrabs, Paramites, or Fleeches, even just by chance? I would want to see the outcome if they did…", "answer": "In our first two games, this was entirely due to memory constraints on the Playstation. Our characters are so rich and so detailed that you can’t have more than a few of them on screen at the same time. We really had to jump through hoops to get as much stuff on the screen as we did … every time you move from one screen to the next, the code is busily swapping stuff in and out in the background. It’s almost like pouring water from a gallon jug, into a cup, then into another gallon jug, over and over again, without spilling a drop in the meantime. Quite a challenge! We trust that our new platform will permit us to work with a broader canvas of characters, although machines being what they are, I’m sure we’ll still be doing all sorts of wizardry in the background to deliver the most exciting game experience possible. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How did the Sligs get their pants? Did they build them themselves, or did the Glukkons make them? (and if the Glukkons did, they would have to sit a bit away from the work area because the length of their arms, wouldn’t they?)", "answer": "Most of the weird technology you see on Oddworld is derived, directly or indirectly, from the twisted experiments at Vykkers Labs. ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "If the Glukkons (or Sligs) can make pants for the Sligs, then why don’t they make pants for themselves?", "answer": "Please! No self-respecting Glukkon would be caught dead tottering about on a gauche set of mechanical legs! ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "I was wondering, since Sligs are first born with an urge to nurture and this instinct is later beaten out of them, is there a chance that we will ever encounter “nice” Sligs?", "answer": "Nice tendencies are ruthlessly sought out and eliminated in Sligs at a very early age … but you never know. A grub here or there might slip through the system. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Alf, do you play a role in Munch’s Oddysee?", "answer": "I’ll be all around in the dark. I’ll be everywhere, wherever you can look. Wherever there’s a fight so hungry people can eat, I’ll be there. Wherever there’s a Slig beatin’ up a guy, I’ll be there. I’ll be in the way guys yell when they’re mad. I’ll be in the way kids laugh when they’re hungry and they know supper’s ready and where people are eatin’ the stuff they raise and livin’ in the houses they build. I’ll be there, too. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "I was wondering why Abe was the chosen one to help free all the Mudokens?…I mean he’s really clumsy and stupid.", "answer": "Odd works in mysterious ways. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "In Munch’s Oddysee, in the Vykkers labs can the player interact with all the specimens in the cages that the Vykkers are experimenting on (i.e. let them out and make them attack Sligs, etc.)?", "answer": "Munch can build a little army with all the Fuzzles he releases in Vykkers Labs. ", "tags": ["Vykker", "Munch"]},

{"question": "In Munch’s Oddysee, will Abe and the various other characters have an extended “Gamespeak?” Will Abe also have different Mystical Tattoos? If so, what do they do?", "answer": "GameSpeak has been both extended and simplified for Munch’s Oddysee, and plays a pivotal role in the game. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "What does SoulStorm Brew taste like?", "answer": "Don’t ask me about Brew! I’m still tryin’ to forget! Man, one is too many, and a million’s not enough! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I remember a guardian angel in an FMV for the first game. It also appears now in the Oddworld Universe section of the website. What relevance does it have to the game? Will the guardian angel appear in Munch’s Oddysee?", "answer": "The Shrink, as he is now known, was originally part of an early concept for a television ad for Abe’s Oddysee. Nothing goes to waste here at Oddworld, so I’m sure you’ll see the Shrink in a game sooner or later. ", "tags": ["Abe’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "I was wondering, in some of the Abe’s Exoddus pictures with the Mudokons hanging upside down on the ‘tear thing’, their loin clothes are staying up? How can that be?", "answer": "Censor’s Glue. It’s the same thing that keeps Xena’s skirt in place. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "After the 5th game of the Oddworld Quintology, will there be something else in store for us Oddworld fans, or is that the end forever?", "answer": "I’m sure we’ll continue to make Oddworld games as long as we draw breath (provided they put work stations in rest homes and insane asylums). ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I heard that Oddworld Inhabitants will make a Squeek’s Oddysee. What can you tell me about it?", "answer": "Only that it is indeed scheduled to be a Quintology title, and that it’s top secret. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What happened to the Oddworld store with all the cool Oddworld Merchandise?", "answer": "Unfortunately our store had to close due to our change of publishers. We hope to re-open someday. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Can Munch talk and if so will it be the same as Abe?", "answer": "Munch speaks, he is a simpler creature than Abe, and his speech is simpler, as well. ", "tags": ["Abe", "Munch"]},

{"question": "I was wondering, since Munch is the last of his species, how will he reproduce without others of his species? Does he even need another Gabbit to reproduce? Is he a hermaphrodite or something? ", "answer": "One word: Gabbiar! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Are there going to be any babies in Oddworld Munch’s Oddysee like baby elums, scrabs, paramites or any other babies? ", "answer": "Not in Munch’s Oddysee, but various Oddworld grubs may feature in future games. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Can you in Munch’s Oddysee morph into the sligs , scrabs ,… like in Abe’s Oddysee and Abe’s Exoddus ? ", "answer": "If by “morph” you mean “possess”, then yes. If by “morph” you mean “change into the Shyrkull,” then maybe. If by “morph” you mean “Murph,” the guy who works at the filling station, then I can’t help you. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Are there females of your kind? Please answer the questions and keep up the good work and keep it ODD 😉 ", "answer": "Our Queens are female. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "You still haven’t replied to my last message and I’m getting a little pissed off. I live in Sydney, Australia and I’m wondering when Munch’s Oddysee will be released here. Could you tell me? ", "answer": "Sorry mate! I’m doing my best to find out for you but we just don’t know yet. Don’t look for Munch to be in the Outback until 2002. When they tell me, I’ll let ya know. G’day! ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "Did Oddworld Inhabitants create an Oddworld movie yet? If someone can please send information if you can. I am obsessed with Oddworld. and I think that Oddworld Inhabitants should make a movie. tell me what website I could by the movie at if possible. it would make my dreams come true.", "answer": "A theatrical short subject was composed by drawing images from Oddworld: Abe’s Exoddus and connecting them together with some original bridging material. The film was screened for a short time in October 1998, Los Angeles, California. It may or may not be made available through other venues in the future. ", "tags": ["Abe’s Exoddus"]},

{"question": "How Do Paramites, Scrabs, and fleeches see? They all don’t have Eyes.", "answer": "There are alternative means of “seeing”, echolocation, for one. Plus, just because you can’t see a set of eyes doesn’t mean they aren’t there, somewhere … ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Are there poor Glukkons?", "answer": "There are quite a few disgraced Glukkons who have gone for broke and leveraged themselves into poverty É most have the dignity to do away with themselves, but there are a sad few who hang on at the bottom of the corporate ladder, a disgrace to their betters and a target of derision for the masses. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "Who are Interns?", "answer": "Surgically prevented from whistling while they work, Interns are finger-pointing finks who enforce Vykker regulations with a song in their heart and a pill on their lips. When not pilfering from medicine cabinets, these sleep-deprived, self-important slaves yearn for the latest in fashion swimwear, punk rock, and designer pharmaceuticals. ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "How much is Quintology (I didn’t found in any dictionary) ?", "answer": "My dictionary defines Quintology as “what you say when ‘quintet’ doesn’t sound cool enough.” ", "tags": []},

{"question": "When will Hand of ODD will be released?", "answer": "Sometime in the future. We are concentrating on Munch right now. After Munch I’d like to add a den and redo the kitchen at Alf’s Rehab & Tea, learn how to fly fish, then think about Hand of Odd. ", "tags": ["Munch", "Hand of Odd"]},

{"question": "Is Alf’s Rehab & Tea a separate game or part of Munch’s Oddysee?", "answer": "It is a location on Oddworld that will be featured in many of our games. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "You mean to tell me that all Mudokons, Glukkons, and Sligs come from their own queen? So, you have never experienced the joys of love and sex. I pity you!", "answer": "Thank you, Mr. T. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How come Abe is blue and you, along with all the other Mudokons, are green?", "answer": "It either has something to do with my diet, or it’s a bit of dramatic license to help Abe stand out from the rest of us… ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "What will happen if both Paramites and Scrabs meet?", "answer": "On your old Playstation, there would be a memory overflow causing the game to crash. In Munch’s Oddysee, you can expect a vicious Inhabitant hoedown! ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Man! I just looked at the munch demo video off fileplanet… it’s amazing! i love it, the camera zooms in on the back of munch’s skull and i still can’t detect a pixel. How often do you think you’ll be posting new videos on your site as the release date nears? ", "answer": "As often as we can spare time from preparing the game to post things to the site. Keep checking What’s New. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How big are the characters in Oddworld compared to humans?", "answer": "Abe is roughly human-sized – you can extrapolate from there. Check out the chart above. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "The Oddworld games are the best games ever made. I have finished them all in everyway. When I heard Munch’s Oddysee was coming out for PS2, I scrambled to get one. Now the game moves to XBox. In your Mission Statement, it says that you people want to get Oddworld into every home. How will that be possible for PS2 owners? ", "answer": "The same way that it will be possible for Dreamcast or Nintendo owners: by buying an Xbox. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I’m very disappointed right about now its been called to my attention that I haven’t seen or heard anything about those loveable creatures the slogs. Please say they aren’t gone and don’t you dare say the fleeches have taken there place. Please don’t disappoint us! ", "answer": "Fear not! Slogs are already in the game, running about, barking, eating Sligs, getting chopped up in recyclers, they’ll definitely be on hand when the game is released! ", "tags": ["Slog", "Slig"]},

{"question": "I am making a model of munch but I can’t do the back part of him could you send me a back front and side picture of munch I am SORRY I am bugging you but please alf, I’m your biggest fan. ", "answer": "What some people won’t do for a butt shot of Munch! OK – here you go! (See above pop up image) ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "When Molluck loses his clothes does he have has 2 big arms or 2 big legs because they only show it for a second I know that there are 2 small ones. ", "answer": "Glukkons walk on their hands. Their legs are vestigial. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf ,will there be any Mudokon freeing in Munch’s Oddysee?", "answer": "Absolutely! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Can you please tell who or what is The Magog Cartel?", "answer": "The Magog Cartel is an association of Moolah-mad capitalists bent on the mercantile conquest of Oddworld. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Is it pronounced as “Munch” as in *The sound of someone eating*, or “Munch” as what it may be pronounced in German with a bit of the short *oo* sound? ", "answer": "It depends on whether or not a German is saying it. Note, also, that Latamire Munch is not to be confused with Edvard Munch, the Norwegian painter known for his evocative treatments of psychological themes and for his influence on the development of 20th century German Expressionism. ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "There was a question on “nice” sligs. Well, if “A grub here or there manages to slip through the ‘system'”, who would care for it? Sligs are born without legs yes? If growning up from grubs (?) and walking with their hands, would they develop arms like the Glukkons? (Keeping in mind the “pants-spoiled” Sligs drag themselves- they didn’t grow up developing “their” arms) ", "answer": "Like many wild animals, Slig grubs are born into the world fully equipped to survive on their own. They only need caregivers for political indoctrination, and while mechanical pants are nice, Sligs have survived for generations without them. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "In Abe’s Exoddus, Elum isn’t in the game! I was shocked! What happened to him, and is he in Munch’s Oddysee? ", "answer": "On the Playstation, Elum was an expensive character (memory-wise) for what he brought to the game, so he didn’t make an appearance in Abe’s Exoddus. We still plan for Elum to appear in Munch’s Oddysee. ", "tags": ["Abe’s Exoddus", "Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "What about Habitales and Farietales series?", "answer": "What about them?   – The End ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Glukkons® walk on their hands which suggests to me that they either have very little legs or no legs at all. This has led me to conclude that if a Glukkon is by itself it has no way to defend itself, which made me wonder: How could the Glukkons persuade the sligs and the slig queen to work for them in the first place?", "answer": "Moolah. Power. Pants. Take your pick. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How did Abe® come across his name? I’ll guess that the Glukkons wouldn’t waste their “valuable” time naming their slaves, so who did? Did the Mudokon Queen Sam name him at birth, and if so how did he remember it?", "answer": "Mudokons name each other. It’s a lot less confusing that saying, “Hey, you!” all the time. ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Alf, are you an ex-RuptureFarms-slave saved by Abe or were you a wild Mudokon who joined him on the quest for Necrum? ", "answer": "I wish I knew. Thanks to my SoulStorm® Brew addiction, I have these …uh … blackouts. Sometimes I just forget what…uh forget … What was the question, again? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Speaking of names, do Sligs have names? If so, who names them? If not, are they identified by numbers (like all the fan-fiction writers seem to believe)?", "answer": "Yes, Sligs have names. They earn them in the crche, after graduating from Slaughter School. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "What are rats? What are Sea Rexes? What are Mudflubs? ", "answer": "Various Oddworld animals that you’ll see in Munch’s Oddysee and other future games. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Why do you torture us by not explaining anything clearly?? ", "answer": "www.springfield-il.com/kids/8ball/8_ball ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I wonder a thing about the movie or/and the picture when you see Mudokons riding on some Elums, what are they doing? Are they hunting? If they are hunting then what do they hunt? Mudokons have to eat something! ", "answer": "Mudokons have used Elums for generations for all manner of work: hunting, traveling, scouting. As far as what we hunt…well, anything we can get! ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Will Munch be in a wheelchair throughout the whole game? If so then how does he jump and what kind of view do you get, is it like Abe’s Exoddus?", "answer": "Munch can get in and out of his chair. He’s awkward on land, so the chair helps him travel rapidly over flat surfaces. ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "Why is Abe’s mouth stitched up, all the other Mudukons’ mouths aren’t? ", "answer": "Abe’s lips were stitched up to keep him from chanting. It didn’t work, and Abe could have removed his stitches a long time ago, but he keeps them as a reminder of what he once was, and what awaits us all if he fails. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "What does Bigface look like?", "answer": "No one has ever seen him without his mask. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Who is the Mudokon named “Sam” and what connections does he have with the Oddworld Quintology? ", "answer": "“He” is a “she,” and you’ll find out in Munch’s Oddysee. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Could the “aliens” that capture Munch when he is stuck in a bear trap possibly be humans? ", "answer": "Not unless humans are using Vykkers technology. ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "Will the “meeches” shown in the Abe’s Exoddus starting fmv on a poster labeled “extinct” ever resurface in a later game? ", "answer": "I wouldn’t bet against it. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Does Oddworld: Munch’s Oddysee have bosses? Will Munch and Abe fight the Glukkon queen? ", "answer": "Queen Margaret would never sink so low. ", "tags": ["Margaret"]},

{"question": "Will there be a game without Abe? Will there be a game that goes back to when the Meeches were around?", "answer": "At one point “Hand of Odd®” was going to be set in Oddworld’s past, before Abe’s birth … and we might explore Oddworld’s past some time in the future. But right now, as in the past, we’re concentrating on the future. Past results, however, are no indication of future performance. Consult your broker before investing in this or any other fund. ", "tags": ["Hand of Odd", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf, what’re the chances of Abe’s Oddysee and Exoddus being re-released for Xbox? You know, all-on-one-disc-for-a-budget-price kinda thing? Go on! Please? ", "answer": "The chances of seeing such a thing are extremely remote, as platform differences between the Xbox and the original PlayStation are so great that we’d pretty much have to re-do the games from scratch. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I would like to know how far the emotion engine goes in the means of helping out hope-shattered slaves. I mean, will it be much more of a caring, nurturing thing when you meet up with a beaten Mudokon, or, and I mean these words, will it be more of a pat on the shoulder, a quick “sorry,” and “ok” response, then the Mudokon follows you? I hate to say it, but the situations I described that appeared in Exoddus seemed soul-less & empty. That’s not really what happens, which made it kind of unrealistic. Know what I mean?", "answer": "Well, I know that Abe was the first guy that ever spared a kind word for little ol’ me. A little kindness goes a long way when you’re a slave, and I know a lot of the guys feel the same way. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Hey, Alf, in Munch’s Oddysee will be able to control Mudokons with Vykkers.", "answer": "Vykkers can’t control Mudokons. At least, I hope they can’t. Yipes! ", "tags": ["Vykker", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Abe’s Exoddus was Abe’s Odyssee’s bonus game. Will Hand of Odd be Munch’s Odyssee’s bonus game or will there be a Munch’s Exoddus? ", "answer": "No, Hand of Odd is an entirely separate concept. The bonus game for Munch will be Munch’s Exoddus. ", "tags": ["Hand of Odd", "Munch"]},

{"question": "Yo, did the Vykkers scientists saw their own feet off or something? They have stitched up stumps. ", "answer": "Or something. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will we be seeing any appearances by any of the “extinct” races of Oddworld, like some secrete secluded area where meeches still thrive? ", "answer": "Oddworld is a big place, so you never know… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I thought Scrabs were solitary creatures that hated each other; so why are there cinematics on the site in which you see Scrabs in herds?", "answer": "The Scrabs you saw in past games were “Alpha Scrabs”- rogue males that can’t stand the sight of other Alpha Scrabs. Long confinement in stockyards and ancient temples had made them a bit cranky. In Munch’s Oddysee, you’ll see Scrabs as they live in the wild with a single Alpha Scrab at the head of a heard of lesser Scrabs. They’re still pretty cranky, though. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee", "Scrab"]},

{"question": "Will there ever be Slig without its mask in Munch’s Oddysee? Will we ever see what they look like without a mask on?", "answer": "Ugh! Why would you want to see such a thing? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi, Alf. Slurgs eat Fleech offal, right? Offal is not poop, so why does everybody seem to act as if it is?", "answer": "It’s all the same when it’s stuck to your shoe. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Are Glukkons and Sligs related biologically/evolutionary speaking? What about Elums and interns? ", "answer": "You’ve got some strange notions, son! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Does the Almighty Raisin belong to a species? ", "answer": "No one knows. The Almighty Raisin is an enigma. ", "tags": ["Raisin"]},

{"question": "If some Sligs are fairly wealthy, and some Glukkons are really poor, then could a Slig buy a Glukkon slave? ", "answer": "A Glukkon would sell his own heart before allowing such a thing. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "Did RuptureFarms make food out of Elums?", "answer": "Some of the guys remember seeing a skinned Elum hanging around the place, so, yeah, they probably did. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Who produces the punk rock the interns listen to?", "answer": "Punk rockers. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How do greeters balance? ", "answer": "Pretty darn well, I’d say! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will there ever be a film about Oddworld? ", "answer": "Absolutely. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What’s the average yearly rainfall in Oddworld?", "answer": "On average, the water falls down, and hits the ground. Sometimes it goes up, but not so often. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What sports do free Mudokons play?", "answer": "Me an’ Buddy play hackey-sack every now and then. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Who was the fattest person and how heavy? ", "answer": "According to the Guinness Book of World Records, the heaviest man of all time was the late Jon Brower Minnoch, who was just a Meech Munchy shy of weighing 975 pounds. ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "Are you a virgin? ", "answer": "Hold on a second…uh…ok…no, not anymore. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "After looking over the skull schematic of a Mudokon, I couldn’t help noticing that there appeared to be the Mudokon’s long lost nostrils at the top of its head. Alf, is that where your nostrils are located? ", "answer": "Are you a Vykker? ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "The same skull picture showed the distinctive lack of teeth. I believe it was said that Mudokons evolve from birds. Do Mudokons have a beak behind their lips? Is their jaw strength stronger or weaker due to this feature? Could a Mudokon potentially bite someone and actually be effective? ", "answer": "You ARE a Vykker! ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "How do Glukkons sleep? Do they rest on their forearms, sleep standing up, or lay down on couch/hammock/bed/etc.?", "answer": "Give me back my skull, and we’ll talk. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Abe is 15, and Munch is 18. How old are they in human years?", "answer": "I dunno. What’s a “human?” ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Glukkons have small eyes, which are very sensitive to the light, does this mean you can blind them by smashing windows to make sunlight come through? ", "answer": "I’ve never tried it. Glukkons do seem to like gloomy places, but that might just be their nature. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "Will you be able to talk to Interns and help Interns get what they want from life? ", "answer": "You can talk to Interns, but they can’t hear you over that infernal racket coming from their headphones. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I heard that you will be able to make the profit makers of the game bankrupt by stealing their credit cards, is this be true? ", "answer": "I’ll have to try that the next time our publishers visit the office. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "When the Quintology is over on Oddworld, will you be going to a different world?", "answer": "No one’s mentioned anything to me. Do you think I should pack a bag? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How many endings will they be to Munch’s Oddysee, please make at least four endings!!! ", "answer": "I’d like to see a dozen, just so long as they’re all happy endings. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How many endings were there in Abe’s Exoddus, I got the bad ending and the good but if you saved all 300 do you get a third?", "answer": "There’s a little bonus recognition for being perfect. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Is the Oddworld team still going to include lethal weaponry or only non-lethal like the Blitz-Packer??", "answer": "Yes! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Since there’s money involved in Munch’s Oddysee, will you be able to buy stuff, like clothes? ", "answer": "What’s “money?” Is it anything like Moolah? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "was reading in a book and came across a section that explained the color and meaning of auras. The text reads: “A stong presence of red indicates a willfull personality; it may signify selfishness, physical strength, or powers of leadership. Green is the color of nature and healing, but may reveal a deceitful character. Orange is an indicator of physical health. A strong yellow presence reveals intellectual abilities. Blue refers to one’s religious or spiritual state: the deeper the blue, the more enlightened the individual. Black is the color of death, malice, or evil. And gray indicates a depressed or melancholy personality.” -From ‘Facts and Fallacies’ by Reader’s Digest. This made me wonder about the color of Mudokons. Was this the inspiration for their colors? Blue, green (and I think I’ve seen orange somewhere, but I could be wrong!). Thank you for your time. ", "answer": "Uh … I dunno about auras, and all that. We’re just the colors that we are. Some of the guys have auras after drinking too much SoulStorm® Brew, but I think that’s something different. The End…whew! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hiya Alf! Why does Abe keep bumping his head? ", "answer": "Hello. I’m not sure why Abe bumps his head. Sometimes I see him eating paint chips. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "I was wondering if you could add a web poll to your site? Also, what do (or did) Meeches look like? ", "answer": "I’ll see what I can do about the web poll. I have personally never seen a Meech, either first hand or in photographs. Some say they looked like small hairy pancakes that left trails of sticky mucous on the ground. Legend has it that on any given day, one could witness swarms of Meeches squirming by the millions over the placid fields of Mudos. ", "tags": ["Mudos"]},

{"question": "Is it hard being an inhabitant? Was Abe the only one that can transform to Shrykull?", "answer": "I’ve got a 47-inch waistline; does my physique suggest to you that it is hard being an Inhabitant? I could do the Shrykull thing if I really wanted to, I just don’t want to. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Yo, can you send me some fan equipment man?", "answer": "Dear Sir, unfortunately we do not include gold chains, spoke rims, or handguns in our line of merchandise. In addition, our distribution network does not extend to your part of “da hood” (i.e. your parent’s basement in the suburbs), so we would be unable to fulfill your order. Seriously, look for stuff in the fall when the game is released. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Why does Abe not get sick when he drinks the SoulStorm™ Brew?", "answer": "Evidently, he has built up some sort of resistance to the stuff. You know, each time it takes a little bit more to get the same effect. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey, would you Mudokons get severely punished if you pulled off BigFace’s mask? Do you know what’s under his mask? ", "answer": "Punished? Please! He only wears that thing for the girls. He thinks it makes him “mysterious” or something. I’ve seen what he looks like underneath. Two words – buck teeth. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Are you guys going to make an Oddworld: Munch’s Oddysee soundtrack? ", "answer": "Well, I’m not sure about that, but if we don’t… I’m in this band and we’re trying to cut an album and we’re really good and I play the drums sometimes well mostly I play the tambourine but we’re really good and we’re going to cut an album and you can buy that instead! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Is Paul O’Connor still writing the Munch’s Oddysee designer diaries?", "answer": "Look for Paul’s next installment of the “Passport to Oddworld” feature on the Microsoft Games website around e3 time. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Are the Interns pot-bellied from a vitamin deficiency through lack of eating or do they just look that way? ", "answer": "The Interns lead a sedentary lifestyle. They have gradually developed a body type known as “the melted candle” whereby deposits of supple fatty tissue ooze down around their midsection. This phenomenon is common among those who sit day in and day out in front of a computer terminal, eating and working, working and eating. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What is a Meep? Is it that one-eyed creature?", "answer": "Correct. The taste reminds one of chicken, but with a subtle hint of the sea. Just kidding! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "In Munch’s Oddysee, do Abe’s eyes move around? In the recent bunch of screenshots for MO, Abe seems to be sort of staring into space. The Sligs and Munch look awesome, but Abe looks. . . well, sort of stupid. Please explain. ", "answer": "You are, of course, entitled to your opinion. Your obvious lack of training in the studies of anatomy and simple common sense serves to explain your comments. Abe’s eye sockets are of the rotator cup variety, which allow him to swivel his eyes in virtually any direction, much like a chameleon. If you saw him “staring into space”, it may have simply been that he felt your gaze and chose to ignore you by focusing on a distant object. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "What’s up with Mudokons’ body? I can understand you’re thin when you’re slaves, but free Mudokons also look anorexic! ", "answer": "What is this sick pre-occupation with body-types? Is this what modern media has done to our youth? Listen, if you are overweight and feel a certain jealousy toward the slim figure of a Mudokon, that is a problem that you yourself must deal with. ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "The only Mudokon names I’ve seen are Abe and Alf. I was wondering are there Mudokons that have female names? ", "answer": "Well let’s see …I’m not good with names, but there’s Pat, Chris, and Cory. (Insert more androgynous names here). I once knew a guy who had some sort of operation done and thereafter called himself “Linda”, but I suppose that doesn’t count. Not really! I’m just feeling feisty. Look for Sam the Mudokon Queen to make her debut in Munch’s Oddysee. Don’t ask me any questions about her because I can’t answer them. You just gotta be patient. ", "tags": ["Mudokon", "Munch’s Oddysee", "Sam"]},

{"question": "In the first two games of Oddworld, can Sligs tell if other Sligs are possessed? Any time I possess one and say hi to another, they reply, and then blow me away. ", "answer": "When Abe was first starting out, he didn’t have good control over his powers. When he’d possess a Slig, the Slig would be all glassy eyed, and stumble around like a zombie. It wasn’t very convincing. He’s gotten much better lately, as you’ll see. ", "tags": ["Abe", "Slig"]},

{"question": "Why is it that Abe has to die in the bad ending? All the time you play, you grow more respect for the little guy. Then, at the end, he gets sliced into bite-sized chunks. Surely Mudokons are more forgiving than that! ", "answer": "It’s not so much forgiveness, as rescuing Abe from the clutches of Molluck the Glukkon wasn’t an easy thing. Especially when you don’t have many lives, rescued mudokons to work with. Chanting like that to create a rescue portal takes years off your life. ", "tags": ["Abe", "Molluck", "Glukkon"]},

{"question": "What do you have to do to get a good ending anyway? ", "answer": "Rescue enough guys so that they’ll rescue you back. I forget the exact numbers, maybe half of the totals. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi, Alf. I’ve got some questions for you here (yes, more). I’ve kept them as Universal as I can think them to be, so I hope you don’t spot any that are really “knucklehead.” Why is that Slig wearing a dress on the right of the Land Muggers picture? ", "answer": "That is a game show host (ess). Since all sligs are male (except the queen, and she’s as big as a house literally) that has to be a guy slig in a dress. He’s following in the fine tradition of Milton Berle and Monty Python and Ru Paul. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Do Gabbits build things underwater? ", "answer": "Not that I know of. Gabbits are more like otters, just living their lives in nature. ", "tags": ["Gabbit"]},

{"question": "Why were there no Bats, Bees or Fireflies in Abe’s Exoddus? Will they be returning in Munch’s Oddysee or later games? ", "answer": "We have so many new and wonderful things coming along for the future, that you’ll scarcely notice the bats and bees and fireflies. Big things, swell things, things that’ll make you run crying to Mommy. You’ll be stopping strangers on the street and saying “Hey, buddy, you gotta see this…” ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I’m sure someone has asked this before, but I couldn’t find that any one did. What is the ending like if you save all 300 Mudokons in Abe’s Exoddus? And what is the ending like if you save all 99 Mudokons in Abe’s Oddysee? Please give me a good answer. ", "answer": "Good question! If you saved all 300 Mudokons in Exoddus and all 99 Mudokons in Oddysee you basically rock, dude. The ending is Good. Check out the Forums for help. ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Alf Please answer my question (I can’t wait any longer)! Tell me about the Glukkon “Lulu”. ", "answer": "Think of LuLu as a bumbling hotshot Vegas type rockstar with more style than brains. Yeah! Almost like real rock stars! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "C’mon guys! I’ve been waiting for the icons and wallpaper for months! Oh, and some screensavers, too, would be lovely. So how about it, MAKE WIT DA GOODS! PRONTO!", "answer": "Now this is feedback I can use! Let me make a note here, let’s see…”Call the folks in production and tell them to stop wasting their time on all of these games”. People are sick of games… what people want are screensavers and icons! Wow, that was close. You know, there were tentative plans for icons and such a little later on, but thanks to you, we can now redirect our efforts towards making this company an icon-producing machine such as the world has never seen! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "You know that Shrink guy (The Magog Cartel Health Bloke), in the Oddworld universe industrial characters bit of the web site it says that he has a track going along the ceiling so he can move. I’m wondering, can he go on trains and stuff to get to other facilities, or is he disconnected then put back on in the other facilities?", "answer": "That sort of thinking doesn’t work here, kid. Sure you could stick him up on the train tracks and shoot him off somewhere else, but who pays for it all? You’ve got transportation fees, rail tolls and cargo taxes…then there’s the land barons, franchise owners and port supervisors who always take their cut. Much simpler and far cheaper to just junk the old one and build a new one somewhere else. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "At what resolution will Oddworld games run on the Xbox?", "answer": "Our resolution will be the same it has always been, to make the very best games out there! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I was wondering why you torture us by never answering any questions completely, and why your answers seem to never follow the whole Oddworld atmosphere?", "answer": "Well, there’s a good reason for this, you see…(burp!)… oh man, big breakfast today. Hey, has anybody seen that movie Cool Hand Luke where that guy eats all those eggs? That’s what I feel like right now. Man, I gotta start cutting back. Anyway, what was the question? Ah well, let’s move on shall we? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Do Sligs live in the factories or do they get to go home?", "answer": "Sligs are like butterflies in that they live short and meaningless lives and their very existence is like a pox on the land. They reach maturity quickly and are immediately assigned to their posts throughout the industrial empires. They stay on duty 24 hours a day until they simply collapse. Their limp bodies are then thrown into the recyclers, converted to a brownish, energy-rich sludge which is served as a delightful lunch ration in cafeterias everywhere. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Munch broke his leg in a bear trap right, does that mean there are bears on Oddworld? ", "answer": "Bears? Jeez, I guess there could be bears. You’re right, I mean why would someone lay a bear trap if there were no bears? It’s ridiculous! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Are there Mudokon and Glukkon drones who sit around doing nothing in the hope of some day “getting lucky” with the queen? ", "answer": "In this case, use of the term “getting lucky” may not exactly be appropriate as the queens are essentially enormous sacks of fat rolls, covered in sweaty lumps, hair and weeping glands. I doubt any drone would consider himself lucky in the face of such a revolting task. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Why have the Sligs eyes changed? In Abe’s Oddysee the Sligs had a visor sort of thing going across their face, and in Exoddus they have proper eyes. Please explain.", "answer": "The Slig suicide rate soared during the time those visors were issued. Sligs began walking off high ledges and stumbling into bone-crunching machinery more and more often. Studies showed that those first visors had a small optical misalignment that caused the wearer’s eyes to become crossed. Vykkers scientists quickly modified the equipment and Slig suicides have subsequently evened out. ", "tags": ["Slig", "Vykker"]},

{"question": "I saw in the movies that Abe could pick up Sligs from the back. Can you ask Abe about any other abilities he has picked up or learned from his mentors? Perhaps anything heroic or daring? ", "answer": "Why doesn’t anyone ever ask me about my heroics? Oh well, hold on a second… “Hey Abe, this person wants to know what new skills you’ve learned!” He’s thinking. You know, I can do this thing with my armpit…oh, hold on again. “Why is everyone laughing?” Oh, heh heh, he farted. Well, I guess that’s a skill. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Should the Fleeches be counted as “wildlife?” They were created by Vykkers.", "answer": "What sort of nonsense is this? Fleeches are most definitely a creature indigenous to Oddworld, almost as old as the world itself and may certainly be counted as “wildlife”. You must be confused. ", "tags": ["Fleech"]},

{"question": "What is an Oddworld rat? ", "answer": "A filthy, detestable little creature, found by the billions in the underground sewer networks. It can be a delicacy however, when roasted and served with a light mustard sauce. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Do Mudokons have teeth? I’m personally stumped on this one. ", "answer": "Of course! Though in addition to teeth, we have a sort of “gizzard” that further breaks down food. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Why do Abe and other Mudokons wear “skirts?” ", "answer": "Are your powers of deductive reasoning really that poor? Surely you can come up with the answer on your own. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Is the bird mask that Big Face wears suppose to be the head of the creature that Mudokons supposedly evolved from? ", "answer": "Good heavens, where do you kids come up with this stuff? Has Big Face been spouting his crazy talk again? As far as I know, he picked it up at an old junk shop in exchange for some comic books. ", "tags": ["Big Face"]},

{"question": "Can you tell us some interesting facts about Paramites that you know and we don’t?", "answer": "Well, if you scratch them in just the right place, they do this really cute kicking thing with their hind leg. Of course that’s just before they turn on you and rip you limb from limb. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What did Vykkers and Interns look like before their (obvious) operations? (stitches around the limbs, etc.) Will we see what they looked like? I mean, just because they’re Vykkers, doesn’t mean they ALL are in the medical profession. ", "answer": "They look pretty much like you see. The limb replacements are just to get better limbs than those that they had. Vykkers, like Glukkons, don’t take very good care of their bodies, and need constant replacement parts. As for profession, Vykkers aren’t all doctors, they’re all researchers. Some do medical research, finding new uses for helpless animals, or new addictive substances to add to the food. Others invent new kinds of noxious industrial chemicals, or cheaper ways to suck the value out of the land. ", "tags": ["Vykker", "Glukkon"]},

{"question": "I know Glukkons “worship” Power and Moolah, (and I suspect most everyone else does too), but I mean OTHER than Power and Moolah is there a religion on Mudos? Or are there several? ", "answer": "Each species has its own main religion. Mudokons (at least the natives) revere harmony with nature. Glukkons worship Moolah, as you guessed. Sligs think that meanness is divine. Vykkers believe that knowledge (especially the dangerous kind) is king. ", "tags": ["Slig", "Vykker", "Glukkon", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "I was wondering why Sligs always obey the Glukkons? They have machine guns and grenades to they can easily destroy them, and the Glukkons don’t have any arms. ", "answer": "O, how I wish it was that easy. Problem is, the Glukkons control the moolah. Sure, you can blow the blowhards to smithereens, but then you don’t get paid at the end of a week. If you don’t get paid, you can’t buy more ammo, or gas for your pants. (Did you know these pants are gas powered?) And if there’s one thing every slig learns, it’s don’t get caught without pants or ammo. We all just love to beat on the dopes who do, and even mudokons will sometimes beat up a pantsless slig. How embarrassing is that? ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "What’s up with the ever-changing Munch logo? First it’s the needles and stuff one and now it’s a soda can. What the heck?! ", "answer": "Shucks. We’re just keeping you on your toes out there. Our fearless leader is always dreaming up new things. The logo changes you see are the merest tip of that iceberg of wonder. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Have you ever encountered a Fleech? I just wanted a humorous answer. ", "answer": "I have not but I know a Slig who has. Crig? Crig the Slig:  Sure, once. It all happened back during Abe’s Exoddus. I was working an outside patrol back then, and I spotted Abe one night. He was too far to shoot, and I would have just left him, but there was a reward, and I really wanted that new BlastMaster 350 dual-barrel alternating machine rifle. It’s so sweet. Anyway, I chased him through the gloom until I stumbled into a pit of Fleeches! Stupid of me, I know, but I was dreaming of that BlastMaster and how it’d make me big slig in the barracks. Instead, I was pants deep in hungry mouths with grippy tongues. Good thing I had my gun (don’t leave home without it). I opened fire on the little monsters, and I got most of them before the last one sucked me in. By the time I had fired my way out, it ate my arm off; that’s why they call me “lefty”. But I was lucky; you should talk to “no-nose” if you want to hear a real sad story. ", "tags": ["Abe’s Exoddus", "Abe", "Slig", "Fleech"]},

{"question": "Do the Scrabs in the Mudanchee vault try to eat you because they’ve been in there for years, do all the Scrabs eat you guys, or is Abe either at the bottom of the food chain or just so darn tasty?", "answer": "Hmph, now that’s an interesting thought. I wonder what we do taste like. I mean, Molluck’s entire corporation went to the mat tryin’ to make ol’ Abe into an entree, and them Scrabs’ll punch a hole through a landwhale if they think there’s one of us on the other side… Tell ya what, I’ll take up biting my fingernails, and let you know my findings. ", "tags": ["Molluck", "Abe", "Scrab"]},

{"question": "Hey dude, I wanted to ask you a question. Is there any Mudokon women out there in Oddworld? How the heck do these creatures reproduce, man? Do you know any other Oddworld fans who have an AOL screen name?", "answer": "If you haven’t seen any of Oddworld’s women yet, you must not be looking! And good for you at that… Odd knows ever since I caught a glimpse of ’em, I’ve tried mighty hard not to look. …yech. *shivers* And if you’re having trouble finding other Oddworld fans, try throwing a brick. Or swinging a cat. The little buggers are all over the place; they must be, what with the number of letters I gotta answer… razza-frazzin’ no good… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Why does Abe loose his tattoos between Abe’s Oddysee and Abe’s Exoddus?", "answer": "Last time I was playing jacks with Abe, he still had them tattoos on his hands… and a darn good thing. He’d never have made it outta the brewery if he hadn’t been able to call up the power of the Shrykull once or twice when he got into a pinch. Next thing you know the little punk will spike his hair or get his lips pierced. Uh. Again, that is. You know what I mean. Eh, next question. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Is it true that you will be able to load up your Mudokon friends with blitzpackers, snuzis, and tomahawks and send them on rampages through factories. Or are these special power-ups for sligs and other creatures only? And When you posses a slig can you go to a vending machine and get power ups like the super bounce and other armnants. PLEASE REPLY!", "answer": "Don’t you get snippy with me there, youngster! Remember, I’m a recovering substance abuser, I could snap at any moment!! It’s little ragamuffins like you that’re driving this whole oddworld into the- huh? My editor is gesturing frantically at me… Right, right, sorry, I do believe it’s time for my medicine. *gulp gulp gulp* Whoo, that herbal chamomile stuff sure hits the spot. Okay… right… count to ten… Okay. If you gave one of these Mudokon chumps around here a Blitzpacker or a Snuzi, he’d probably use it for a fencepost, or a headdress ornament, or a garden hoe. We’re just not that sharp with technology. Conversely, give a slig one of our tomahawks and he’d probably be squished under it’s weight. You seen the skinny little sissy arms them fellas have? As for vending machines, well, sure, maybe you could buy an instrument of mass destruction or two, but then if I had Moolah to burn and vending machines about, I’d buy the sauce. I mean, that’s what those machines are best for, getting blotto right quick- Huh? What? Right, sorry, more medicine… *gulp gulp gulp* ahhhhhh… ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "I can’t believe that you Mudokons are sooo corrupt! All the new movies and trailers are all supported by Microsoft/Windows media programs! What happened to all the QuickTime goodness!? Did Bill Gates hand u some Moolah under the table? Or did he hand it to the Glukkons and they screwed everything up?!", "answer": "Uh oh… Uh… Yeah, that second one you said. The one about the Glukkons? Yeah. They’re responsible for it, they always are! Those Glukkon creeps! We’re innocent, we were just following orders! We did NOT have monetary relations with that man! ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "I was wondering. Since there is a queen for each of the races on Oddworld. Is there a slog queen? ", "answer": "There must be. I bet the Glukkons have her stashed somewhere where they can make obscene profits off her babies. That’s so like them ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "What’s your take on linear games vs. non-linear games. Do you think it’s possible to have a non-linear game with a solid story? Which type of game will Munch be?", "answer": "There’s a place for linear and non-linear play in any kind of game. Munch’s Oddysee does have an overall direction, but within each ‘level’ the play is wide open. We found that that gave us the kind of freedom for the players and let us keep the story on track. You can have story in a non-linear game, but we found that the story either didn’t follow the in-game action, or we didn’t always get the story we wanted to tell. We kept the broad structure of Munch linear so we could tell exactly the story we wanted and get the emotional impact we were looking for. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee", "Munch"]},

{"question": "I’ve always wondered why Mudokon’s mouths are ‘sewn’ together. If the Glukkons wanted them to shut up, it didn’t work very well. They should’ve stapled them. 🙂 Why does Abe have stitched lips?", "answer": "Well, they worked pretty well at first, but Glukkons aren’t much for long-term thinking or quality control. With the headlock they have on management on Oddworld, they don’t really have to be. So, after a while, the stitches get loose, and Abe and the other workers can talk again, some. ", "tags": ["Glukkon", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf, why is there a crater on the Oddworld moon that is the shape of a Mudokon hand? ", "answer": "I dunno. I always wonder why my hand looks like that shape on the moon. Maybe someday we’ll find out. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Do the organisms of Oddworld have common names and scientific names? If so what are they?", "answer": "Only the Vykkers would know that, and I’m not getting close enuf to them to ask. ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "Hey, I was wondering if you could give me some information on the Almighty Raisin?", "answer": "The Raisin has four eyes and they glow a bright yellow. He is quite large so he can only move very slowly and has labored breathing. His skin is like the bark of a tree mixed with a raisin and it’s purplish brown. He is wise and all knowing but often tires and falls asleep in mid sentence. He is the guide for Abe and Munch through the game and tells them what they have to find and do to achieve their different goals. ", "tags": ["Munch", "Abe", "Raisin"]},

{"question": "What do the Mudokons eat? They all seem to have a slight gas problem. Is it just something they do to pass time? Or do they agree with me about Madonna? ", "answer": "It’s not the eats that do it to us, it’s the drink, the Brew, the juice, the sauce, the hair-o-the-slog-that-ripped-your-leg-off-so-now-everybody-gave-you-the-nickname-‘Pogo-Boy’. That Brew will get you tooting like a souzaphone, but if you’re drinking that sweet, sweet- er, horrible, nasty, addictive stuff, then passing time or gas was the least of your worries. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Listen is there some way to get the music of the game from somewhere cuz its so cool? I love hearing that music but I don’t know from where to download it. ", "answer": "You’re a person of discerning taste, you are. None of the new-fangled be-bop for you, just the pure, motivational stylings of the RuptureFarms PA system, eh? Well, after a quick glance on the Alfabetizer (my state of the art super-computer… it’s kind of like that big evil MCP computer in ‘TRON’, but without the lasers or diabolical sentience… I use it most of the time to play Minesweeper), I couldn’t find much of anything in the way of stylish Oddworld tunes, either. Come down to the rehab center sometime with a tape recorder and we’ll all hum a few bars for ya to tide you over. ", "tags": ["RuptureFarms"]},

{"question": "I know you probably are going to tell me that you can’t legally tell me but I want to know how I can change some of the sounds in Oddworld: Abe’s Exoddus specifically the background noise so I can shove some teen music in there (Oddworld has a great soundtrack please don’t be offended!) ", "answer": "I would never tell you something like that! What I will tell you is to lose that teeny-bopper crap yer listening to. Land sakes, the things that pass for music these days woulda caused folks in my day to hold their nose just in case a foul smell was short in coming… Get yerself some Grass Roots, or The Platters… you know, they did that one that went “Smoke… Gets… In… Your….. EEEEEEEYYYYYYYEEEEEESSSSSS-HACK ACK *cough cough wheeze*”… eh… whoo… and so forth. Then we’ll talk. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Do Glukkons like to be tickled behind their ears? I’ve been toying with this notion for quite a while now. ", "answer": "Would you say that the majority of the notions that you toy with are of a similar subject matter and caliber as this one? If so, well, whatever mows your lawn, I guess, though you might want to consider therapy… me personally, I wouldn’t know; I wouldn’t touch a Glukkon’s skin with a hunnerd’n eighty foot I-beam even while schnockered. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "Best Odd Munck wen it going to bi rilist in Belgie? Plz enser alf plz! ", "answer": "Maak je geen zorgen, Munch komt naar Nederland in 2002. Groetjes, Alf. ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "I was wondering why fleeches and slurgs work together. It’s like they are twins!", "answer": "I dunno if I’d call that ‘working together’, buddy. Think about it… if every time somebody stepped on you and smashed you into a pile of goo, a pizza was delivered to your next door neighbor… would you say that the two of you are working together? If so, you might wanna renegotiate your end of the bargain. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Is it possible to make food that looks just like Scrab Cakes and Paramite Pies?", "answer": "Hey, throw enough food-coloring, lipstick, or concentrated laundry bleach into a recipe, and you could get it to look like just about anything! But sadly, the taste, well, there’s nothing like the real thing. Ah- not that I’d eat Scrab Cakes or Paramite Pies, being made from them endangered critters and all. I could do that. But that would be wrong. ", "tags": ["Paramite", "Scrab"]},

{"question": "I heard that a Meeches’ favorite prey is an Elum. Is this true?", "answer": "Chicks dig Elum. Not Meeches. ‘Sides, I can’t imagine how they could’ve preyed upon something as stupid as Elums and still managed to get their dumb selves extinctified. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What happened to Elum? Did he go to another planet or what?", "answer": "You ever seen that episode of Winnie The Pooh where the bear got his head lodged inside a beehive filled with honey? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Everyone knows that Scrabs can’t stand each other, so what’s with the “Large Scrab Herd” video?", "answer": "Uh. They’re Union Scrabs? I dunno, YOU go ask’em… maybe if yer real polite they won’t accidentally knock you over and tear you to shreds first. Me, I’ll be happy to just smile and nod at whatever they show on the Oddworld Nature Channel. ", "tags": ["Scrab"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf, well me and my brothers have completed the games on Playstation it ripped. Well I’m 13 and my brothers are 16 and 19 and I want to know how much will the Xbox cost and I wanna tell U I love Scrabs they are cool I even did a project on Oddworld so U can tell I”m pretty obsessed. This is what I really wanna know will it be 3D like can you only walk straight or on a diagonal and can you please answer me Alf and what will you not be able to take over in Munch’s Oddysee. ", "answer": "Well thank ya much- er, 16 and 19 you sa- um, I think it cost- Hey, look, slow dow- scrabs? I just said I’m not gonna- Project? What ki- AGH, darn right you’re obs- Eh, what’s 3D- Gah, I walk anywhere I wan- MOLLOCK ON A MOPED, SLOW DOWN KID!!! Good Odd Almighty, there are states where it’s a felony to have a run-on sentence that long!! I was just waitin’ for you to throw in “And one time? At band camp?” somewhere. Okay. Now. Lemme see… Thanks; 35,299 Moolah here (dunno the Moolah-to-dollar conversion, sorry kid); yer obsessed alright; what’s this 3D techno-jibba-jabba?; and… can I walk straight?!! Listen kid, I got put in rehab so I wouldn’t have to answer questions like that again!! I just had a couple after work to take the edge off, I promis- … whoa. Okay, maybe time for the next question… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "If most of the prominent Oddworldian species breed like hive insects (that is, with a single Queen producing hordes of sterile workers) and the Mudokon Queen, Sam, is in a Glukkon facility, then how are the free-born Mudokon born in the first place?", "answer": "Hmm… is that where I came from? My foster slig always told me he found me underneath a dew-covered Spooce Shrub on a sunny spring day. I always thought it sounded kinda romanticized… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "In Munch’s Oddysee, is Abe going to have another “special ability” from a tattoo or something similar like the Shrykull and Mudokon healing tattoos?", "answer": "The last two times Abe called everybody out saying he’d acquired a new power, they turned out to be card tricks. I don’t even bother to check anymore. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Can you maybe send me a complete list of the Mudokon language? ", "answer": "Write me up an English dictionary in your free time and I’ll swap ya. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Is BlitzPacker Brew the same as SoulStorm Brew, or is it a competing brand, or what? If it’s difference, what is it made of (as compared to SoulStorm being bones and tears)", "answer": "I think BlitzPacker Brew comes in a special, heavier can, so it’ll leave bigger dents in things it’s shot at, ya know, like walls, our skulls, etc. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Abe blew up SoulStorm Brewery, right? Why is it that those cannon-toting vending machines fire SoulStorm Brew then? Is there more than one brewery? ", "answer": "You think if we blew up one brewery on your planet that beer would cease to exist? Here on Oddworld, there’s a simple rule… if it turns a profit, you can bet yer ponytail there’ll be more’n one of ’em… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will there ever be an evolutionary chain picture of how Oddworld’s creatures came to be? ", "answer": "Yeah, I seen you people’s idea of evolution. Everytime I try and picture a hunchbacked, overmuscled Mudokon with extra hair toting an enormous club over his shoulder, I gotta start laughin- huh? Whozere? Oh, ah, heh heh, hiya Tom. No, no no no, I wasn’t talkin’ about you or any of the other Tomahawkers… yeah, go on back outside. Right, so, um… what were we talking about? ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf, I was wondering…in Munch’s Oddysee when U rescue the Fuzzles do they follow you the rest of the game, or do they leave after a while?", "answer": "Munch considered the viability of a legion of the little critters at his beck and call ’till we had him watch that Star Trek episode about Tribbles. Since then he’s been pretty keen on just getting them free from their cages, into a rescue portal, and out of his sight. ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "Do Gabbits not have a Queen cuz most others do and if they don’t are they asexual?", "answer": "Munch don’t know, and Munch don’t wanna know. Think about his situation, after all… if he pulls of this caper and gets that Gabbiar, he’ll have saved his race, sure. But then when all those baby Gabbits start asking ‘Where did we come from?’ he either has to make something up, or else say “Well, a can, actually.” Even if Munch had somebody to ask, I think he’d be afraid to for getting a similar answer. ", "tags": ["Gabbit", "Munch"]},

{"question": "Where did you get the name Exoddus from? Did you get it from the Bible because there’s a book in the bible called “Exodus”?", "answer": "I think that Lorne guy read it off of a Successories poster in a mall and thought it sounded cool. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf! Where the heck do you live? I mean, so you live on a drifting continent? What does your planet look like? I would like to know. It’s o.k. if you don’t know. ", "answer": "I’m glad you gave me that out there at the end; I was gonna be having major fits of introspection about my self-worth if I got this wrong. At a guess, I’m gonna say it looks round and bumpy. With, you know, bits of blue, brown, and green spots, like an overripe Spooce Shrub or something. Fact is, I don’t know. You gotta get pretty far away from a planet to be able to tell what it looks like. Munch might’ve gotten a good look when he plummeted out of the Lab, but I think he was a bit distracted by shrieking “I’M GONNA DIEEEE!!!!!!” at the top of his lungs at the time. ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "What is the Brewmaster Glukkon’s real name? I refuse to believe that his name actually is “Brewmaster”. ", "answer": "Hey, he’s one of the lucky ones. Just imagine how Gas Station Attendant Glukkon feels… he can’t even get his whole name onto a loan application. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "On Munch’s Oddysee, a creature’s appearance changes depending on status or health, right? In this magazine article I saw a “Slig Health chart” that showed increasing amounts of injury like casts and crutches and stuff. In the same article there was also a “Slig Status Chart” where a slig was shown with increasing amounts of armor and firepower. Also, the article quoted Lorne Lanning talking about socially contorted GameSpeak, where a mid-status creature would speak insultingly to his inferiors, normally to his equals, and subserviently to his superiors. Did all this awesome stuff make it into the game?! ", "answer": "Hey yeah, I saw some of those sligs walkin’ around in wierd-lookin’ suits of platemail… I thought they were having a Ren Fest or something. Don’t count on seeing any slig in a cast, though. A slig in a cast is a slig on sick leave, and a slig on sick leave is a liability that his boss would just as soon recycle as let heal. And if you want socially contorted gamespeak, step on down to my little rehab center sometime. Where the tea flows like brew, the brew don’t flow at all, and the conversation’ll make a sailor blush. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "When characters are damaged in Munch’s Oddysee, will they show signs of injury? For instance, say Abe wandered where he shouldn’t again and was shot. Even if he’s only holding onto life by a thread, will he still be able to run and jump at his maximum potential, or will he be forced to hobble around at a horrendously reduced speed? Just wondering. ", "answer": "That’s one of the things that didn’t make the cut for this game. Look for some kind of visible damage in Munch 2. We have really cool concept art on one or our conference room walls. Right now, the thinking in the designers’ dungeon is that slowing down abe or munch when they hurt isn’t much fun, but they’ve changed their minds before… ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "Helloooooooo! Were there any sligs who were friends with you and Abe? ", "answer": "Once there was a slig named Wildum who was kind of a nice guy to me and Abe. He didn’t beat us, and he’d even let us have a drink, if we brought him one, too. The other sligs found out, and they beat him to death with his own arms. It was horrible. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "I was wondering if the Big Brother Sligs crawl around on their hands like other sligs do? ", "answer": "I dunno but back by popular demand is Crig the Slig to answer all those Slig related questions. Crig is a freelance writer for the Daily Deception. Crig:   Well, once they finish their hormone treatments (to make them all big and musclebound) they can’t actually get out of their big pants any more, so they don’t take them off at night or for repair like a regular Slig. But if you can wreck the pants, I’m sure they’ll crawl like anyone else — right over to you and squish your head like a grape. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Will we ever see a Slig without a mask? ", "answer": "Crig:   Pray you don’t. Your eyes will melt in their sockets and your brain will explode. We are UGLY. Uglier than your kid sister. Uglier than … words fail me. Even we don’t like to look at us; that’s how ugly we are. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How smart are Sligs in comparision to Glukkons, Interns and Vykkers? ", "answer": "Crig:   Well, we think we’re the smartest, cause we get to shoot the guns and bombs. Glukkons think they’re smart, cause they get most of the Moolah and the good cigars. Vykkers think they’re smart, cause they know lots of stuff (like how to cut someone open so it hurts the most; you know, useful stuff). And Interns, … not even Interns think Interns are smart. ", "tags": ["Glukkon", "Vykker"]},

{"question": "Hey, Alf. I was wondering, on this website, Abe’s STATUS report says that he has no sexual organs. Then why does Abe and his friends wear those loin-clothes? ", "answer": "Style, baby. If presence of a clothing item meant there were naughty bits beneath, people’d start wondering why you humans wear hats. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How do Interns communicate? I’ve looked at pictures and couldn’t find their mouths.", "answer": "All the better, since they all have those walkmans on all the time. Even if they could talk, nobody’d listen to ’em. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi, again. Do the Mudokons take to Munch pretty well, or do they kinda avoid him and wipe off their oversized palms after shaking hands with him? ", "answer": "The most I’ve heard any Mudokon other than Abe say to Munch other than giggling at him was “Heh heh, Hey, Do that thing with your fins again so Buddy can see it!” ", "tags": ["Munch", "Abe", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "What do the Zulags in RuptureFarms stand for? Do they have anything to do with the Russian GULAGs? ", "answer": "What’s Russia? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Do Slogs have eyes, or are they blind? if they are how do they know where they’re going?", "answer": "Given their propensity for running their dumb selves right into active minefields, my guess is they don’t. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I was just wondering if it was possible for other species to have Slogs besides Sligs? If not, why?", "answer": "I imagine if one got a hold of a slog pup and, over the course of several years, regularly beat, starved, and wittily pointed out his various inadequacies as an Oddworld being, one could ingrain the neccessary fear and respect needed to keep it in line – provided you never turned your back on them. That’s how the Sligs do it, and only because that’s what they get paid for. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "I wonder if you can answer this question which has been bugging me for a while; how old are Aslik, Dripik, Phleg and that Brewmaster guy? Just wanted to know, thanks for reading!", "answer": "They’re all 29, coincidentally enough. In fact, Phleg was 29 for at -least- the last 17 years. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "In Oddworld: Abe’s Exoddus¨, the Glukkons keep talking about Molluck. Is he supposed to be the “Master”, or something like that?", "answer": "Molluck pulled a lot more weight than any of those chumps did. On Oddworld, a CEO stands head and shoulders above a Director, Vice President, and General combined. But that’s a good point… Molluck was presumed dead after Abe was first freed from Rupture Farms… why were those 3 so worried about him ‘finding out’ about the Necrum Mines incident? ", "tags": ["Abe", "Molluck"]},

{"question": "Is there a level editor for Oddworld: Abe’s Exoddus¨? ", "answer": "A level editor? What, you think our existance is some kind of GAME?!! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What Are The Requirements Of Becoming Fan Of The Month On Your Website? ", "answer": "For Starters, Conservative Use Of Capitalization In A Sentence. Secondly, well, it’s kind of ambiguous. Put it this way: You scratch our back, we’ll shave yours. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I’m curious about the 3rd Oddworld game for Xbox. What’s the main plot of it? What are Interns? Who is the big boss? (Molluck was the big boss in the first one.) It’s okay if I can’t know.  ", "answer": "Abe’s and Munch have their own missions. Abe’s gotta save his brothers. And, in a way, so does Munch… Interns are lazy bums with itchy trigger fingers who needed a summer job and subscribe to the motto “If it’s worth doing, it’s worth doing later.” As for the big boss… well, hard to say. The two guys in charge are always fighting over which of them ‘wears the pants’, whatever that means… ", "tags": ["Munch", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Who is this Lulu? Lulu sounds like a girls name? Lulu is a guy …right?", "answer": "Eh. Technically, yes. Most folks who know him tend to use more colorful adjectives. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "In the game opening of Abe’s Exoddus when Abe falls a Slig flies by and says “somethin’ smells”. I noticed that the Flying Slig seemed to have ‘wings’ instead of ‘blades’ I was wondering if you could explain this?", "answer": "He was commenting on the smell of ozone that was generating by the lubricating oil in his wings burning away, resulting in his wings seizing up and him plummetting to a fiery crash about 10 seconds later, well offscreen, where you’d never have noticed. They discontinued the winged model after that, on the completely unrelated reasoning that the propeller model was also cheaper to manufacture. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "In the game can you switch between Abe and Munch at will or does the story carry the switching? ex. Resident Evil CV?", "answer": "If you wanna help those two get around, we figure that’s your business, and we’ll let you do the deciding as to who goes where and when. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How close are you guys from finishing the game, percentage wise?", "answer": "Hmm. Hard to say. Somewhere between 14 and 97%. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Is there ever going to be a Oddworld movie , there must be cmon if Final Fantasy can do it so can Oddworld.", "answer": "What’s Final Fantasy? Is it near ‘Russia’? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Are There Any Insects On Oddworld? ", "answer": "Heh. Wait till you see our intro. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What is the reproductive model of Elums and do they lay eggs or give birth to live young?", "answer": "Well, on this one, I’d have asked the Elums that are in the upcoming Munch’s Oddysee, but they were surprisingly, um, unresponsive. Confidential to our fan who uses the handle ‘Elum’: I’m so very, very sorry. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "How can I kill Scrabs and the “dogs” without chanting???", "answer": "Don’t go killing those Scrabs! Remember, they’re sacred, holy beasts, an endangered species, and they have to last us until breakfast tommorrow!!! ", "tags": ["Scrab"]},

{"question": "How come Abe is blue and all the other Mudokons are green?", "answer": "Back in Rupture Farms, we bet him 5 bucks he couldn’t hold a mouthful of Paramite Juice for ten minutes without swallowing. He won. ", "tags": ["Paramite"]},

{"question": "Is it at all possible that Munch’s Oddysee will be reformatted for the GameCube?", "answer": "It’s probably equally possible that Mario will be ported for the XBox. It’s also equally possible that I’ll become a responsible ‘social’ drinker. But I wouldn’t hold my breath if I were you. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, Joe and Matt here, we were just wondering what pieces of crawling meat bags with extra limbs will be running around in Munch’s Exoddus, and who the hell is this guy Squeek?", "answer": "Hopefully not too many, for their own good… the Magog Cartel has a rule: ‘More Limbs means More Flavor!’ As for Squeek… don’t know what you’re talking about. Sounds ludicrous that such a creature would exist… I mean, what kind of self-respecting being would have an onomatopoeia for a name? *BRRRZZZZZAAAPPPTT* GYAAHHH!!! What the heck was that for, Munch?! ", "tags": ["Squeek", "Munch"]},

{"question": "I’d like to know why you Mudokons are always the victim of the Glukkons. Are you weaker or something??? (I don’t think so, so don’t be offended). ", "answer": "Well, lets look at it this way. Suppose you’re thrown into an arena, barefisted, with a toy poodle, and only one of you can leave. Sounds like you’re at the advantage, right? Now suppose you’re thrown into an arena, barefisted, with a toy poodle, but this poodle happens to be well funded and has a retinue of 200 pound guards with shotguns in front of him. Your odds suddenly take a dip. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I know that Mudokons are good, Glukkons are bad, Sligs work for the Glukkons…which make them kind of bad and Vykkers are mad scientists. What kind of nature are Interns? ", "answer": "They’re on par with the Sligs… lazy creeps that are in it just because it’s an easy job and they get to carry guns. Rather than nap all the time, they just leave their headphones on and never listen to their co-workers. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Will there EVER be Oddworld toys that I can buy and play with? ", "answer": "You never know. Eh. Well, wait, I should rephrase that. I never know. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What is that green gas in the background of the SligBarracks? ", "answer": "And you thought Abe had bad gas. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "To Alf–urp, hold on…brew’s coming back up.", "answer": "…(sniffle) …I’m all choked up… All I ever wanted was to be recognized, to hear somebody tell me ‘I done good’ … to get out from the shadow of Abe… To think I turned to Brew to try and cure my depression, when all I really needed to do was roll up my sleeves and get out there with the rest of them and do the job, get my buddies off the sauce, make a difference. Well buddy, you’ve renewed my dedication. I’m getting back on that stage and helping my fellow muds again… just as soon as my Soaps are done. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "I’ve heard that the Sligs are gonna get new weapons and stuff, so can you please tell me what their names are, how they look like and what they can do to others? Yeah, and will the BigBro Sligs talk like the normal Sligs. I have hundreds of questions since it’s kinda hard to get magazines about Abe and his friends down in New Zealand here.", "answer": "The philosophy behind the Magog Cartel’s weapons development division seems to be this: If it’s good enough to be eaten, drank, smoked, licked, or injected, it’s good enough to be shot. Why waste valuable research on developing ammunition when you can just stuff a can of SoulStorm Brew into a BlitzPacker? And yeah, the BigBros can talk, but of course they talk differently from the little sligs. Takes a lot of testosterone and steroids to get them that big, after all. ", "tags": ["SoulStorm Brew"]},

{"question": "Why Did you call those Punk Rock looking Mudokons Tomahawkers? What class are they? Are we going to know more info on them? They look like My punk rock group. That would be so nice if Mudokons had their own rock band:) :). ", "answer": "They carry big Tomahawks, and they aren’t the most imaginative bunch when it comes to naming. Hence: Tomahawkers. And they tried to make a band once, but they just got into a big fistfight over who got to play drums. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Where does all the main game programming for Oddworld games take place.", "answer": "At Oddworld Inhabitants, of course. The real question is where all the de-programming happens… we still have a problem with the coders getting kidnapped back by their families every so often. Then we just gotta go out and brainwash another. ", "tags": ["Oddworld Inhabitants"]},

{"question": "PS: Where did you get that cool accent from I want one, I want one, I want one, I want one, I want one, I want one. ", "answer": "Gee, that’s incentive. Two fewer lushes hanging around and being belligerent? Golly, I wouldn’t want that. Well, I tell ya what. I can’t be sure which 2 you didn’t save unless I know which ones you did save… so tell me exactly where the other 298 were when you rescued them, and I’ll get back to ya. As for the accent, eh, when I was in the brewery I was trying to suck the last couple drops outta a bottle and got my tongue stuck in it for about 4 days. I’ve talked kinda funny ever since. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I couldn’t help noticing that in a recent batch of screenshots, we see a SoBe beverage dispenser, complete with stylized text and SoBe logo! Don’t tell me that anti-corporate Oddworld has stooped to product placement! ", "answer": "Oddworld ain’t anti-corporate, first of all. Oddworld’s a business, and just like any other, to make our product, we rely on people buying them and then we use that money to pay the scrubs in the pens to crank out code and art and design. Oddworld’s opposed to certain corporate practices, though… Environmental destruction, apathy towards better health, animal experimentation, the likes. As it turns out, the folks at SoBe are also a business that relies upon consumer dollars to provide them with a product they want, and they also have similar beliefs to our own. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I’m a Slig with some serious mental problems. I feel that the slavery of Mudokons is wrong and should be paid at least! I have spoken to my fellow Slig buddies but they think I’m mad or possessed!!! What shall I do and what do you think about the Mudokon slave trade?", "answer": "…What are those little lights floating around your head? Abe, is that you in there? Doggonit, stop trying to mess with me when I’m answering fan mail… ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "I just wanted to know how Abe got that stupid sneaking motion! Is it a habit or something? Was whoever thought of it having a hangover when he/her thought of it?", "answer": "Abe came up with that exaggerated sneaking motion during a game of charades a couple years ago, and has just been kinda fond of it ever since. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "I may be in the neighborhood sometime soon, is it possible for fans to come and visit the Oddworld Inhabitants?", "answer": "We’re not exactly a hot spot of tourism… unless you have some remarkably potent Scrab and Paramite repellant, are prepared to gnaw your leg off on the off chance you happen to step into a Gabbit trap, and all just to get a loincloth that says “I was very nearly rent to shreds by a flock of hungry red bug-looking things and all I got was this lousy loincloth.” ", "tags": ["Paramite", "Scrab", "Gabbit"]},

{"question": "I was wondering, why is Abe’s eyes a bright orangey-red while everybody else’s eyes are a pearly white? Has he got some version of pink eye? (and if he does, why doesn’t he use eyedrops?). Also, why, in your picture, do you look so dazed and glassy-eyed? Have you been smoking something?", "answer": "Why is his skin blue and the rest of ours green? Why are his lips stitched shut? There are some things we just weren’t meant to know… yet. And if you’re asking why I look dazed and glassy-eyed, you haven’t done your homework. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I am particularly excited about the new Oddworld game, but I have one worry. I know that Oddworld is now advertising for a soft drink company, there won’t be any references to this in the game will there? No blatant advertisement? I have seen games like this, sometimes they pull it off, sometimes it comes off as blatant advertisement. Which one will you be? ", "answer": "You are likely referring to the product tie-in that Oddworld has with SOBE BEVERAGES, makers of fine, refreshing drinks. Rest assured that Oddworld would never subject itself to unneeded advertising, even for a splendid company which makes such quality products as SOBE BEVERAGES. Don’t worry about it…instead, go and have yourself a drink to ease your stress…why not a delicious Elixir or Lizard Lightning made by SOBE BEVERAGES? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I was wondering, don’t you and your mates get cold at all , I mean since all you have to wear is identical clothes? Isn’t there a fashion industry or something?", "answer": "We Mudokons tend to hang about in arid regions, and our loincloths, in addition to being sexy as all get-out, make for comfortable living in such a climate. ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Are Sligs really evil or are they just following orders?", "answer": "Is Eddie Haskell evil? Sligs just gotta survive. They are easily influence by their surroundings. Evil breeds evil. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "How come Sligs can’t jump even when you chant one? ", "answer": "Given the shoddy manufacturing, it’s amazing Sligs can even stay upright in their mechanical pants, let alone attempt to get athletic in them. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "There’s been something bothering me for a while now. Technically, a Slig is about half critter, half machine right? What would be the scenario if Abe possessed the Slig, and Munch Possessed the pants?", "answer": "Put yourself in Munch’s shoes. Would you want to plug your mind into a Slig’s pants? ", "tags": ["Slig", "Munch"]},

{"question": "How do Sligs turn into BigBro Sligs? Do they have this muscle builder fluid or what?", "answer": "For a while they tried pumping iron and eating lots of high-protien foods and buying those Nordic-Track things that are advertised at 3AM on cable. Then, inevitably, a Vykker came along with an invasive, destructive steroid that got the same results at a fraction of the cost. And the rest is history, albeit history that seems to be repeated quite frequently. ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "My friend said that in Oddworld you can walk around doing nothing and slapping people continuously, is that true????? ", "answer": "Heck, you can do that in your world if I’m not mistaken … just don’t make any plans for the afternoon that you can’t accomplish in a body cast. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Yo Alf, why don’t Interns have mouths, I mean what if something goes wrong and they need to talk. It’s weird!!! ", "answer": "They do have mouths. Or did, anyway. Let’s just say that stitching technology has come a long way since they slapped those loose bindings on Abe’s lips. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Hey, would you happen to know why Scrabs have calf muscles? I mean, their feet are just fixed spikes, so it seems like any contraction of the calf would fail to serve any purpose… Actuator muscles, maybe?", "answer": "You’re talkin’ to the wrong guy on this one. As far as I’m concerned about Scrabs, they see you, they start moving. Whether they do this via superfluous calf muscles or rocket engines, it’s all the same to me, ’cause I am outta there. ", "tags": ["Scrab"]},

{"question": "Firstly, will the sligs guarding Vykkers Labs have really high-tech stuff like cyber-slogs, flying greeters and super zappy things with an added flame-thrower and inter-continental ballistic missile attachment? ", "answer": "Crig:   I wish. Those cheapskate Glukkons would never spring for such things, no matter how obvious it becomes that we really need them. In fact, sligs have to buy their own guns, ammo, and pants, at inflated gluk prices. Odd! I hate those pus-headed loudmouths! What you will find is that some of the richer sligs and others were able to buy some armor, and we did get chant suppressors installed in a few areas. Naturally, the glukkons reserved the best suppressors for themselves. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "Secondly, how can you reply to these E-mails if you are part of a race with no idea of electronic devices?", "answer": "Crig:   What’s E-mail? I get these notes on paramiteskin parchments, and that’s how I answer them. No true slig would write any letter that didn’t involve killing something. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "And finally, will Crig the Slig be in the Quintology?", "answer": "Crig:   I have hopes, but there is a strong pro-mudokon bias working against me. I try to explain to them the true nobility of sligly viciousness, but they just don’t understand. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, what are the blue fish-like things the gabbits are eating at the beginning of Munch’s Oddysee? Could you tell me anything interesting about them? ", "answer": "They are called Worryfish, and you have to be a slippery fella like them Gabbits to catch one. They enjoy swimming around in schools. I guess if I had to walk around with my school, I’d worry too. ", "tags": ["Gabbit"]},

{"question": "SUB QUESTION!!!: Since Abe’s Exoddus is a special bonus game, does that mean we still can look foward to 3 other games in the quintology? or just two?", "answer": "Once you find the eggs, you’re hot on the trail to where they came from. Sometimes the first clues can be pretty unspectacular, but they sometimes the most important. Hang in there, Buckaroo. The powers that be may indeed give up 3 more games — but believe me, the Oddworld Universe is larger than maybe even three games can contain! No one can contain me, alone! I will not go! Oh no! Sorry, pal! Not going! Nuh-uh! I …. huh? What? Oh. Ahem. Yea, I dunno — let’s watch. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi all you Muds! I have a little question for Abe. How many years did you worked as a slave at RuptureFarms?", "answer": "I’ll answer for Abe. Way too many. He was trained since he was a little meddling Mudling to do the stuff at RuptureFarms, so it’s all been a bit of a blur. ", "tags": ["Abe", "RuptureFarms"]},

{"question": "How come scrabs are found in herds in Munch’s Oddysee and scrabs are supposed to REALLY HATE EACH OTHER (that’s what saves me in Abe’s Oddysee from these Slick creatures!! 🙂 ) ", "answer": "One on one, they can be confrontational. But in one big group, they tend to get along, and just go with the crowd. Y’know, like people in general. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi my name is Robert and I have been an Oddworld fan since Abe’s Oddysee. Can you tell me why Abe’s voice is different in Abe’s Exoddus to what it was in Abe’s Oddysee? I’m getting the XBox and Munch’s Oddysee in March when it is released here in Australia, but what voice will Abe have this time? ", "answer": "Abe changes as the years go by, and it reflects in his voice. Eventually, it reflects in the mirror. That’s why I don’t have any, myself. Who needs to see your ponytail turning grey? Next question. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Can you tell me a cool thing about some creature of Oddworld that I don’t know about. Just telling ya I know a lot about Oddworld. I got every question right on an Oddworld Trivia. ", "answer": "I happen to love dancing. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I’ve seen a picture of these two hideous old looking Vykkers, (Not like they are all not hideous) but they are friggin’ ugly. They also always stand by facing their backs facing each other. They’re purple. They seem to be like the head Vykkers. Anyway, I would just like to know what their names are. ", "answer": "Their names are Humphrey (the scientist) and Irwin, his … friend. If they have friends. These guys are so ugly, they could scare the pants off of a Slig. I personally like it when they face away from me because then I don’t have to see their ugly mugs. Bleagh. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf, I was wonderin’ which guy are you in A.E. I know you were one of the dudes who went with Abe on that journey, and then you got sick from brew, and Abe has to cure you yadayadayada. So are you the guy with the high pitched voice, or the guy with the throat that sounds like there is a frog in it, or whooo???? Which guy are you I need to know???? SEE YA WOULDN’T WANNA BE YA!:-) ", "answer": "I am the man. The A-number one man, the one, the only, the Alf. That’s who I am. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Why stick with Elum when you could have a cute slog ! Even though you claim that chicks dig Elum…I like Slogs so much beter! there Cute and…Cute and you just wanna hug em ! so why not trade in Elum and get a cute Sloggie…or one of those things…you know..there fuzzles but they look like rabbits with three eyes, what are they? anyways, thats all…so bye !", "answer": "The thingies you are referring to are Meeps, and perfectly huggable. Lemme tell you something: If you want to make it to old age with your face intact, you don’t wanna get friendly with a Slog! They make buzzsaws look cuddly. If you try to pet them, you’ll wind up feeding them. They are trouble with a capital “T”. Which brings me to my next question… ", "tags": ["Slog"]},

{"question": "What exactly is your TEA made of?", "answer": "Goodness from nature, wholesomeness from the earth, and a sprig of springwater for that right touch of ‘liquid’. And then sometimes I just grab a handful of leaves. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "O Alf, I just played the Oddworld demo and when Abe climbed this long pillar thing he more or less walked up it. It looked like some cartoon. Why doesn’t he just climb regularly? ", "answer": "I’ve tried to get him to climb, but, dag-nabbit, that fellow is just as shy about certain things as when I met him! If he doesn’t wanna climb, he ain’t gonna climb! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hiyas Alf. Well done to your great success! I have a few questions: Why don’t the sligs all gang up on the glukkons, theres enough of them aren’t there? ", "answer": "They would have to be able to be smart enough to band together- they’re not. Plus, the Glukkons keep all the power to the Slig’s pants. Good luck doing a revolution as a slug. ", "tags": ["Slig", "Glukkon"]},

{"question": "What’s Aslik the Vice-President of? ", "answer": "Some blown-up part of Feeco Depot. I think the crispy section. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "This one is from my friend. Why does Phleg look fat? (ridiculous question I know!). Also could you say hi to Phleg for my other friend who’s crazy about him! And say hi to Aslik for me, i think hes kinda cute.", "answer": "‘Cause he is. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, I was wondering if you had a spare Abe’s Oddysee game lying around that you could send me for around $10. Please get back to me. From T ", "answer": "Oh well, sure! Let me just wrap that right up for you, and then stick a big sign in my head that says “Convenience Store”! Then I can open up a Snow-cone machine in my ear, a gas station in my shorts, and I’ll become a flip-flappin’ Convenience Store! Please, allow me to be your personal hookup for whatever you can possibly sponge off of me – I live for it! Forget that I’m just a guy that ANSWERS QUESTIONS! Sheesh. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "hi, I’m a very big fan with a pc and have heard rumors that Munch will only be on Xbox… is this true? I have the other two games and was looking forward to seeing abe in 3d but if the rumors are true that will never happen, PLEASE reply as soon as you can, I have already asked this question to a different oddworld e-mail address but they have not replied (maybe they are really busy) Huge fan, Andrea", "answer": "Well, the Oddworld folk are busy folk, and for now, the Xbox suits our world just right. Would you want us to be carried on a system that doesn’t do us justice? Doesn’t show the true brilliance of the Oddworld world? Show how the Sligs can chase you and beat your behind as well as they do? Me thinks not! ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Why don’t you have any facts on Shrykulls? I saw something about a Sea Rex and a Rat and I was wondering why they disappeared and what they were.", "answer": "Shrykulls are mysterious beings, that have hardly been caught and studied-they are weird mystical creatures that scare the heck outta me. When one comes in and offers its mitts to us and want to have tea and tell us all about it, well, I’m all ears. But have you seen those things? Yipes. Sea Rexes and rats are ugly little creatures that make my skin crawl. Sea Rexes swallow me, my shop, and all my precious text in one gulp, so that’s why I’m glad to stay on the shore and be happily ignorant of them. Ask me about meeps—they are pretty approachable. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Did Abe marry Sam the Mudokon queen ? If so was he insanely in love? or was he just plain confused from his little fantasies ? Oh yeah one more, Did you always looked that fine in your pictures ?", "answer": "I am the Mack who packs a smack, dishing’ out the phat flavah for here and the future. Now that we’re done with the 70’s B-movie talk, let’s get down to business. I don’t think Abe married Sam, since she’s just downright nasty. Abe isn’t insanely in love, but he is a little dopey. He’s also a bit of an individualist, ready for whatever and whenever. Hardly a guy who’s going to slow down. Did I always look that fine? Lady, I’m nice-fine like rice wine. ", "tags": ["Sam", "Abe"]},

{"question": "I have a few questions that I think need to be asked. or not. but still, I wanna ask them. Well here I go. First question, when will you have your own game? Ya know, something like “Alf’s Rehab Oddysee” or “Alf’s Tea Exoddus”, you could like smash sligs with…uh…well…Tea….yeah! Acidic Tea Bombs and stuff.", "answer": "Hey! Yea! Now you’re talking! I can see the hero (me) of the world, with a quest for someone to save the people (me), in a world full of rewards (for me!). Lessee … if I see a billion bejillion copies…. and keep the royalties… carry the seven… WOW! Kid, I like your style. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Second Question: how old are ya? like 20 something? ", "answer": "More something than 20. Let’s move on. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Third Question: I think there is a Glukkon running our educational facilities. He makes us work like Mudokon slaves writting down pointless stuff. He yells at us and smells like bad cigars and call himself principal. Help! What should I do? ", "answer": "Graduate. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Last Question: My friend has a drinking problem, he drinks too much Storm Brew. Last night he called my house in one of his drunk moods and told me that a Slog was eating his mom. What can I do?   Your Friend, Rick ", "answer": "Get your friend on tea, toot-sweet! That Brew will drill a hole in your head and leave your face-flap blowing in the wind! We have a delightful selection of good teas, including “banana-fana”, “Yibba-Yo” and “Gnort”. Special today! Buy one, pay for it! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey ya all U Muds! No offense Alf Ur cool and all, but Abe is my favorite character and I’d like him to answer, it’s one only he could answer anyway…What was Ur first thought and feelings when U first was told U had to save Ur fellow Mudokons from Rupture Farms after U just escaped from it and also when U successed and got praise for a hero? Well that’s all for now. See ya Abe", "answer": "Ur? What is this “Ur”? Am I some kind of ancient demigod with two letters to his name? No, I have THREE letters in my name: “Alf.” I would love to speak to this “Ur” fellow and ask him your questions, but I don’t know him! I don’t speak in rebus—try the King’s English, m’boy. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alfie, Got a big favor to ask. I love oddworld, and I love video gaming. I think I might want a job in the field some day, but I don’t know how the system works. I’d like some pointers as to where I should go to college if I aspire to be say… a conceptual artist. cuz, I got no clue and I can’t get answers from NOBODY in big business. You’re my last hope alfie man.   Always a fan, Erin", "answer": "Go check on a place that you would like to work, and find out what their requirements are. If they are a good place, they’ll give you the answers you seek. Also, be persistent, but be ready to do the work. Most people just fall in love with the idea, then shy away when they find out it’s hard work, so good luck! M.C. Abe is just striking a buffalo-stance pose, looking coy and cool in his new washed loincloth! M.C. now means Mudokon Chillin’! ", "tags": ["Abe", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "[There’s a lipstick smooch at the bottom.]", "answer": "What can I say? I love people and to serve them nice hot tea. Don’t knock it until you try it! It’s a lovely relaxing way to enjoy the day and the evening, as the sun sets slowly in the West… uh, East… whatever… I like to drink tea, to walk about the place, and by gosh, I actually like to answer these questions! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Yo Alf, Ur cool and all, but my favortie Character is Abe and I’d like him to answer this one himself….It’s one only he could answer anyway…..What it’s like when you possess someone? It must have been weird the first time you did it. Plus judging by how you fell after possessing Lulu and lost control sometimes it must be alot work. Also I wanna say Ur the coolest character on Oddworld by far Abe….Well thanks for your time and good luck on getting a break…..See ya ", "answer": "Abe once told me that possession took a lot of concentration, and sometimes that can be broken, when someone else is in the room, distracting them. Or yelling at them, or whatever. That poor guy had a roomful of squawking people, he had the pressure of saving the world, and he had Munch yelling at him! I suppose possessing someone would feel weird no matter HOW many times you’d done it. I tell ya, that guy’s got more heart than a King Scrab. ", "tags": ["Scrab", "Munch", "Abe"]},

{"question": "O Alf, great fountain of wisdom and awe, I beg to you, answer this question:   Is your formula, Ugly+$$$=Chicks, a branch-off of Professor Alf Alpha’s theory: Cute and/or Sexy+$$$=Lots of chicks? ", "answer": "Cute? Sexy? What’s that? I’m a businessman. I like the peoples as a whole. My formula for success is this: Tea+Me= Happy Alf zzzz, Tea+Me+Others= Cash flow. Happy Alf again! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "With the ever expanding Oddworld Universe that is visitable in the games, are there any plans afoot to use a system (similar to that in Seaman from Sega) wherebye speech recognition could be use to communicate with the inhabitants of Oddworld. Maybe with the option to set you own prefernces so instead of just saying “hello” to get someone’s attention you could instead say “hi” “oi” or “hey” etc… Still looking forward to X-box’s UK release, Dan J. ", "answer": "You can shake me up until a little blue triangle floats to the top of my eyes that says “Unclear, ask again”, but the truth is I can’t see the future. But take this to the bank: The future keeps coming, and it does seem an interesting way to go… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hello Alf. I’ve asked this before but you didn’t answer it so I’ll try again… What has Crig the slig been doing the last few months? I know that you are knowledgable enough not to need his help to answer our questions but it was interesting to hear (and when I say hear I mean read) a slig’s points of view. I hope Crig hasn’t died or anything, ever since you introduced him I have wanted to learn more about him, his job and his adventures (if he has any). Please tell me more about him. ", "answer": "Crig took a permanent vacation after barely escaping an explosion at FeeCo. I think he’s off somewhere tending a herd of Slogs in the mountains, or he’s punching tickets at a bumper-card ride somewhere. I do believe we’ve heard the last form that boy. ", "tags": ["Slog"]},

{"question": "As I played the game called Munch’s Oddysee I could turn Natives into Tomahawkers and then into Mudarchers, but why couldn’t Abe turn into one of them?)", "answer": "Abe is a truly unique character, he doesn’t need to change into anyone to get out of a situation. Look how far he’s come with just his wits! Stay with Abe, he’s a survivor! ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Hello, Alf. my name is Tony, I’m from Brazil and I’m a fanatic for the Abe games. I did play everyday, Abe’s Exoddus and I would like to know you will sell the next game “Munch’s Oddysee” here in Brazil! Congratulations for the game. ", "answer": "Thanks so much for the letter, Tony—we wouldn’t be anything without you fans! You truly make each day worth getting up… and serving tea! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear What’s it all about? What’s it all about, Alfie?", "answer": "I would just blame it on Rio. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi! I am a huge Oddworld fan and I love the games too they are soooooooo cool! But I have a few questions here. Please answer!!! What is the next Oddworld game and will it come to XBox? ", "answer": "The next Oddworld game is going to be “Alf Alf Saves The Universe”, and it’s going to be starring yours truly, who runs around for an hour or so, instantly defeating anything I touch. Well, it was an idea I gave them—I haven’t heard back, but my hopes are high. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Is there going to be any new characters in the new game?", "answer": "Oy vey, I hope so. I hate to keep running from the same Scrabs. ", "tags": ["Scrab"]},

{"question": "Is Mollock really dead? If he is alive will he come to a new Oddworld game?", "answer": "With these slimy types, you never know. I wouldn’t buy it unless I had him come up, shake my hand, and personally announce that he’s snuffed it. I wouldn’t turn my back on him, otherwise. KnowwhatImean? If he’s alive, how else would you know? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Are the sligs or whatever builded RuptureFarms build it up again?", "answer": "I think that those sneaky so-and-so’s would go and build something completely different and new, since the Rupture Farms design proved flawed and vulnerable. Why build the old place back up if all it’s going to do is blow up again? And kiddo, what’s with the ‘builded’? Didn’t you learnded nothing in school? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I’m a big fan of the Oddworld games and I’ve got a few questions. What type of animal do the glukkons put mechanical masks, pants and wigs on and call sligs? ", "answer": "Uh… those would be Sligs, boyo. Even without the mechanics, it’s still a Slig. And what do you mean ‘wigs’? Did you see something I didn’t? I have yet to see a Slig cabaret. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Do you have star ships or something, so you can go to other planets? ", "answer": "Not just yet, but I have some tea that is absolutely out of this world! Care to buy some? I have a special deal: Buy one, and I’ll give it to you! Howzat? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How come the glukkons don’t just put anti-chant orbs everywhere?", "answer": "Time, money, laziness. Don’t say it too loud, they might just get an idea. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How come Abe seems to be the only Mudokon who can possess sligs, glukkons, etc?", "answer": "Well, Abe is who you currently run around as in the game-if you ran around as another Mudokon, maybe you would be able to use their powers. Also, let’s remember that he’s the leader and savior of the race. I think that entitles him to one or two powers, hen? ", "tags": ["Abe", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Hi Alf my names Robert and I have recently gotten Munch’s Oddysee. I noticed that when Abe or Munch drinks a can from a vend it has a SoulStorm Brew Lable on it! You couldn’t possibly tell me that Abe or Munch is chuggin’ down SoulStorm Brew to bring up their health or make them run faster or jump higher could you? ", "answer": "No, I couldn’t. Ya got me there. But I would like to address something: What the heck is a “lable”? I’ve heard of Labels, and Ladels, and even some Ukeleles, but never a lable. Could you tell me what a lable is, if you’re able? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi, Alf, It’s me again!!! I just wanna ask you a question, (again). Recently, I looked at the front cover of Munch’s Oddysee. I don’t want to be rude, but Abe looks a bit different. I saw the marks on his hand, that’s obvious, the Paramite and Scrab marks from the Bigface. But I noticed a mark on his chest. Could you tell me a little about that please? If you could, that would be fantastic. (I will stay Odd) ", "answer": "To get even with your Oddness, you’ve missed out on a whole section of the previous game! In Abe’s Exoddus, Abe was bestowed that big chest mark by the three weirdoes in Necrum. It gave him some wonderful powers, and that was the mark. What were you chugging Brew while that part of the game was playing? ", "tags": ["Abe", "Abe’s Exoddus"]},

{"question": "Are there any new Sligs or animals? I quite like sligs. They’ve got Odditude!", "answer": "All the time! Our world is chocked full of goodness. Why we gotcha Meeches, your Fleeches, your star-bellied Vykkers… ahem… and you should be sure to stay abreast of all the animal kingdom of Odd by staying abreast of the game. That means go get it. Now. Check out the Universe section of this website too. ", "tags": ["Fleech", "Vykker"]},

{"question": "On your first game, Oddworld: Abe’s Oddysee, there was a cheat, where you could look at any story that occured in the game. I preformed it and went on a story called Guardian Angel. You know, the one with the Shrink is talking to Abe. It was so cool, great job!!! But I was somewhat puzzled when the Shrink said, “You’ve gotta look within, if ya wanna be free!” Then you heard Abe cry for his life. What happened man? ", "answer": "It scared him. A little. I mean, a big mechanical thing comes down out of the ceiling, then you would probably be frightened too. But since the old boy is still around, we can deduce that he’s doing just fine. That movie is actually a television commercial that was never seen. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Well that was my question are there any plans in the future for it to be released for PS2. ", "answer": "Beef? Your beef is nothing but bouill-ion! You’ve already shelled out an un-oddly amount of moolah on four different consoles… what’s one more? Make your collection complete with an Xbox! Wow. Four systems… you lucky gluk… uh I mean… duck…. Oh, and for the millionth time: The next four Oddworld games will be exclusively for the Xbox. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How did Dripik lose his eye? And do you delete all the questions that don’t get screened or do you keep them all in a big Word file for posterity? ", "answer": "The Muds down at the home office keep all the questions in a big pile. I only get the ones that are dropped off monthly. As far as Dripik losing his eye, I don’t think he lost an eye; he’s just too stupid to realize he put the patch thing on. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I have a question. I’ve enjoyed all three games so far, but in Munch’s Oddysee, I noticed something strange about Abe. His eyes seem to glow in the dark, and I’m sure I didn’t see this in the previous games. Since you’re his friend, could you tell me if they have always been like that? Or did something happen to him? ", "answer": "He got a lot of tattoos, and a lot of powers… I think he may be having more of the usual healthy little glow we all have. I mean, he is the big Kahuna here on Oddworld. I guess it helps him see in the dark. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Bye, Oddguy ", "answer": "Glukkons are the ones in power—that’s why they get to sit around. I would say the Sligs should rise up and overthrow them myself, but it doesn’t seem to be in the cards, since the Sligs are as dumb as a bag of hair. The scumbag Glukkons came into power, because they didn’t care WHO they stepped on or WHAT they ruined to get there. Once you throw all your own personal motives out there first, you wind up being a bad man, like these Glukkon clowns! I say we put them all on a sligshot to Oddworld’s moon… Also, the whole first game is based on the Glukkons taking power, maybe you should give it a whirl first, and see if that answers any of your questions. You can read about the history of Oddworld at   www.xbox.com ", "tags": ["Glukkon", "Slig"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf I have some questions for you. I would really like you answer them because it would be annoying for both of us if I had to send this to you over and over again until you finally gave me an answer. Why doesn’t your section in the Oddworld Universe have as much information as Abe’s or Munch’s. You are just as interesting as both of them combined? ", "answer": "Sigh. I keep tellin’ ’em at Oddworld about having an all-Alf game, see above. Still waiting for that call back, y’all! I did make an appearance in the new UYI video. Check out the images on top of this page. Thanks for your support! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What are the names of the other continents on Oddworld (as of now I only have heard of the one you live on, Mudos).", "answer": "Eh… so far, that’s all I know myself. I don’t travel much, and I’m not quite the jumper I once was. I used to be able to run around the house a couple of times and not even be tired! Of course, that’s when I was usually being chased by something… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Have you ever eaten a Mudokon Pop? If so, what does your species taste like?", "answer": "Aw, c’mon. Did you ever have a people-steak? BLEAGH! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I just wanted to ask u a few questions , firstly I was wondering why the creatures in Munch’s Oddysee have become more humanized. the glukkons talk like gangsters and the paramites like pigs and the scrabs don’t have their infamous shrieks like they used to in the previous games. I thought the creatures of Oddworld were supposed to be nothing like the things on earth? . I mean they look nothing like creatures here but they sound like things from earth. can u tell me why?? ", "answer": "There are plenty of creatures that don’t speak or make sense, but it varies from adventure to adventure. I have yet to hear a fuzzle make sense, or a fleech to give a speech! Hey, that’s pretty good: To hear a Fleech give a speech. Kinda like the earlier one fish two fish thing. Maybe a got a knack for this kinda thing… ", "tags": ["Fleech"]},

{"question": "What can you tell me about the queens Sam, Maggie and Skillya?", "answer": "They are indeed queens of different species in Oddworld. We’ve heard about them and seen images of them. Their stories have not been told … yet. Remember Oddworld is a big place! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "finally do u have any info on the next game or is another bonus game likely?? There have been rumors about it being called Squeek’s Oddysee, is this true?? ", "answer": "Whoa, whoa WHOA! Too much at once! These questions were asked before and the answer is the same: We can’t reveal all the characters in every game. The world is a large place here on Oddworld, and the point isn’t to show you everyone in one game, but to have different adventures that give a little here, a little there. If we show you all the same characters every game, well, then it’s not really a new adventure, is it? We dole out the fun, equally each game, and some characters change and evolve, others are new, and others have yet to be revealed. The planet is Oddworld and we live in the continent of Mudos. Stay tuned for the fun! Well, that’s all the news fit to print, I’m Alf and I’m out! ", "tags": ["Mudos"]},

{"question": "Do sligs have other weapons like handguns and knives or swords they can use or could they be tough to use hand to hand combat ? Also do they have tanks they can drive? -Cheese Deamon", "answer": "Enh… I think guns are enough, don’t you? Aw, nuts…looks like you spoke too loud, maybe they’ll get an idea or two, dag-nabbit. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I was wondering, why can’t Vykkers, Interns and sligs attack the Glukkon slobs and steal their Moolah? And if this hasn’t been heard to them could you send it? -Chris90 ", "answer": "Well, for one thing, WHO NEEDS MOOLAH WHEN YOU DON’T BUY STUFF? All the rubies in the world don’t matter when you live off the land very nicely, kiddo. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I have some Q’z if you don’t mind answering them for me: Do you visit the Oddworld Forums a lot? Thanx for reading this email and I will look forward to hearing from you soon. Replies will be greatly appreciated although I understand if I don’t get them straight away. Thanx again. Sincerely Chris ", "answer": "Every once in a while, while surfing the web for new tea flavors, I accidentally end up in one of those crazy forums. I sort of enjoy the Oddworld forums, but some of those other ones, they make me feel funny. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Helloooo Alf! I am your biggest fan of you, your tea, and your wisdom. So, I’ve got a few questions for you, how the heck can you get our e-mails if you don’t live anywhere near our planet? Can you give me some info on this “expresso” drink? (sounds like coffee to me!) And,inspired by your greatness opened my own Tea shop with my own special tea made with my own special ingredients, so I was wondering if you could give me some tips for when the pigions,..er!! customers come.Thanks a lot o great one! – Danny", "answer": "Steep! Steep! My little apprentice! And when you are done steeping, steep some more!!!! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I have noticed that in Abe’s Exoddus that walking and crawling sligs still have visors and flying sligs have two eyes why is that? – Jason", "answer": "Sneaky li’l devils! I would think their beady little eyes have been modified to be better at flying, etc. Yuck. I can’t even stand glasses. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will the Meeches come out in any other Oddworld game? – Jonny E.", "answer": "Whaddaya mean? Onscreen? The way I remember it is that the last box of Meech Munchies was shipped out of RuptureFarms during Abe’s Oddysee. The meeches are an instinct species as far as we know. At least on the continent of Mudos that is. ", "tags": ["RuptureFarms", "Abe’s Oddysee", "Mudos", "Munch"]},

{"question": "I think its about time you guys told us a little about Munch’s Exoddus, like a story line or some new characters? – Justin", "answer": "Coming attractions? … This is the story of Abe, a geeky Mudokon who lives with his Aunt and Uncle. A freak accident miraculously grants him incredible cool insect-like abilities. Abe finds that there’s a thin line between an ordinary Mud and an extraordinary hero; and he’ll have to be the one to cross it. Stay tuned. Molluck, is a sleep-deprived Glukkon detective tracking down a murderer, but accidentally shoots his own partner. Huh, I mean… it’s an adventure of a wild and rambunctious mustang stallion named Elum journeying through the untamed Mudos frontier… Oops! … Agents J and K (Abe and Munch) are back for more battles with alien rabble-rousers who take the form of a host of estrogen-charged extraterrestrials. Whaaa? The next game is set in mythic Middle Oddworld, a young mud named Abe inherits a magic ring from his elderly cousin Alfo. Take your pick! ", "tags": ["Glukkon", "Mudos", "Molluck", "Munch", "Abe", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Guten Tag Alf Sorry ’bout the foreign greeting, I was feeling bilingual today, but on to the serious stuff. It’s about Mud’s hands. They are huge compared to your bodies. I am willing to bet they weigh twenty-five pounds, and could be used to club Glukkon’s brains out. I mean, they are giant. You could guide aircraft with them. I’m surprised that you aren’t weighed down with them. My question: Why? Why do you need such abnormally large hands? -Kathleen", "answer": "To cuddle my abnormally large fuzzle at night. Well, to club something to death, you need a deadly attitude, things like that don’t come easy to us peace-lovin’ mudokon folk. I would prefer that maybe we just grab big bags of tea! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Can you please tell me a bit about those huge statues with the tusks in Necrum. thanks nate_dog", "answer": "The tusk statues are known as Guardians to the Mudokon inhabitants. Legend has it, that at one point in Oddworld’s history they helped defend Necrum from invaders. However, all that is left of their presence in the modern Oddworld record is their fossilized remains. ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "I have a mess of Slig related questions here!!!!!! Lets see if you can answer some. 1. What is the name of the Slig valets name? is he the dude who wears the dress? ", "answer": "The Emcee Slig. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Who is that cute Slig announcer? (call me crazy, but hey a girl could have some fantasies too ya know! -oof", "answer": "Whoof. Well, his name is (strangely enough) Slig Announcer. The reason these guys don’t have personal names… well, they’re trained to be servile to the Glukkons—and you can’t have individuality when that’s the case! ", "tags": ["Slig", "Glukkon"]},

{"question": "What’s the average life span of a paramite and a scrab? – Poltergiest", "answer": "It’s really hard to get a hold of a paramite or a scrab for study. And really, I think I speak for most Mudokons when I say that I’d prefer a hot cup of tea to the scientific investigations of paramite and scrab life expectancies any day. But since you bring it up, I once heard a rumor of an alpha scrab that lived to be 80 years old!!! But maybe that was the brew talkin’—you never know! ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Hi Alf! I’m Robert and I was wondering why Abe has two paramite scars on his hands in Munch’s Oddysee rather than one paramite scar and one scrab scar? I would also like to know why Scrabs and paramites sound different in Munch’s Oddysee?", "answer": "Well, as a close and personal friend of Abey’s, I can tell you for certain he’s got no such scars! He uses a secret blend of herbs and spooces to form a salve that cures all such ailments! The Scrab and Paramite tattoos from Abe’s Oddysee remain the same. ", "tags": ["Abe’s Oddysee", "Paramite", "Scrab", "Abe"]},

{"question": "I suppose I’ll start the normal way… I own all 3 games and they r great. Outta this world, Oddworld is the best bunch of guys (and girls) around!!! Danke! But… We want a fleech comeback!!! Would it be possible for the fleeches in the sewer to get outta control and mutate and take over the real world and develop advanced communicating stuff and pose a new threat as flesh eating mutants and be weird and you get the picture? Just wondering and thanx for your time. – Rod", "answer": "Eh… lemme think… is it possible? Yea. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, I was wondering if Mudokons change their skin color to show their emotions at will or if it just happens when they get moody? For example: When an angry mudokon turns red does he do it on purpose to tell others to stay away or does it happen on its own? If you can change color at will, why is the common color green and why do the mudarchers and tomahawkers turn white? – The Radke’s", "answer": "LESS BIOLOGY, MORE COSMETOLOGY!!!! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf. I had some nagging thoughts in the back of my mind, so I thought I’d give them to you. Hey y’all: Why have you classified the Raisin as ‘wildlife’? I mean, he was born in North Mudos, doesn’t that make him native? – nare k ", "answer": "Can’t you understand? It doesn’t matter what side of Mudos you’re born on. Everyone has their own special abilities and traits that make them special. Like narcolepsy. And… being all wrinkly. And incredibly… Large.. and fruity. ", "tags": ["Mudos"]},

{"question": "What’s going on in that Meep Herder Village? Every time I kill a Meep, it just springs back to life again. Not that I’d want to kill them. Anyway, what tricks are those shepherds up to? Help me out here. ", "answer": "It seems that someone or something on Oddworld has taken an affinity to protecting the Meep. Much in the same way Abe and Munch are brought back to life after dying the Meep are brought back to life too. The whole thing is quite a testament to the survival skills and fortitude of our little furry friends. ", "tags": ["Munch", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Oh yeah, Alf, where do you keep disappearing off to? You’re with Abe in the Raisin’s Cave, you’re there again when you push him into the Big Well. Why can’t you help your buddy instead of rushing off like that? No wonder you haven’t got your own game, you keep chickening out. Still, that’s all from Max, I’ll catch ya later. ", "answer": "Chickening out? Whatever! You gotta understand, that when a guy drinks as much tea as I do, well, when you gotta “go”, you gotta go!!!! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What is the story or meaning behind the two little fetuses in the OW logo? -Xavier ", "answer": "The twin fetuses have long since been absorbed into Oddworld lore. The caliper and test-tube motif for the Oddworld logo was created for a brochure for the 1999 E3 convention. At the time, we were working on two games simultaneously; Munch’s Oddysee and Hand of Odd. As time went on and the gears of corporate commerce kept turning, Hand of Odd faded away and Munch’s Oddysee became the sole focus of production. In the end, Oddworld gave birth to a kicking and screaming Munch’s Oddysee only. This is the history of the twin fetuses. ", "tags": ["Hand of Odd", "Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf here is a simple question, none of that hard biology stuff ; ). When will we be able to see some more pictures of kinto slaves and when will we get to learn more about them? Are they as intelligent as you and the other mudokons or are they more primitive? That’s all. Hope it isn’t to complicated for you. Thanks for all the work and occasional effort you put into answering our questions. —TheKhanzumer", "answer": "It’s hard to say if the Kinto’s are intelligent or not, as their paranoia about things looming above their head sort of limits all of their other abilities. It’s pretty hard to enslave a race that refuses to work in an area with say, a roof or trees or anything overhead. The Glukkons pretty much abandoned the idea of exploiting them when they found it would take an inkling of effort. But who knows, maybe one day they’ll get a burst of motivation and try it again. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": " Thanks for your time, and may the Odd be with ya. —Andrew H.", "answer": "Yes, you are quite rude, and I think your parents would be more upset at your terminology than with me not replying to your Oddworld-shattering email. As for your questions, no one really knows how they possess something, it just happens! I mean, you don’t have to be a gastroenterologist in order to belch, do ya? The same goes for the pants. And if you don’t like my answers, go ask the Raisin!!!! ", "tags": ["Raisin"]},

{"question": "I would like to know, since I haven’t got no Xbox, WHY THE HECK YOU’RE AFRAID OF SLOGGIES?! They are just little buggers you can easily kick out of the way. How come you are afraid of em? —Jose", "answer": "So young, so naive. Without the proper equipment, you can never experience the utter terror a sloggie inflicts on its prey. And without living here in Mudos, I fear you can never even come close to the barking, slobber dripping, tongue slapping, teeth like razors reality of what a Sloggie really is. ", "tags": ["Mudos", "Slog"]},

{"question": "thanks alot Alf from daz36", "answer": "You have much to learn about the spirit world, which cannot be seen by you or I. Sometimes we just have to think of a way to represent it as closely as we can. Even then, there is still much to be interpreted. Go now, and meditate on this. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi Alf! u know ur rehab and tea? We’ve all heard of the delicious tea with its golden leaves… but what about the rehab? Do They nurse sick soulstorm brew drinking mudokons? Or is it just for mudokons who’ve had too much tea? Also, is there a killing bonus in Abe’s Exoddus if u kill all nearly all da mudokons? Not that I would do that. I just want to confirm rumours. THANX ALF luv NIC XXXX", "answer": "Too much tea? There is no such thing! And for the record, killing one Mudokon is killing one too many!!!! ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Hi do u remember me I’m Kaled from Egypt I’m sorry for late my answer about your mail because I’m was busy in school. but I ask you when Munch’s Exoddus finished? and please answer this question. your Kaled from Egypt ", "answer": "Hi Kaled, Munch’s Exoddus? Is Munch going somewhere? Where is he going? Do you think he’ll stop by for tea? I should fix this place up if he’s coming by! There are used tea bags everywhere! I’ve got to go!!!! ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "Alf- I’ve been working hard at getting the next to impossible Black Quarma (I have an evil side) How in the heck am I supposed to pass the first level with Munch without saving a fuzzle! the Crawdaddy", "answer": "Skill. Reflexes. Hand-eye coordination. Determination. Opposable thumbs. You get the picture. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Two months ago somebody asked if you have ever eaten a Mudokon Pop. You said that’s disgusting. You’re absolutely right, but you DID drink Soulstorm Brew. And THAT’S made of MUDOKON BONES AND TEARS! What’s it all about Alfie??? —The Biggest Dutch Mudokon ", "answer": "Dear Charell, Why you gotta go and bring up that horrible business? It is true, the Glukkons tricked us into thinking that stuff was so good, and we believed ’em, with their slick advertising and chemical preservatives. Seemed good at the time; we didn’t know! Thank goodness for our buddy Abe, who saved us from that whole nasty mess. Even by then we were so addicted it was downright hard to quit. That’s why I started the Rehab! Now if I could just kick the tea . . . ", "tags": ["Glukkon", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf, I was wondering: how come there’s no Shrykull power in Munch’s Oddysee? I mean, you have got to be pulling Mudokon’s arms out of there sockets to get away with no Shrykull power. It was a great and cool way to help Abe take out those Glukkons in RuptureFarms. And Abe still has those hand scars and he just let them go to waste in this one. So, why didn’t Abe use the grand power of the Shrykull? It could have come in useful in Vykker’s Labs. —Colin", "answer": "Woa! Hey, there now! Let’s not get carried away … there’s no need to go pulling arms out of sockets just because you didn’t get your Shrykull fix in Munch’s Oddysee. I think Abe just thought his other skills were better suited this go ’round. I mean, we wouldn’t want it to be too easy on the poor bugger! Besides it’s called Munch’s Oddysee and Abe didn’t want to show up Munch. ", "tags": ["Abe", "Munch", "Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Do you have a release date for Munchs Exoddus because I have finished Munchs Oddysee? Do you know if Shrink will return to the games because his appearance in Abes Oddysee was very brief? —Shrykull ", "answer": "Congratulations! You finished Munch’s Oddysee! Now play it again and quit asking so many questions! P.S. Can you answer Colin’s question? I think he’s about to go nutso on us I hope the Shrink does return because, well, ahem… I think one of our fans could use his help… ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Do GLUKKONS have moolah if they don’t yousit —Jose", "answer": "Dear Jose, NO! You sit! Why should I have to sit? Huh? Wha? Oh, right … GLUKKONS dew yous moolah, to bye smokes, sparkly soots, and priceless food items like Gabbiar. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "yo Alf y can’t mudokons pkup weapons form sligs? form your bast bud sean", "answer": "It isn’t a matter of can or cannot, but a matter of want or not want. I’d much rather pick up a nice, warm steamin’ cup ‘o tea. Ahhhh, now that sounds nice. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "In the intern’s groove music, what are the lyrics being sung/chanted? — Nathan Alf Rocks!", "answer": "He rocks! He drinks tea, he answers silly questions, and… He rocks! Chorus He Rocks! Oh yeah, he rocks! Alf Rocks! Well, that’s what I hear, anyway. You probably heard: “If you could save my life I’d meet you at the lightpole, baby.” ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I wanted to ask you why is it that only Abe can save the Mudokons by chanting. — Harry ", "answer": "If you’ve found a method better than chanting, please, let us know! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I was walking around in the FeeCo Depot and I noticed a sign that said Vykkers Lab coming soon! And since Vykkers Labs is a flying fortress how could a train get there if it’s in the sky? And how come Shock Rockers were in the book thingy that comes with the game but not in the game? — James.", "answer": "Sometimes things come soon to places other than where their posters are hung. For example, if you were at your local drug store, and they had a poster that said, “Bobo’s Circus, coming soon!” You wouldn’t expect the circus to set up shop right there in the toiletries department, would you? Don’t be silly! And the ShockRockers… well, their equipment was shoddy and they shocked themselves right out of the game! Crazy! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Thanks for the time. Hope to hear from you soon. — Geoff ", "answer": "Mudarchers power their bows with Spooce. And as you probably know, if you run out of spooce, you can always grow some more! I would love to dedicate some of my time to short film and/or gameplay, but I find that the rehab keeps me quite busy. My Brethren need me! As for the poor blind folk: If they did get their stitches snipped, their poor eyes would never adjust to the light after being closed so long. It’s a shame. Better to be blind and free than blind and a food product, though! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I ‘d like to know what Mudokon clothes are made of. I ‘ve seen meeps so you obviously have wool. But you don’t seem to be wearing any wool clothing so what other fabrics are your clothes made of? — Kleeng ", "answer": "I don’t know if meeps give “wool”, though they may contribute to the textile production process … at the fertilizer level. Various plants are used to create our light, comfortable and stylish loincloths. They are handcrafted by Mudokons who don’t have to spend all of their time answering questions about interplanetary fashion! ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Hi Alf! My name is Robert and I have a question for you. Do fuzzles have a queen? ", "answer": "Hi Robert! I’ve never seen a Fuzzle queen, but I’ve never seen any of the other queens, either. Most creatures on Oddworld are descended from a queen, so it is safe to say … Probably. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Since Glukkons only have vestigial stubs for legs and walk on their hands, I just have to wonder … What happened to the Glukkons’ legs? And does having hands in your shoes make your shoes smell as much as having feet in them does? Thanks a bunch! — Jon", "answer": "Well Jon, when your species doesn’t use something, generation after generation, it degenerates to a pathetic, good for nothing stub. You know: use it or lose it! And I don’t know about having your hands in your shoes, but I do know that everything about a Glukkon STINKS! ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "Hi, how are you? I don’t know where I’ve read about Abe’s fingers, I was just reading the website. I want to ask you, how do you perform the games? Have all of you studied computation or you are a team of musicians, drawers, computer designer etc? — Facundo ", "answer": "I’m tea-riffic! Oddworld has Production Artists, Modelers, Animators, Real-time Artists, Programmers, a Sound Designer/Composer, Technical Support and an Administration staff that all work together on the games. Not to mention the kind upper management, who have never once threatened to sew anyone’s eyes or mouths shut! Isn’t that sweet? Just one more benefit of being an Oddworld Employee! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi Alf I just wanted to ask you a simple little question. It is said that the true evil of Oddworld will be revealed. Does this mean that the Glukkons and other Industrialist are not the bad guys? And if so do you know who will be the true bad guys? Or will there even be a bad guy as some of us think. I hope this question wont force you to reveal much. But I am curious. — Kaimana ", "answer": "Kaimana, you should know by now that you can’t force Alfie to do much of anything! In general when people refer to “true” evil, it is usually what’s considered most evil of all, or the source of all evils. Glukkons and Industrialists are bad guys, but someone or something causes them to be that way, right? ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "When is oddworld 4 coming out, what is its name, and what system is it coming out for. — Matt ", "answer": "Oddworld 4, codename “Oddworld 4”, will be coming out sometime in the future. Only on Xbox! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi Alf! My name is Robert and I would like some info on Mudflubs and Khanzumerz please. ", "answer": "Hi Robert! I would love to give you some info on Mudflubs and Khanzumerz, but they are folks whose stories are still in the making. It would be like writing the biography of a three-year-old. Sometimes characters are released, but then don’t make it into the games, and fans such as yourself are let down because they’ve heard or seen something about them. Which is why you won’t be hearing ANYTHING about Oddworld 4 until the time is right! Sorry, bud! ", "tags": ["Khanzumer"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf what is it like to ride an Elum?????????? — Brad", "answer": "Stinky, sweaty, bumpy. All the things one looks for in affordable transportation. Comparable in your world to “Public Transit”. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf I’ ve been wondering, if Mudokons don’t use moolah why does Sam (Mudokon Queen) give her eggs away to Glukkons or do they offer it but she doesn’t except it. Thanks alot, Daz36.", "answer": "Well, neither! She doesn’t give them away, but what she gets in return is not moolah. Let’s just say that in addition to other things, her employee benefits offer an outstanding prescription drug plan. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I’ve got another question to ask you Alf. In your first two games Scrabs were extremely territorial but in the third they don’t fight at all. What’s up with that! -Jason ", "answer": "Well, I’ve never gotten close enough to a scrab to ask him, but they seem to be much less hostile in the outdoors. Captivity does something to a creature, you know? Makes every inch of space more valuable. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "— Dark Xinos (Forum guy)   PS. You should visit the forum more often Alfie! We NEED you!!", "answer": "Xinos, I cannot answer a man who faintly tastes deodorant. I just can’t. It is wrong, so very, very wrong. But I will visit the forums, they’re swell! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What’s going to happen to Oddworld Inhabitants when the Quintology is completed? — Andrew ", "answer": "Quintology II! Starring . . . ALF! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Beloved Alf, I admire your generosity in answering your fans’ mail no matter how stupid the question. I have a question myself. Are sligs distantly related to paramites? They’ve both got the “finger things” around the mouth and are almost the same size. I know mentioning sligs and paramites in the same sentence kind of degrades the paramites’ name but I’ve got to know! ", "answer": "Yes, how observant of you to notice how generous I am! Goodness I’m blushing! I am so overwhelmed by this moment we’ve had! What a wonderful reminder of how, on one level or another, we are all related. Hugs, anyone??? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hello Alf, If Scrabs fight and kill each other every time they meet,how come they aren’t extinct? Maybe they have some strange mating ritual whilst fighting,maybe they reproduce alone or is there another reason……..Thanks for now……..Long Live Abe !!! —Johnny Q. ", "answer": "Yeah they fight a lot but they don’t kill each other off every time. It’s when you get two dominant Scrabs together that’s when it gets REALLY ugly! ", "tags": ["Scrab"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf, What sort of things do you like to watch on TV? How many channels do you guys get? I already know about Magog On the March (M.O.M.) and FUD Network, but what else do you guys like to watch on the tube? Also, what is the deal with that article in the Daily Deception? The one about you slapping people? Thanks, Khanz ", "answer": "I know that I am a celebrity, and that by dedicating my life to tea and rehabilitation I automatically put myself “out there” in the public eye, but this has gone too far! The tabloids, the intrusive questioning! Underneath the glamour I am just a Mud like everyone else! Why doesn’t anyone understand that? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Alf Man! As there are so many Wanted Posters of Abe and Munch, could you, Buddy, Abe, or Munch get some for us loyal fans? And, how come some Mudokons have more feathers than others? Great Site by the way. Thanks, toddmann. p.s. Really Great site. ", "answer": "Todd Man! Thanks! There aren’t as many wanted posters as you’d think. They gave Abe and Munch a funny feeling, so they pretty much tear ’em up whenever they see one. The feather question is simply a result of a traditional supply and demand scenario. ", "tags": ["Munch", "Abe"]},

{"question": "I forgot to mention in my other letter, in Munch’s Odysee, the good ending, When Lulu is betting or about to, a lot of clapping is going on. I understand they wanna clap but how!? Glukkons dont have arms and the Vykkers looked to be less then 1/3 of the bidders. Alright then… good luck with your tea. ", "answer": "Not entirely true. Though shamefully tiny, useless and hidden, Glukkons DO have arms and hands. Also, Vykkers have double the appendages of the average Inhabitant, AND they are fierce clappers. But you know, it wouldn’t surprise me if they invented some sort of clapping amplifier to make others believe that they are even better at it than they really are. Showoffs!!! ", "tags": ["Glukkon", "Vykker"]},

{"question": "In O.World Munch’s Oddysee why the (pardon my language)H*** the fuzzles eat you when you get terrible quarma at level 23 Loading docks. Please this happened 3 times exactly so help me out here will ya? The Weirdo and Mud Worshiper —Cody ", "answer": "Hi Cody. Try getting good Quarma. I think this will solve your problem, as the essence of Quarma is “what comes around, goes around,” to put it in a Fuzzle’s perspective. Besides, wouldn’t you be a little vindictive if your buddies left you to suffer in Vykker’s Lab? ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "How old is BigFace? Who’s the oldest Mudokon you know?", "answer": "BigFace many years old. Raisin Older. Raisin Eldest Elder Alf know. ", "tags": ["Raisin"]},

{"question": "YO!! do u know anything about the release date of Munch’s Oddysee gor GBA?? i would like to know… Also, y is your name alf? y isnt it Calvin…or Janet? PEACE OUT!! —Phil ", "answer": "My name is Alf because I was named after an Inhabitant in Leicester, England. Named Alf. You can read about him in the November 2000 archives. Calvin and Janet are fine names, just not “me”. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf! Why on Abe’s Exoddus the sligs masks have been changed? And do u feel sorry for sligs because they’ve been neglected by skillya? Also 1 more thing, has a scrab attacked u ? stay odd —Declan ", "answer": "I hear the sligs have great systems admin, and keep up on all the latest technology, hence the upgrade in face masks. Do I feel sorry for the them? Puh-leaze. Where is Alf’s mommy? What about my needs? Does anyone feel sorry for me? NO! And to wrap up, a reality check: Had I been attacked by a scrab I would be in that big Rehab in the sky, not down here doin’ dis! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What customers have you had lately?did elum come to your shop to have honey in his tea? And is their anyone else on Oddworld I can e mail? —Brad ", "answer": "Hi Brad. Yes, Elum likes to stop by, but more for honey than tea, I think! He’s got an insatiable sweet tooth. Sorry to say that I am the only one you can email, though I am always happy to pass on the occasional message to other Inhabitants! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, What happend to the idea for Elum and the Flying Sligs!! They were some of the greatest things I think, but I have one question: Will Elum or the Flying sligs ever return?? —the one who mix’s dish soap with his ice tea, Abe’s Son ", "answer": "Well, those ideas got used. Now there are new ideas! Wassamatta? You don’t like new ideas? You think it’s ok for you to think of new ideas (i.e. mixing dish soap w/ice tea) but we’re supposed to just keep doing the same thing over and over?! Maybe you should try your tea with a dash of Hypocrite! Or a twist of Infidel! Maybe a dollop of Deceiver! Or just a touch of Blasphemer! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Thanx, Robbie ", "answer": "1. Upgrades my man, upgrades. It takes the very best technology to constantly maintain the level of sham that Sligs do. 2. Hmmm. Think you’re mistaken. Look again. Closer … Closer … is your nose touching the screen? Get a little closer. Closer! 3. No silly!!!! 4. Sligs have been known to name their masks Fred, Bob, and Phyllis. But they are generally referred to as “Slig Masks”. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Hi Alf! I’ve got a little question for Abe: When is you birthday? I would LOVE to know that! Take care and stay Odd all you Muds out there! And specially Abe and Alfieeeeeee! Kissies, AbeLover (Dutch girl named Charell)", "answer": "After years of Brew addiction, not even Abe remembers when he was hatched! And rumour has it the employee records all hit the shredder during the big SoulStorm audit! ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf, how’s it goin on Oddworld? I hope your rehab and tea is doing well. I was just wondering about future video games based on the happenings of Oddworld. As in, what’s a sea rex, how do Kinto slaves fit into all of this, what are some possibilities of future game names, etc. I know you must get these kind of questions a lot, and they probably bug the heck outta you, so I’m sorry. I just thought it would be worth a shot. Anyways, I hope everything is well and that Abe is staying out of trouble. Bye the way, nice new website. —SLIGcatcher", "answer": "Fine. Thanks! Oh. Hmmm. Yes, yes, that’s ok. Sure it is. Yeah, sure, everything’s fine! Thanks. Okay. Buhbye now. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hello Alf, I have been a big fan of the Oddworld games for a while. I have the first two, I’m still savin’ for an Xbox, but I have a question for you. Why aren’t there any female mudokons??? What the heck did I miss??? Please clear this matter up for me. From Bryce ", "answer": "Bryce, You didn’t miss anything! Female Mudokons haven’t been seen in the Quintology. Us Muds are so in touch with our feminine side we thought you’d be perfectly content with guys like me and Abe! ", "tags": ["Abe", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "If I want to start a fan Site do I have to get an OK from you?", "answer": "Create your own Oddworld approved fansite you say? Well my friend, just follow these three easy steps! Make a fan website. Get pictures, text and ideas from the internet or wherever. Then send a link to your fabulous fan creation to fanlegal@oddworld.com. (This way we can approve it and give you the proper disclaimers.) VOILA!!! Your very own Oddworld fan website! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf!!! This will be a quick one since I have to go to school soon. I was wondering, do Mudokons have noses? Can you guys smell things? Like, when your really close to a filthy slig, could you say they smell in a literall sense? Ok, thanks for your time, Alf! Talk ta ya latta. SLIGcatcher ", "answer": "Well I know for sure that Abe can make some pretty noxious smells, so I guess that means we can smell things! Have fun at school! ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Anyway, can you just answer a couple of questions to sum this up, How are Mudokons bred and what happened to the female population if there is one?", "answer": "You are a genius! Studying the female species could really shed light on how Mudokon eggs are produced! Uh, gotta go, I need to get out my little black book. *wink wink* I’ll get back to you, I have some uh, research to do! ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "In Munch’s Oddysee, doesn’t Munch break his leg in the trap? It said that somewhere on the website. Anyway, if his leg was broken, how come he hops around as soon as the fuzzles break him out of his bonds? Love your games and website. Gobi the talented camel. ", "answer": "The Vykker’s mended his broken leg. Those snaggle toothed freaks got him in tip-top condition so he could lead them to more pharmaceutical fodder. Vykkers become very kind and generous when it comes to the bottom line! ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "I love playing videogames with my buds all the time. My mom thinks I should get outside once in awhile and get a life. She’s threatened to take away my Xbox. I don’t know what to do cuz I love videogames so much. I know you love ’em too. I don’t care about girls cuz they are all thumbs. What should I do Alf? Your pal Ryan. ", "answer": "Ryan, that whole “outside” and “life” junk is completely overrated. I stopped drinking tea once to check out some other interests. You know, brew drinkin’, stuff like that. BO-ring! Now I’m back in my routine and happy as ratz in a biohazard container! Yeee-hooo, boy! Perhaps a new hairstyle or wig is a better answer to your need for change. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Heya Alf, I luv Oddworld! I’m obsessed by anything ODD! I’m thinkin of getting an Odd tattoo on my back. My wife and kids say I’ll regret it but I love Oddworld so much. Anything else I can do besides a Tattoo? In Odd We Trust … forever yours, Warren. ", "answer": "No way Warren, this idea is way out there. You should not even consider this for another moment. You see, getting a tattoo is a big step and will last forever. So why would you want one on your back? It totally has to be on your belly, so that you can look down and see it anytime ya want! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "If you could switch jobs with any other Mud, what would you do? Thanx, Jen.", "answer": "Tea brewing and chillin’ with my buds is where my heart’s at. I wouldn’t have it any other way! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, I have a theory. If you put females in your games then more girls will play them. If more girls play games then boys can play games with them. Make sense? ", "answer": "Huh. Never thought of that. I just always assumed girls wanted to play as male characters, or as girls with genetically inconceivable proportions. How ’bout if we just make gender-neutral characters with boy names??? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I want to give my brother an Oddworld related gift for Hannukah. I can’t decide between the Paramite Pies, Scrab Cakes or Elum Chubs. Are these items kosher? Thanks in advance, Mo. ", "answer": "Odd-vey! NO WAY! Don’t be a schlemiel! Try a nice matzo-sculpture of our buddy Elum instead. Or perhaps a few spooce-shaped chocolates wrapped in gold foil! Kids these days, I tell ya! Some of ’em I’d like ta kick in the tuchis! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, how come abe cannot turn into a shrykull all the time but needs a special portal? Is it spooce?", "answer": "Spooce it is not. There are just certain, rewarding moments in life when Abe gets to take advantage of the shrykull. A tear in the otherwise oppressive fabric of fairness, if you will. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Since the sligs caught the gabbits befor at the end of the game what is going to stop them from catching the new baby gabbits again? ", "answer": "Hmmmm. Sounds like a job for an unlikely hero to me! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Ok, I just wanted to know why do Interns realy have thier mouth sewn shut and feet, hoves, etc cut off? I also just wanted to know if Interns were made for the Vykkers for personal use or have they always been what they are today? ", "answer": "Yes, interns really do have their mouths sewn shut. This is to prevent them from whistling annoying techno and trance tunes while working. Unfortunately, they can still email and surf the net. They do also have hooves, this is hard to notice because they seem to be the same size as their leg bones, unlike a horse or a pig, where the hoof is semi-cone-shaped. Nothing’s been cut off yet, but I’m not sayin’ it couldn’t happen! The interns weren’t created, but like so many of the poor critters that cross the threshold of Vykker’s Labs, they’ve undergone slight “mODDifications”. ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "ALFY MY CHUM! I must ask a question of you, what ever became of fleeches and greeters and slurgs, you guys did’nt put em in the third game.", "answer": "They are still fleeching, greeting, and slurging around Oddworld, they just didn’t make it into Munch’s story. Better luck next time, ay? ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "Is Abe the only Mud with the power to open bird portals?", "answer": "Yes, Abe is special. But I have been known to open tea canisters and sugar packets. Doesn’t that count for anything? ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Why did the Glukkons choose Abe as an ad campaign, all Mud product posters show blue skin, not the common green. Even Mudokon Pops are blue!", "answer": "Studies show that nine out of ten muds prefer the color blue, especially in the edibles category. It’s all about targeting your market, bud. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Why was Abe’s mouth stapled shut? No other Muds in stapled have this done to them.", "answer": "Not stapled, stitched! Abe was a noisy, whiny, cry baby and no one could stand his incessant blabber, so they sewed him up tight. Not too tight to have a brew, though! ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "In the bad Exoddus ending you cannot see Abe’s feet when he is in the tear extractor, but when you see Muds in the game you can easily see their feet. Also, why do their loin-clothes stay on their legs?", "answer": "What the heck are you talking about? That isn’t even a question. I’m sorry that you can’t see Abe’s feet. There. Are you happy now? And the loincloths happen to be heavily starched, OK? Every good, upstanding citizen of Mudos knows that a well starched Mudokon is a happy Mudokon. ", "tags": ["Mudos", "Abe", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf how is it going in the world of odd? And how is your tea coming? My name is Dave and I am a huge Oddworld fanatic. I pretty much love Oddworld so much I am a member of the Oddworld forums. Ok enough with the pointless talking. I have these two iching questions and I need your answer. How big is a Sea Rex? And will we see them in future games?", "answer": "Well things would be better if people made sense, but I don’t want to ask too much of the human race. ANYWAY, here’s some soothing ointment for your itch: It is very difficult to determine the size of a sea rex because they are constantly undulating through the water, and are never lain out straight next to another critter where you could make some kind of a comparison. I just know they’re big, cause no one wants to catch ’em … either that or they just taste bad! They’re probably the largest animal I know of on Oddworld, though! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Alfy baby, Ya cool by me you’re actually one a my favorite characters and do the sligs despise the Glukkons even though they serve’em an’ all? ", "answer": "They don’t despise the glukkons, they probably aren’t capable of thinking enough to despise them. They do, however, have a natural desire for the nurturing and attention that they were deprived of as children. They are also easily impressed by status, and therefore I would guess are highly susceptible to abusive relationships, such as serving the Gluks. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I have one question that has been bothering me for a while. What happened in the desert while travelling with Abe that the cameras didn’t show? Anything funny? ", "answer": "You mean when the thing was all whatever, and we all went AAAAHHHH and then that one time when the hahahhahhaaaaaaaaaa! Man that was so funny! And oh my gosh there was this one thing that was all blabidyybalbllllaaaa! And we were like all, “Whoaaaaa!” That was like, I don’t even know what! I was just like, couldn’t even believe that that even happened! Dems good times, man, good times. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Has Munch started his colony of Gabbits yet? Or has his lungs been stolen.", "answer": "Colony starting is a far more complicated process than one might expect. You can’t just dump the eggs in the water, stir well, rinse and repeat. These things typically take some time, so my guess is that he’s still in the planning stages. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "When do ya hope to kick off you merchandise? I sooooooooo want a collection of posable action figures from oddworld.", "answer": "Wouldn’t you rather save your money for things you really need? Like books, wholesome vegetables, and a warm winter coat? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, me again. I was wondering: where does Abe go when he’s not out possesing Sligs or blowing up boilers and stuff like that. I mean, he must have a break in between his missions, right? So what does he do? Does he hang with the Big Raisin in Raisin’s Cave, does he chill out with Big Face in Mosaic Lines, does he go drink some tea at your Rehab and Tea? Thanks for your time. ", "answer": "Abe used to just sit around watching the tube and drinkin’ brew all day. Last I heard lately he’s into hot yoga and soap making. Saving your species brings many changes to a mud. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "And did Elum die ???", "answer": "Elum is a species, so the whole species did not die, no. But alas, we did come to know and love Abe’s Elum as far more than just a mode of transport. He had an untimely ending on the RuptureFarms chopping block. Unfortunately, Elums are known not only as good pack animals, but also as a valuable commodity for Sloggy Chow and Elumer’s Glue. ", "tags": ["Abe", "Slog", "RuptureFarms"]},

{"question": "Are fuzzles predators ??? (Cuz their teeth are so sharp)", "answer": "Fuzzles are little sweety-pies that have been genetically altered and are pretty peeved about it. Calling them a predator implies that they victimize and destroy for their own personal gain, yet we saw in Munch’s Oddysee that they are perfectly willing to do that for the good of others, as well! I’d say they’re more passive aggressive than predator. ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "I’m only wondering where’s BigFace? I haven’t seen him since Abe left to Necrum Mines with his friends. Can we see him anymore?", "answer": "Well, at the last sewing circle, I heard BigFace went to one of those “stress reduction” spas, and no one has seen him in weeks! If you ask me it’s a flimsy coverup for a face job- you have no idea how hard it is to live a name like “BigFace” down when that is exactly what you have. I actually feel sorry for the chump. But you didn’t hear it from me! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What powers the slig’s pants? oil? gasoline? batteries? Thanks… Oddworld rocks! ", "answer": "Vykker’s Pharmaceuticals is always looking for newer, cheaper, more destructive ways to better serve the greedy. Fuel is from Magog Motors. ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "Help, I’ve been using the Odd icons for the past two years, I have now had my computer updated and have lost the icons. Are they still available to download or are they lost forever???", "answer": "Yes! Oddicons are back by popular demand. Check out the downloads section of this site early 2003. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alfie, can you give me some info about Munch’s Exoddus?", "answer": "Uh, no! Check out the FAQ’s will ya? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, Me and a few of the guys at The Forums are wondering something, what Abes loin cloth for?? I know its been asked sometime before, but Ive forgotten what you said. Someone actually thought that it has some kind of spiritual significance, but I assured him that skid marks would be the only out-of-the-ordinary thing about them, so we’re all kinda skeptical at the moment. Thanks if you help us out and we’ll see ya next time youre in chat….or something. —BigBro ", "answer": "BigBro, Even skid marks are highly unlikely with a loincloth, as you should know, they don’t have a traditional crotch like your typical, modern-day undies. A loincloth is like a skirt, only without the feminine stigma earth folk so often attribute to skirts. (Think kilt.) The significance and purpose of the loincloth is both practical and fashionable. One doesn’t necessarily want his bum exposed to even his closest of buddies, and it has been known to get pretty chilly at times here in Mudos, so it is the most efficient way of keeping that area warm while still providing necessary mobility for the active, “Mud on the go”. ", "tags": ["Mudos"]},

{"question": "I just completed Munchs Oddysee for the third time this time I rescued everything. I can’t wait until the next game could you answer a question for me, I found something on an oddworld fansite called Humshrubs that look like spooce but are pink do you know what happened to them? Are Slig Guard towers going to featured in future games? Thanks Shrykull68 ", "answer": "“Humshrub” was a work-in-progress name for Spooce. They were later renamed and the color was changed. Why? Because! That’s why! That’s also why you’re not hearing too much about the next title. This way it will all be a big surprise, with no confusion or let down about what didn’t make it into the game. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Thanks a lot Bro. From Barnaby ", "answer": "Hey Barnaby, It always bothers me, but I’ll get over it. 1. Well, I don’t know much about the next game, but since Munch IS a Gabbit, I don’t see any reason why he wouldn’t be able to communicate with them, unless that headport has affected his social skills in some way… 2. Hand of Odd is not yet. 3. Sometimes it’s better to be lovable than playable. 4. OI finish the OQ? FYI – I think your IQ needs some TLC! TTFN! ", "tags": ["Munch", "Hand of Odd", "Gabbit"]},

{"question": "Hi alf I was wondering if well could you give me the cheat for the extra endings for M.O. I promise on all that is odd I won’t tell a soul unless you tell me to. In odd we trust .", "answer": "Yeah … in Odd we trust. Not in cheaters! No dice chump! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf. I’ve this is gonna be the best Christmas ever,I got the OWI x-mas card in the mail.that was cool.plus I sneaked a peek at what I’m getting.so anyway, I was wondering, is the mudokon queen Sam ever going to make an appearance? ", "answer": "Yes. Though when, where and to whom has yet to be decided. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I was just wondering if there is anything more powerful than a Shrykull? Furthermore, do you know when (or if) there is going to be a last game of Oddworld? (I hope not.) Your best fan, Dylan ", "answer": "Hi Dylan, nothing that I know of is more spiritually powerful than a Shrykull. But it’s like anything, the answer is limited to my experience. There may be something more powerful than any of us can imagine lurking out there, just waiting for the right moment to reveal itself. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Thanks for your time, Jerry ", "answer": "1. A squeek is a short shrill cry or sound, such as that made by a mouse or rusty hinge, or a mudokon attempting to maintain composure while answering the most annoying questions on all of Oddworld … 2. Because you’re funny lookin’. 3. The story stays the same but not all of was included. There were parts of Munch that will remain a mystery … at least for now. ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "I know the Glukkons manufacture a lot of products, but who buys them, because other Glukkons don’t seem like the buying type. Just wondering, Stranger. ", "answer": "Hey there, Stranger. Do you ever find yourself wondering, “who am I?”. Heh heh heh! Oh I crack me up. Anyway, yeah, you’re right. Glukkons are not only stingy, but they know all the nasty stuff in the products they make. That’s why they count on the other creatures of Oddworld, coupled with mind-bending propaganda to earn their profits. ", "tags": ["Stranger", "Glukkon"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf, its me once again. In Oddworld: Munch’s Oddysee, their are those Blitzpacker drinks, but in Oddworld: Abe’s Exoddus, there’s Soul Storm Brew. I know they are both bad and probably the same to you, but whats the difference? Are they 2 different, competing brands, a new-and-improved version, or what? Anyways, thanks for answering this, and happy holidays. SLIGcatcher ", "answer": "Hi SLIGcatcher. Blitzpacker is a beverage power up for possessed sligs, while SoulStorm Brew is the Glukkon’s drink of choice for addicting and controlling the Mudokon race. See the difference? ", "tags": ["Glukkon", "Mudokon", "SoulStorm Brew"]},

{"question": "Which mud are you? Are you the one that pushes Abe into the big-well? ", "answer": "Let’s be clear about that so-called “pushing” scenario. I merely gave my buddy Abe a gentle, encouraging pat on the back, like any good friend would. Abe, being clumsy and of course subconsciously wanting to go into the big well, FELL at the same time as the gentle pat. OK? Got it? Or do I need to be a good friend to you, too? Huh? Well do I? ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Hay Alf! I just wanted to know some stuff about the Glukkon Queen and why Abe doesn’t attack her. ", "answer": "Hay-ay! Alfie in the Hay-ouse! Whudup? Hey, here’s an idea: Why don’t you just go and attack the ruthless and oppressive leader of another race? It’s not easy, there is planning, tactical training, and brew induced confidence that has to be achieved prior to such attacks! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf my favorite mud, Hows it going man any new female muds you got your eye on? Well enough of the formal talk I was wondering who wrote all the poetry that Abe says in his games? Was it Bigface or Raisin perhaps anyway whoever wrote it maybe OWI can publish all the poetry and stuff in a book and maybe even some fan poetry like the stuff found on the site….that might be a good idea for merchandizing eh taking some money out from the glukkons greedy paws or wait umm whatever they hold their money with. ", "answer": "Have you ever seen a female mud? Bluckhhhaaaaaaa! They aren’t as attractive as you may think! Anyway, Abe isn’t reciting poetry in the games, he is narrating, speaking from his heart! He is the one who spoke the poems that you heard. (I don’t even know if he can write, but if he can, I’ll ask him to make a book of them!) ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "hey alf! your my fav mud. i have a simple question, what are the dominant species on oddworld, i always like to think it were the glukkons who i have the honour to serve … but i guess they are not, maybe you know? terry the slig ", "answer": "Well, it depends on the point in history that we are talking about. I believe it is the waxing and waning of the moons that causes the rise and fall of these cultures; it causes the tide, it makes the weirdos come out, and no one else seems to have a better explanation. And with multiple moons, well, things get pretty crazy around here! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Alf, yer just the greatest 🙂 First of all, that book you are holding in you’re hand on the photo of you …yes, that’s right,the one just over, yup thats it. Can I see it? Let me take a different approch. Can you guy’s at OWI write a few books for puplishing? I would looove to sit down with a nice fairy tale about Oddworld. Not that I have anything against Fan Fiction, but it’s just not the same thing. It’s not as “real” (ahem). So, Alfie, when you got some spare time, could you either write a novel or two or lend me that book you’re reading. Secondly, I would like a quick question. How come Abe has a tatoo on his chest in the cinematics and not in the game? (That would be Abe’s Exoddus, not Munch’s Oddysee). ", "answer": "First of all, I know I am, now get over it! Abe’s tattoo? What’re your eyes stitched up or something? The tat is there. Maybe it’s just so dark in the mines that you can’t see it. As for a book … Sure, I’ll write a book. Let’s see … I can pencil that in for tomorrow at … 3:30? Is that good for you? Assistant! Assistant! Get that on my books, will you? Yes, that’s right, tea at 3:00, write novel at 3:30, and tea again at 4:00. Thank you, dear. Now be gone with you filthy beast! ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Hi, I was just at oddworld.com and it said to send an email here if you had a question about the website. I was just wondering how come there aren’t any Christmas pictures this year? I’ve been looking around and I can’t see any… The past few years there have been some really good ones and I was looking forward to seeing more this year. OK that’s my question. I’m sorry if I wasn’t supposed to send it here, I didn’t mean to waste your time. Thanks Kram (from Australia) ", "answer": "Kram, you are all wasting my valuable tea drinking time, but I am loving and benevolent, so I carry on. You’re welcome. We wanted to post the Christmas pictures, but frankly they were all too inappropriate to be posted. You know that people watch the internet all the time, right now in fact. That is all I can say. I’ve already said too much. Out. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, in Exoddus how can you tell which mud you are in the desert scene? One more thing can Munch, Abe and his fellow mud’s survive really high falls, because in Munch’s Odysee Abe can chuck his fellow Mud’s and Munch from really high platforms or buildings without them getting hurt, and speaking of Abe chucking his fellow mud’s can the mud’s jump for themselves or does Abe need to pick them up and throw them?Thanks Alf, I’m a fan of you and the Oddworld Universe. ", "answer": "I am the severely dehydrated one. When not dehydrated, Mudokons have amazing rubber-like qualities that prevent them from injury. And yes, we can jump for ourselves, but muds are like little children. When you are in a hurry, sometimes it’s just easier and faster to DO IT FOR THEM! ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Hi Alf, seeing as Munch’s Oddysee is exclusive to XBOX, Why can”t GW make a shorter cheaper game exclusive to PS2?", "answer": "So you are requesting a shorter, cheaper “Munch-Lite”? Let me explain something to you: short and cheap, BAD. Full length and quality, GOOD. ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "Hi Alf, it’s me again. Could you PLEASE tell me how the industrial facilities are built and who builds them? Does it take a long time, because those factories are HUGE! Thanks, Phlibbo ", "answer": "Slave labor, mostly. The more slaves you have, the less time it takes. The industrialists love to waste materials too, thus they “super size” there facilities. The more trees they can cut and the more rivers they can pollute, the bigger they feel. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I know Glukkons and Vykkers produce their…products…to make moolah. To make moolah you have to have customers. It doesn’t seem like the Mudokons would be their only source of income. Who are the other customers? Or am i just utterly wrong, and the Mudokons support the bad guys bank accounts?", "answer": "I suppose YOU’VE never bought anything that supported anyone but good doers! See if you can make clear consumer decisions while your mind is reeling from the case of brew you just drank! We didn’t always know what was in those products! We thought if it tasted good, it must be good! That’s what the commercials all said. I want my mommy! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How come the blind mudokon on Abe’s Exoddus(where you drank all that brew)fell down a hole, was there 301 Muds and if you can’t answer this, ask Abe or Lorne L. ", "answer": "Lorne says I don’t have to answer any more if I don’t want to. He says I can have tea and a biscuit and take a nap. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, Where does the name Magog Cartel come from? Love Kurdt", "answer": "Kurdt, I love you too, man! You have never heard of Magog before? Really, you kids are getting cheated on your education, you really should register a complaint! But really, Magog Cartel is serious business. This name is many centuries old, and as I’m sure you know, history that sticks around that long is likely to take part in the future at some point. Just be careful how much digging you do, this council of powerful financiers have a way of making problems disappear, so don’t be a problem, if ya know what I mean! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, I was just wondering in Munch’s Oddysee there is a huge skeleton bone in the Paramite Run stage, I was just wondering if you could clear that one up… There is no creature in Oddworld that big that I have seen yet… Is that Searex I have heard a little about ..and one more question please…if Oddworlds’ next game isnt going to be Munch’s Exoddus then what the next installments purpose to the Quintology? Thanx for the chat. Catch some tea some time else. – Daniel", "answer": "You are correct. It is a creature that you have not seen yet. And the purpose of the next installment in the Quintology is the same as the others. The whole thing isn’t about Munch, it never was! Abe would be really hurt if he heard you say that! ", "tags": ["Abe", "Munch"]},

{"question": "What kind of life exist on other continents of Oddworld other than Mudos? Now I know thats a pretty deep question but have you seen other continents of Oddworld other than Mudos?From a loyal fan and hopefully one day a future conceptual artist Paramiteabe …(“-“)", "answer": "Dear PA. I am content with the confines of Mudos and my cozy Rehab for now. I know there is more out there, but, well, most of us are pretty lazy and not really interested too much in anything beyond our own backyards right now. If I hear anything, I’ll let ya know! ", "tags": ["Mudos"]},

{"question": "I’m getting Munch’s Oddysee for my birthday and I can’t wait. Any ways, I would like to know if there is a Slog queen and will we see slogs with machinery like robotic arms in future games thanx for your time", "answer": "Wow, Happy Birthday! Slog Queen? I don’t know. I guess slogs have to come from somewhere, though I always thought they probably just evolved from a stank-nasty cesspool. If the Glukkons or the Vykkers found a good use for Slogs with robotic arms, I am sure that they would build them. I’m not gonna be the one to bring it up, though. ", "tags": ["Glukkon", "Slog", "Vykker"]},

{"question": "I have a question to ask you about the glukkons. Here’s the question. W hat would happen if Mullock came back? Hope you answer my question. May Odd be with you!Cody", "answer": "I have an answer for your question. Here is the answer: If Molluck came back, everyone would know, as his stench precedes him! Besides, Abey wouldn’t let that happen, not in a bazillion years!!!! ", "tags": ["Molluck", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Hey, Alf, how come you haven’t recognized as a hero like that bigshot Abe? And what exactly does BigFace have to hide? A facelift gone wrong maybe? See ya, Robman. ", "answer": "Well, lets see. Abe saved the entire Mudokon race and destroyed a majority of the corporations taking advantage of Mudos. I make tea. You do the math! And let me tell ya something about BigFace: he’s got a big face! And a big heart! So don’t you go talkin’ ’bout Mr. Big that way! He’s gotta wear that mask because he’s so beautiful you couldn’t bear to look straight at him! Your eyes would shrivel up like used spooce! ", "tags": ["Mudokon", "Abe", "Mudos"]},

{"question": "Hi Alf, I have a question. I read that Sam (the Mudokon Queen) is the mother of all Mudokons. So, who is the father? -VaniLLaKiLLah", "answer": "Well, uh, Sam isn’t exactly a one Mudokon kinda gal, if you know what I mean … and by “you know what I mean”, I mean, he is really a they, and they are DRONES. Creepy, huh? ", "tags": ["Sam", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Hi Alf! I wanna ask u what is ur Rehab tea made of? Thx Shen", "answer": "Well, there are several recipes, but they all have one ingredient in common: Alf’s tender luvin’ care! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Yo Alf, I have a few questions for you. First of all, what the hell is that thing on a slig’s face? I figure you would know the anatomy of a slig from your years of the beating them silly. I thought it would control their pants, based on the wires leading to them, but crawling sligs have them too. My next question is probably a FAQ, but I’m too lazy to check. But why are Abe’s lips stitched together? Was it a sick plan the gluks thought up to keep him from communicating? If that’s the case, it doesn’t work too well. And the last one is, why did you get the rehab and tea center? Why not Abe? He may be a goofy schmuck, but he’s the savior. Not that I think you’re undeserving. So don’t hurt me. ", "answer": "Yo, lazy, I was gonna answer your question until you started insulting my abilities as the Rehab and Tea Proprietor. Abe may be some kinda savior, but he’s no genius, and his entrepreneurial capabilities are, what some might call “lacking”. Besides, if he were tied up in the Rehab, who would save the species? You? Pssssh! ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "I have trouble staying odd so please help me. ", "answer": "1) Get Odd 2) Stay Odd 3) Lather, rinse, repeat. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey there fellow chimp … err champ (no offense), it’s me again and I have just one question for ya that I forgot to ask which it will be; whatever happened to the flying sligs? Anonymous", "answer": "They flew away! Badump Bump … ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf at the risk of repeating myself, I am in desperate need of another fix of that amazing creation called ODDWORLD. Is there anybody out there that can help? I have tried the doctors but he told me he didn’t have anything strong enough. I don’t know what I can do. I need to get hold of the next dose before I go completely insane. Is there anyone who knows where/ when/ how? Kind regards your most desperate fan Shane, ", "answer": "Dear Shane, I have heard of people with your desperate condition. Perhaps you should visit the Vykkers’ , wherein a headport that beams constant Oddworld content over a special frequency can be implanted in your noggin. Otherwise, have a sip of tea and quit yer whinin’. ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "I was wondering what Sam the Mudokon queen looks like. If she is the mother of all the muds will that make her huge like a termite queen or is she the same size as the rest of her family. Please sent a picture or describe how she looks. Thanx bud. ", "answer": "Yes, she is one huge motha! She’s never had her picture taken; our current megapixel technology just isn’t mega enough. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Just have a few questions for you… while I was reading “Dear Alf” I saw that one of your answers was; “Have you ever seen a female mud? Bluckhhhaaaaaaaa! They aren’t as attractive as you think!” My friends and I have been wondering for a while what do female muds look like? ", "answer": "Like nothing else on Oddworld! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "… And could you ask the coolest guy in the world (Lorne Lanning) to show a picture of a female mud on http://www.oddworld .com? ", "answer": "I’m not gonna cause it would ruin your eyes or something! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "… Also, I don’t want any crap saying that you’re not gonna cause it would ruin my eyes or somethin! ", "answer": "Oops! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How come in Abe’s games he doesn’t need spooce to take control of someone but in Munch’s game you do?", "answer": "Transmedial spoodiosis, coupled with the realtime continuum. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "In Munch’s Oddysee, glukkons say “how am I gonna pay the rent?” If they have no arms, how do they ever pay the rent anyway? ", "answer": "This is going no where… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Please send your reply to my email address instead of Alf’s rehab and tea", "answer": "Oops! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey, how do you reply to our emails? I may be wrong, but I’m pretty sure Mudokons don’t have computers. Does the Almighty Raison do it for you? Somehow? He is Almighty after all. ", "answer": "Almighty indeed! It takes a little finagling, some garden hose, half a pint of mojo and a little thing called imaaaaginaaaaation. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "HI! My name is Stephen F. from Sussex in England. I Love ODDWORLD so much I even bought a XBOX so I could get ODDWORLD:MUNCH’s ODDYSEE and I do most of my class work on it. (If I get the chance.) I also draw comics of it! Any way I have a plan that will boost your success! Have you thought of using famous actors? Well here’s some suggestions: (these actors come from the U.K.) Richard Br yers, David Jason, Robert Lindsy, John Cleese, Dawn French and Rowan Atkinson. Bye Alf! ", "answer": "Hi Stephen! I am glad that you are such a big fan! I can’t really agree, because I would probably be banished from Mudos forever if I didn’t say that our creator Lorne Lanning’s character voices are superior to all others. Although, one of the actors you mentioned seems just perfect for a particular role. ", "tags": ["Lorne Lanning", "Mudos"]},

{"question": "Hi ! I’m search on the web, the soundtrack of Oddworld series. Have you got a CD contains these musics ? I like there !!! Could you to be send a copy at my home ? Thanks.", "answer": "I’d be happy to send you a copy at home, if we had a soundtrack out! Of course, we’d love to do one, but then again, there are a lot of things that we’d like to do! For now, we are just concentrating on making games. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hello Alf. I am Xercon, a Jr. Executive Glukkon working for FeeCo Depot. Coulld you tell me more about my great boss, Aslik? Also (Aslik says he’ll promote me if I get this right) where is Abe hiding these days. Oh yeah, that Slig behind you hates you and will shoot the second I say the word!!! (Evil Laughter). Thanks for your time. By the way, you should be scrubbing decks, NOT answering fan-mail! Have a good day! – Xercon", "answer": "Hello Wanna-be-Exec Xercon. Your great boss Aslik has the breath of a thousand donkeys. He can reorg a company with one deft wave of a pen, and likes his hourly latte with extra fat and foam. Don’t start counting your moolah yet—I’ll never tell you where Abe is. Do I look like some kinda dumb chump to you? Don’t answer that!!! Now, don’t you have some papers to collate? I’m sure if your boss found you writing fan mail to a Mud you’d be demoted to Sloggie Chow pretty quick ", "tags": ["Slog", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Hows it going in oddworld? I jusy have a few questions for you: When will you get your own game? did Meeche’s have temples like scrabs? do slogs, srabs and parimites have queens? and do elums have a queen? From Oddball_Zim …(“-“)", "answer": "Alf’s my name, tea makin’s my game! So what’s with all the hierarchical, philosophical, religious questions? Eh? It”s not polite to discuss such things in mixed company! Besides, very little is known about these wild, beautiful and elusive beasts anyway. Maybe because if you get anywhere near one you’ll be reduced to tooth pickins! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey alf, thanx for putting my last question on your website I appreciate the thought, so to thank you I have some questions about your precious tea and rehab place and they are: Do you use spooce as one of the secret ingredients for your tea or do they taste soooo bad that spooce don’t get your sign of approval? and besides tea will you put up a juice & rehab to go with your tea and rehab?", "answer": "Anonymous: Spooce tea would probably taste like mud and money pie. Do you know how many people have touched a dollar bill by the time you get it! Ack! Can someone please bring me my sanitizer!?!!! The mere thought of it gives me an infection. As for juice, I can’t be bothered with all that squeezing. Do you know how hard it is to squeeze a piece of fruit with a mug in one hand and the other on the keyboard? I’d have to employ something with more arms, then there’s that mess with social security, workmuds comp…. Headaches I tell you! Headaches! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, I have finished Abe’s Exoddus (saved all 300 Mudokens) and the weirdos told me I find out about Abe’s Mudoken mother when I meet Munch in the next game. I finished Munch’s Odysee with all Mudokens and all Fuzzles saved and still no one tells me anything about Abe’s mother. Can you fill me in? Raven", "answer": "The journey of Abe and Munch is not over. The only place we can find out more about Abe’s mother is in…. the future! ", "tags": ["Munch", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Hello Alf! I’m a little new at this but I hope it wouldn’t hurt if I ask a few questions. thanks!   Gerald ", "answer": "Well Gerald, I don’t normally do this, but it is a slow month and I shall be answering ALL of your questions! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "1. What made all you native people and the industrial punks hate each other in the first place? (Was it a BIG disagreement between the mudokon queen and the glukkon queen?)", "answer": "A: Excellent question! It wasn’t always like this. There used to be balance on Oddworld. But overpopulation caused fights over land, mates, resources, etc… and a great divide between the species. At first there was just fighting, fighting everywhere, but then even the dumbest of species realized how futile that was and slowly the militaristic clans became special interest groups, utilizing business as a vehicle for their goals. It’s no big surprise that those with the most war-like tendencies were the best at business. That’s how the riff between the tree huggers and the land muggers all got started. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "2. I noticed in Abe’s Oddysee and Abe’s Exoddus Abe’s voice changed. What happened?", "answer": "A: Puberty. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "3. I looked and saw one guy asked about an oddworld movie. If you are making an oddworld movie what will it be called?", "answer": "A: Um, I think we have to figure out the movie part before we name it. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "4. Finally, I read that the industrial punks want to find Molluck allive just to shoot him. What did Molluck do to make the other guys want to shoot him after the lighting bolt went to his head?", "answer": "A: Molluck didn’t get where he was by making friends and influencing people. He lied, cheated, back stabbed and stepped on whoever necessary to get what he wanted. He used fear-based management techniques. Now, what do you think? : ) ", "tags": ["Molluck"]},

{"question": "4.WHAT THE HECK IS A SEA REX??????????????????????? Bye! Stephen", "answer": "Bonjour Stephen! Wow, lots of people interested in the voice thing. Next! Kintos are a lovely shade of Burnt Sienna. Or maybe it is Raw Sienna. Can I get an artist in here? PDD! Here PDD! (whistle) Come here boys! Oh never mind. They’re brown. Irwin and Humphrey? Of course they love each other… they are best mates ; ) A Sea Rex is a mysterious and elusive creature that, out of respect, I shall no longer speak of. The more who know about it the less likely the species is to survive. Au Revoir! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, I wanna know why Abe has a red and black hairdo. You can see it real clearly on the Abes Oddysee front cover for PSX. See ya, Robman P.S. Don’t say he just did the haircut because I know that ain’t true.", "answer": "Duh! Red and black are the hottest of haute couture! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, are sligs from the wild or are they made by Glukkons? Please reply ", "answer": "Sligs are not made by Glukkons. They are born in captivity and leased at birth as corporate security personnel. Only their “gear” is manufactured. They are given mechanical pants or wings, batons, tear gas, various types of weaponry, but are never taught to use any of them all that effectively. They are easily impressed and even misled by anyone who sports larger or more exotic weaponry than their own. Status is very important to Sligs. ", "tags": ["Slig", "Glukkon"]},

{"question": "“Hey there fellow chump!” “How’s it hangin'” Recognize any of these phrases from “Munch’s Oddysee”? ", "answer": "No. Not at all. ; ) ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Well I finally have an Xbox and I’m playing the game like it’s my child. I’ll start by reasking a question I have previously asked. When Oddworld Inhabitants finish with the Oddworld Quintology, will they move on to some multiplayer Oddworld games like racing games, fighting games or even party games?", "answer": "I think when Oddworld finishes the Quintology, a new one will be started. Or maybe a Heptology or a Quadrology … ooooh, maybe a decology! Possibly an Alfology! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Now I’ll ask two new questions.Kind regards your most desperate fan Shane. ", "answer": "Must you? I’m getting weak! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Are sligs evil because Glukkons force them to be? And that somewhere on Oddworld there are some nice ones? ", "answer": "No, they aren’t evil all because of the Glukkons. It is also typically thought that Sligs are malicious and sadistic at birth. This is not true either. The callus nature of a Slig is the result of parental shortcomings. Deprived of their early needs, they grow hardened to the ways of their reality. What could have turned out to be a race of sensitive, loving creatures, has in practice been perverted to become the most reliable clan for the contracting of dirty deeds. If left alone, Sligs talk to themselves to cope with their loneliness. ", "tags": ["Glukkon", "Slig"]},

{"question": "Can you give us any info on you said you will make when you have the money? ", "answer": "Money info give cannot saying what you are I know not sentence structure of because bad and words missing probably. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hiya Alf! I’ve been wondering just who came up with the idea of the game’s setting as a meat packing plant. I myself looove the looks of refineries and big factories how they have so many pipes and big somke stacks and there’s lights everywhere and there’s huge machinery. A lot of people don’t except the person who made the setting of the game. So what I’m saying is who came up with the idea of putting a meat packing plant as a setting and why? Your BIGGEST fan, Mike.", "answer": "Well there, Big Mike, I’m happy to hear that you think the structure which enslaved and later snackified my brothers is so visually appealing!!!! Who could think up such a demented and horrible place? Lorne Lanning, that’s who. Luckily he also thought it would be cool to have a saviour to lead us out of that Odd forsaken bung hole. ", "tags": ["Lorne Lanning"]},

{"question": "dear alf, everyone else e-mails in to see pics of muds, about technology and that sort of stuff…but we on the other hand…have seen real mudokons…and are on a quest to save them…though it is VERY DIFFICULT…especially when 1 in 10 will not pay the slightest attention to us…being a mudokon yourself (elssacecon bow to you) could you tell us how to approach these shy and very fast mudokons… – THANX- ElSsAceCon xxx", "answer": "EISsAceCon, All you need is bait. Try offering those chumps some tea or brew and munchies! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Amazing Alf, I was wondering…What ever happened to the flethches or what ever they were called? Will there be an “Oddworld: Munch’s Exodus”? How come in Abe’s Oddysee the Scrab’s attacked each other and they don’t in Munch’s Oddysee? Will we ever see a female character? Will there ever ba a “Slig Army”? Thank’s for your time …(“-“)", "answer": "Since most fleeches get flushed when they become too obnoxious for their owners to handle, you can find most of them hanging out in the marshes, lakes, sewers and forests of Oddworld. I don’t recommend going and looking for them, though. You know what they say, two heads are better than one! especially for chomping an innocent bystander! Oddworld Munch’s Exoddus? Read the FAQs. I’m sure that in time some of the female characters of Mudos will be revealed. A slig army? I doubt it. They are highly social and easily misled by those with larger weapons than their own. Can you imagine the chaos just of setting up the chain of command? Madness! ", "tags": ["Munch", "Mudos"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf, I have a few more questions if you don’t mind. If all of your eggs are shipped to factories how come there are so many wild Mudokens? Also are you a wild Mudoken or did Abe save you? Also if its not asking too much could you have Abe open a bird portal to Earth? My bags are even packed already! From Oddball_zim", "answer": "Dear OBZ, Well, there were Mudokons around before the eggs were shipped, so you do the biological math! I myself am a worker class like Abe. I will see about the bird portal thing. Maybe we could switch houses for a week or two. You can run the rehab while I lounge in your cabana just off the keys. You do have a cabana just off the keys, don’t you????? ", "tags": ["Mudokon", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Alf, if Abe and his fellow Muds can survive really high falls than how come in Abes oddysee and exoduss you cant survive them, you just die. ", "answer": "Well, if you drop a super ball from an airplane, it ain’t gonna bounce back to you. Everyone and everything has its limits. Mudokons are no exception. ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf my favourite mud, I wanna know why the sligs and glukkons don’t get afraid when Abe starts chanting to posses them in Munches oddysee. One more thing how come in Munches when you posses a glukkon you cant kill him by self disrupting him. Thanks for your time Alf buddie.   ", "answer": "Well, actually, by possessing a Glukkon, you ARE “self-disrupting’ him. If you want to kill him, or make him self-destruct, that is another story. Personally, I think it is more entertaining to play with their minds. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf Why are Glukkons profit crazy and evil? Were they born bad? Christopher ", "answer": "It’s part genetics, part environmental. A little bit country, a little bit rock and roll. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi Alf! I got a few questions for ya. What happened between Abe’s Exoddus and Munch’s Oddysee? How much time was there in between them? A few days? Weeks? How did Abe come across the Almighty Raisin? Do Big Face and the Almighty Raisin know each other? Did they meet before Munch’s Oddysee? Will Big Face return in the next Oddworld game? Okay, so its more than a few questions but only one more question. In the opening movie for Abe’s Exoddus where you and Abe first get into Necrum Mines, did the Mudokon push Abe off or did he fall? If the mudokon did push him, were you that mud? Thanks Alf!", "answer": "Between AE and MO? Well, let’s see, there was the big one, then my downward spiral into black tea drinking, the goat tee phase, my cubist period, my blue period, my lack of punctuation period (spawned by the internet), and then the inevitable feta and avocado on flatbread period. Odd how I love flatbread. It is like bread, only satisfyingly flat! Ok, so that was probably more information than you wanted, but just one more useless tidbit: I may or may not have pushed Abe. Those memories are foggy, very foggy!!!.. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "1. Are you going to be making an online/multiplayer game somewhere in the future?", "answer": "Hmmm!. Good idea! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "2. Why don’t mudokons steal sligs guns after they’ve been killed?", "answer": "If it won’t open a can of brew or change the channel, most muds aren’t interested. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "3. If the mudokons and native forces overpowered the glukons, would sligs fight agaist the mudokons, retreat or join them?", "answer": "They’d wet their mechanical pants. Sparks would fly. Electrical shocks would occur. Many an already wasted life would be lost, and Mudos would be a happier place. ", "tags": ["Mudos"]},

{"question": "4. When the Playstation 3 is released in a few years, would you make games for it? The Official Australian Playstation 2 magazine said that some of the wiring in the console is thinner than human hair!", "answer": "Human hair? Big whoop! Now if it were thinner than a Mudokon eyelash, now that would really be something! ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Thanks for your time anyway, and keep up the good work! from Hawk the slig. ", "answer": "Aaah, whatever! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "“hey ALf! I was wonderin’ if you could give us fans any info about the kinto slaves, octigi, gloktigi, meetle and mug? Also could you by any chance talk to the webmaster about starting a page for ideas for the games that were never used in the final version. Thanks, Kendall ", "answer": "Hi Kendall, I can’t tell you much about them now, but pretty soon you might be learning more. I tried to talk to the webmaster about games, but that chump is always at the massage chair or the coffee shop! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi, long time no sneeze… See! Ehm, I was wondering what the reahab is like late at night when the young muds go home to sleep. Do you serve brew? (Yes, I know that’s the whole point of the tea, to heal muds from brew…) becuas in that case, you could sell them tea afterwords… I think you almost must do this Alfie, sense all mudokons know brew is bad, AND Soulstorm is blown to pieces… So therefor you must have yer own secret brewery, to keep the customers in, to buy tea. Otherwise I have some aditional questions.", "answer": "You are the man that invented the deodorant that makes you sweat, the breath mint that makes breath smell bad, the acne gel that makes you break out, the diet soda that makes you fat! You are an evil, evil man! But I respect your ingenuity and will answer your questions accordingly. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "1: Why did Mullock start the Employe of the year thing? They are slaves after all. You know what I think? I think Mullok had a bigger heart than you think :p", "answer": "Molluck started Employee of the Year for the same reason all companies do: To instigate competition among employees which will, in theory, encourage all to work more. More working makes more products, more products makes more sales, and more sales makes more moolah, more moolah, more moolah!!! ", "tags": ["Molluck"]},

{"question": "2: How did you get to earth from Oddworld? Sense you are using a earthly email address and Internet does not go out into space. (Do not skip this question do to explenation of satalites… etc)", "answer": "How do you know? Have you been to space? Huh, smarty-shorts? Don’t mock what you don’t understand! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "4. (3 was a bad question): When is E3, and how long time will pass after that untill the information and movie clips are on the net? (Hopes for a Munch 2: Leaked Alpha version 😉 …not) ", "answer": "Yeah, no kidding. I can smell #3 from here. It’s almost as bad as #2. E3 is over and there are already movie clips and information on the net. Just not about the new Oddworld game. Nice try sucka! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf i have two questions iv been dieing to ask you 1 is: on Abes Exoddus why didnt you listen 2 abe when he told you not to dring the brew when you knew what a hero he was and that he had saved 99 modokons from rupture farms. And another is: why do scrabs and paramites and other creatures attack abe on sight, do they have a natural instinct to kill mudokons or something ur greatest rehab attendent KIT", "answer": "Uh, we all drank the brew, even Abe, until he saved us and I started the Rehab. Get it straight! If you are a rehab attendant I oughta have you scrubbing latrines! Scrabs and paramites attack because they are hungry, like most wild animals they have to eat, and if the food wants to play chase, even better! ", "tags": ["Scrab", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Is this Alf im not sure. Well i got ?’s. When does the Shrink appear and will Vykkers be in the next odd game? Also… how come you scare me? j/w. buh-by", "answer": "It’s me, unfortunately. Just to try and salvage some tiny, itsy bitsy smaller-than-human-hair fragment of my reputation, I will tell you that it is highly likely that the Vykkers will play a role in the next game. Not for sure, but probably. Why do I scare you? Are you also afraid of other tea makers? Do you have issues with Rehab? Why do people come to me with their personal problems? I don’t have time to deal with this slogwash. ", "tags": ["Vykker"]},

{"question": "1. At the end of Oddworld: Abe’s Exoddus, was Abe at your Alf’s Rehab and Tea party?", "answer": "Oh yeah, me and Abe party together all the time. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "2. What made you join Abe in his journey to SoulStorm Mining Co.?", "answer": "Well, I thought about hanging around to become a tasty treat, but I really felt my skillset was better suited to the escapee and rehabilitation industries. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "3. Personally, what do you think of the Glukkons?", "answer": "Personally, I think they are kinda cute. In an evil, greedy dastardly kind of way. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "4. What do Meeches look like and what do they do?", "answer": "I don’t know, but they sure were tasty! Those were good questions. What’s your angle? Are you an HR Director? Get outa my rehab, infidel!!!!!! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, I gotta question (obviously). In the end of Abe’s Oddysee, Shrykull fries everbody in the Magog Cartel conference room. If they are all dead, how can they still be terrorizing Oddworld? —SLIGcatcher.", "answer": "One word: Progeny. NEXT! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "HI Alf it is me Grant hows life on oddworld? thank you for repling to my last e mail i just whant to know were did Elum and how are those greddy glukins so dangers if they do not have arms or wepons? Oh one more thing do you know what the next oddwold game be called and when is it comeing out? your odd friend —Grant", "answer": "Life on Oddworld is sublime and I am loving it. Elum is out to pasture and the Glukkons use the most terrifying weapon known to Muds… their wallets! And I know nothing of the next Oddworld game, except that there is one. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "I haven’t played Munch’s Oddysee – I haven’t got an XBox – but I have read what I can about it. I’ve noticed in one review that at one point you get chased by a herd of scrabs. A herd of scrabs?! Shouldn’t a herd of scrabs rapidly become a smaller herd of full scrabs and then down to one exceedingly fat scrabs? Mind you, there must be some way that they can interact peacefully in order to procreate. I’m really curious to find out more. Please enlighten me. …(“-“)", "answer": "Well the procreation doesn’t have to be peaceful. Of course in our fairy tale minds we want it to be but it isn’t always so. As you may know creatures often act completely different in large groups. The larger the group, the stranger things get. Hey, wait a minute, why haven’t you played Munch’s Oddysee? I don’t have time for this drivel! Poof! Be gone! ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Hello Alf! What about a re-release of Abe’s Oddysee, and Abe’s Exoddus on Xbox, so i can toss my old Playstation away!??? Thanks for a great games series!!! Hi from a big fan in Norway! (“,)", "answer": "Great idea! I will tell Bill. Cheers Norway! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "1.What kind of Natural Resources are there down in OddWorld?", "answer": "We’ve got fossil fuels, water, dirt, plants and spooce. All kinds of great stuff that you could live off of for centuries. Barring any money-mongering industrialists, that is. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "2.How come just about every industrail character works for the Glukkons?  ", "answer": "Glukkons are very powerful. Not the most powerful, but it’s kinda like the top of the food chain. Or the high rungs on the corporate ladder. Or the pointier part of the pyramid system. They’re almost at the top, so most of the others are working for them, in some form or another. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "3.If you wanted to make a t-shirt with OddWorld’s logo’s and stuff on it, do we need to get your permission and how? ", "answer": "Do I look like Matlock to you? This is Dear Alf, not some courtroom drama show. Send legal a note at fanlegal@Oddworld.com ", "tags": []},

{"question": "4.Is there big giant oceans in OddWorld and can you ~possibly~ show them in the next game?", "answer": "Yup and Maybe, respectively. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "5.What sports are in OddWorld?", "answer": "Great question. We’ve got the normal stuff, you know, Meep Tossing, LaCross the Scrab Herd, Running, Sneaking, Spooceball, etc…. ", "tags": ["Scrab"]},

{"question": "O.k., so that’s more than a few questions ~sorry~ but please respond back to them! ttyl! bye!", "answer": "Don’t be sorry, be odd… and STAY ODD! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, My question is while I was browsing the Oddworld site i stumbled upon a picture that said Fud TV. What is Fud TV? And, unless it appeared in an earlier game and I missed it, will it appear in the next game? One of your biggest fans, Mike", "answer": "Mike, FUD TV is the station that unearthed The Bones-Brew Connection and attempted to make it public knowledge. The circumstances surrounding their success and their whereabouts remain in question. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "dear alf I know im just an ant in a world of things to you, but as a fan i wonder so much about the next odd world game. and im sure you get tons of e-mails about it, and magazines bothering you like crazy, and what not. i just think tomyself… what could be cooking up for the next game. i havent herd a single thing about it. does it invalve munch? is it funny like munch’s oddessy…. or kinda darker like odd abb’s 2 tittles. well i cant wait to know. keep up the wonderful work. and let the fans here to good word!! thank you. —John", "answer": "John! You are not an ant! A slimy, light-fearing cockroach maybe, but not an ant! As for the next game it is still in the oven. Did you see the Discovery special? You really have to check it out, it’s all the rage. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "To Whom it May Concern: I hope I sent this request to the right address; I was wondering who was the voice actor for the Sligs in Munch’s Odyssee? I realize he acted for several characters in the game. I traded Odyssee last year so I couldn’t look up the credits, but I still remember his work on the game and a few words came to mind: entertaining, humorous, and talented! I hope he will be available to make a contribution to your upcoming games for the Xbox. Thanks for your time! Sincerely, Brian ", "answer": "Brian, I really hope that he can contribute to the upcoming games as well, because the voice talent for the Sligs was none other than our very own Lorne Lanning, President and Creative Director of Oddworld Inhabitants. He’s the brain behind ALL of this crazy stuff! ", "tags": ["Oddworld Inhabitants", "Slig", "Lorne Lanning"]},

{"question": "“Yo alf i was just thinken with Munch around will oddworld be the same Oddworld is never the same, always different, always Odd! ", "answer": "All I can say is it’s probably going to get Stranger. ", "tags": ["Stranger"]},

{"question": "Hey,I was wondering why you aren’t going to put Oddworld out on Playstaion because the first two games are on Playstation? And when are some of the Oddworld movies going to come out? And for my final question, When you sign up with the fan club do they send you mail like letters or do they send you E-mail. Oh YEAH!One more question, how longdoes it take for the mail to come? thanks,Alf! ", "answer": "Munch’s Oddysee was an Xbox exclusive because the Xbox has superior harware capabilities and is easier to program for. If you want a more detailed explanation, you can look up the November 2000 archives for a statement from our President and CEO. I don’t know when the movies will come out. Could be a while, though. Movies are a big process! When you sign up for the fan club you will get an initial mail letting you know the form you submitted worked, then I will send you mail very, very sporadically. Hey—it’s a work in progress! As for mail, it is a fickle system that often results in people accusing me of not sending anything. Whatever! ", "tags": ["Munch’s Oddysee"]},

{"question": "Wazzup Alf! How’s bussiness for you in the Rehab? You should have a question of the month or something like that. That would be cool. I have 2 questions, please answer them! Thank-you. See you around! —Anthony", "answer": "Oh boy. Questions. I can hardly wait. Hold me back. Hold….me…….back. Hey—did he just call me round? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "1. What are the requirments of becoming the fan of the month?", "answer": "You must never have asked, “What are the requirements of becoming fan of the month?”. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "2. What kind of meat is in the meat sacks? ", "answer": "Mystery Meat. You may have tried it at your local cafeteria. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "1. Who is the Chronicler, and is he the one who writes the “storydweller” story stones?", "answer": "The Chronicler is an accountant. He doesn’t have anything to do with writing. He’s a left brainer. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "2. Will any of the Oddworld heroes actually meet the queens? I’ve seen pictures of them, well apart from Skillya… ", "answer": "You saw pictures of them? I am so, so sorry. I mean I know I can be a little sarcastic at times, and well, maybe a bit rude and cranky, but no one should be exposed to that level of punishment. On behalf of all the Inhabitants, again, I am so incredibly sorry. Really. Oh Odd, how could this have happened………. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "3. Do you have any plans to give PS owners Munch when a better console comes out, PS3 for example? Because it would be able to handle the grapihcs etc. If not, I think you should listen to that idea, it would make many fans happy!", "answer": "Nope, no plans. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "A dedicated fan, drakan90", "answer": "Do you make that cologne? Drakan Noir? Good stuff. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, I was wondering about Abe’s Mom. At the end of Abe’s Exodus, it said that the next game would introduce her but you never see her in Munch’s Game? What gives?", "answer": "What gives? No one gives anymore. It’s just take, take, take! Besides, why would ABE’s mom be in MUNCH’s game? That is what I would like to know! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Oddworld-Web: Abe hey this is abester i have 3 questins 1 will abe be in further games 2 will elum be in further games3 howcome you and abe like never have a pet like a scrab or paramite or fuzzles or are elums and meetles your pet", "answer": "1. Maybe 2. Maybe 3. Pets = waste. Alf doesn’t do waste. Hey, you gotta draw the line somewhere. Dear Chris, You are in luck my friend! You can visit the Rupture Farms catalogue at http://www.Oddworld.com in the November 2002 archives. Outdated you say? Nay my friend… outstanding! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Does Phleg have acromegaly?", "answer": "Ok, lets not kid ourselves. The real question is, “does Alf have to look acromegaly up in the dictionary?” Well the answer is yes, as a matter of fact I do, as that is a very obscure medical reference that I personally have no interest in. The answer to the other, more superfluous question is no. Phleg does not have acromegaly. He just has a severe case of egostroke-e-osis. Oh yes. That, my fellow buds, is what I call linquistics in action. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Not to bother you again. I was curious… is this one person, or a thing where a bunch of people use one name and answer the overabundance of fans who have pointless questions. (Chuckles), sorry. Um, thanks for your advice. So how did you get into this job? Oh, and could you, er….will you send information on the new oddworld game? I missed the sneek peek on the discovery channel. I love oddworld games. They are so original and mindblowing. It would be cool to meet the creator, and tell him how awesome he is, and that there are a lot of kids in Troy, Illinois who love these games, and cannot wait for the next installments. Anyhoo, any pics that you can send, and info would be much appreciated! Thanks again! Love and light! —Randy", "answer": "Randy, please my friend, bother away! It is merely I, the Alfster, knower of little, teller of less. How did I get this job you ask? Well, it all started with me and Abe in the desert. If you want to know more, study your games! Thanks for the love and light, but I can’t tell you anything about the next game. I have to leave you in the dark on that one. Har har. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "—Petit (Yes, I am female )", "answer": "Hey there chuckles, Sorry about deleting your first five questions, but at Alf’s Rehab, Alf’s the only one who gets to be excessive. Them’s the rules. So, #6: Mudos is populated by a whole slew of native Mudokons, all of different tribal background and heritage, each with their own unique customs and manner of dress and uh, makeup. The entire Mudokon race is indebted to Abe for his actions. ", "tags": ["Abe", "Mudos", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "is there going to be any new characters in the new game??? …(“-“)", "answer": "Yup, new game = new characters. Woohoo! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, I was wondering who it is who does all that wacky Oddworld art? Could it be just the “production designer” Farzad Varahramyan (yes! I spelled it right!). Or is it the “game designers?” I don’t know, do you?", "answer": "Well, you’re a good speller, but your info is a little watered down. Over the years Oddworld has employed many talented art-folk. Right now we have a team of three production designers: Raymond Swanland, Silvio Aebischer, and Gautam Babbar. They are all super talented, each in their own right and are slaving away, pencil in hand, right at this very moment to keep the art flowing. Now, the Game Designers are equally as talented, but they do something entirely different! They plan out the logistics of the game, make it fun and functional, and although they may be closet artists, that’s not the talent we harvest from their bountiful minds. At least not yet….. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi Alf I have a couple of questions. 1. in the upcoming game do you play as abe or is he out of the storie. 2. Also does the latest game still have the same type of gameplay.", "answer": "Uh, no, no, and sorta but not really. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "3.I dont have an X-box is there a default in them.", "answer": "Hand on Odd. Heeheeeheee! No. There are rumors about Hand of Odd, but we’re not working on that right now.Your second question, quite frankly, confuses me. I guess if you were talking about a score of 1 through 10, I would have to say a 7. After all, I’m not in it- how good could it possibly be? And yeah, there are a lot of defaults in the Xbox, but then, consumers have their defaults, too, right? Your second question, quite frankly, confuses me. I guess if you were talking about a score of 1 through 10, I would have to say a 7. After all, I’m not in it—how good could it possibly be? And yeah, there are a lot of defaults in the Xbox, but then, consumers have their defaults, too, right? ", "tags": ["Hand of Odd"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf dude, Thanx for posting my question a few months ago! But here comes another one: All these inhabitants like Skillya, Sam, Chronicler, Accountants, meeches, etc. seem to be known by everyone except me! Where can I find pictures, info and stuff about them so I’m not behind everyone else anymore? —Raven", "answer": "Well Raven, I am glad you asked! Just flap, flap, flap your little wings on over to the Universe section of http://www.Oddworld.com and you’ll be schooled properly on all the necessary Oddworld characters. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "HI! I love your games,I have Abe odyssée and Abe exoddus at home,in Abe odyssée,I am escape 77 Mudokons and in Abe exoddus escape 339 Mudokons. I love Abe becose, the fart and in my family the farts is a tradition.Ok that`s it.Oh! Wait.Please tell Abe for me:Good luck Abe for the next adventure on Oddworld!!!!!!!", "answer": "Hm. Wow. That is just way, way too much information. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I was just reading the article in gameinformer magazine about the next oddworld coming out. And all I’m wondering is why? Is Abe going to be in the game at all. He has been the star of the past three games, well sharing the role with munch. Please give a more in-depth explanation if at all possible. A concerned gamer —Erik", "answer": "Dear Erik the Concerned, Don’t be concerned, dude. Abe is just worn out and needs a rest. And aren’t you just the least bit interested in what other characters inhabit Mudos? I know I am. I mean, it’s foolish to think that Mudokons are the only species out there, right? We can’t be the only ones……….. ", "tags": ["Abe", "Mudos", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Hello, Alf! I’m Eduardo, and I am Brazilian, so, if you can read this, tell me, and I will send more questions. Will you guys release one RPG game of Oddworld some day? I love RPGs, and it would be very good to see Abe, Monch and all of those folks in one RPG game. Eduardo ", "answer": "Hello Eduardo! An Oddworld RPG? I wouldn’t rule it out, but we definitely aren’t working on it at the moment. The focus right now is on that Stranger you saw on the Discovery Channel. ", "tags": ["Stranger"]},

{"question": "“Dear Alf, As much as I love Munch’s Oddysee so far, I find myself missing the old 2D gameplay of the first 2 games. Has the idea of making a 3d oddworld game on a 2d track (a’ la Contra: Shattered Soldier or Duke Nukem Manhattan Project) been kicked around at all? I felt that the main reason that I liked the first 2 Oddworld games were that they were beautifully done 2d games in an era where the industry was moving into 3d, they kind of showed that 2d still has it’s place in the industry. And now with Oddworld and Castlevania as well going 3d I’m wondering if 2d is actually heading out to pasture for good. Thanks in advance for taking the time to read this. Oh, and regardless of my preferences for gameplay I just wanted to congratulate the folks over at Oddworld Inhabitants for creating a world with so muchh beauty and depth. Thanks again, Kenny", "answer": "Well first of all, thank ya from all the Inhabitants! That is a huge compliment. As much as we all love the first two 2D games, (you aren’t the first to point it out), the background of the founders of Oddworld is steeped in 3D tradition. Sherry and Lorne both come from the 3D effects industry, and are always looking for new challenges and ways of expressing the Oddworld story. So the goal is to eventually move into 4D and 5D, where in real time is actually REAL TIME, and you can actually taste and smell everything, creating the first-ever, fully functional immersive video game experience. Oh, and did I mention that I don’t play games? So I don’t have a clue what I’m talking about. But wouldn’t that be sweet! Possibly even sour…… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, I’m thinking of getting Xbox Live and I was wondering whether the next Oddworld Title will support it. If it’s still undecided or under-wraps, that’s fine. Anyway, thanks for your time. SLIGcatcher ", "answer": "Uh, I choose B. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Good tidings to you Alf old bean! now i have to admit i was a bit slow off the mark getting Munches Oddysee….and i love it…but!….i finished it in under a week!…dude whats goin on! the first 2 games i was stuck on for weeks on end…but i love how theres more then 2 ways to solve the puzzles…that fact i like muchly..gimme something to sink my teeth into man!!! just 1 more question tho……..Do the sligs have a Workers Union? —Dom", "answer": "Wow, I’ve never been referred to as a bean. I feel kind of, well, pretty and cute, and sproutish. Unlike those dirty, rotten Sligs. Union? Puhleaze. The closest sligs will ever get to anything resembling a union is their relationship with their pants. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Hi Alf, my name is Alex and i´m from germany. So, my english isn´t the best! 😉 Question: How was the graphic in the three games made? I mean, is it “2D-Pixel-Art” or 3D-Rendering? Or a combination? Best wishes, Alexander.", "answer": "Well, the first two games, Abe’s Oddysee and Abe’s Exoddus were 2D side-scrolling platformers, and Munch Oddysee was a 3D platformer. ", "tags": ["Abe’s Exoddus", "Abe’s Oddysee", "Munch"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf I have one question in the last level of Munch’s Oddysee when you had to fight all of those armored Sawbones with the Mudarchers were those elums on the table with there head cut off or some new odd creature that we havent seen yet please write back and thanks for your time your odd little friend, Cody", "answer": "Yeah, you’d think having a flatulent rider on your back all day would be the worst, but sadly, most Elums endure a fate far less enjoyable. Oddys, Don’t be ridiculous, your English is far better than most Americans’! Honestly, I don’t know for sure yet if Abe or Munch will be in the next game. I do know that it will take place here in Mudos, though. And yes, we hope to one day make an Oddworld movie. For the love of ODD pleeeeeease make that movie soon, people! Oooops, did I actually write that? I’m a little anxious, that’s all. ", "tags": ["Mudos", "Munch", "Abe"]},

{"question": "thanx alf, ElSsAceCon xxxx", "answer": "EISlongobscurenamedontfeelliketypingitalldangit, If I could be any animal on Earth it would be a Bulldog, where I could lounge at my master’s feet on a soft pillow of tartan plaid and sup the finest Earl Grey from a gold-rimmed puppy bowl and be referred to as “such a good lad”. Regarding Big face: he wears the mask as religiously as the wife of a tv evangelist, my dears. On the clumsiness of sligs: you’d trip too if you had to learn to walk (let alone run) in metal trousers! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "bye sucker, opps ,I mean bye wise one! ", "answer": "Dear Foolish Mortal, oh, I mean foolish fan, oh, I mean best buddy, oh… nevermind. Something about your mail utterly intrigued me. Prezoomed. Presumably, it means to zoom beforehand, to zoom ahead of time, which is a paradox, because zooming ahead would mean to move forward, but can you actually go forward in a pre-zoom state? I am utterly stumped at this abstract concept, so much so that I cannot continue with the laborious task of answering any more questions, including the ones in your mail…. Now it’s off to think and drink…………….. tea of course………… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I know this is a bit overdue but I finally got an XBox and MO yesterday. Before I was a PS2 fan but XBox is seriously miles better! To be honest I wasn’t expecting much of Munch’s Oddysee but I was blown away! It’s brilliant. The standard is right up there and I can honestly say it’s my new favourite Oddworld game. The levels are well done and the character interaction / gamespeak is incredible. I haven’t finished it yet but I am thouroughly enjoying it! Well done Oddworld and good luck with Steef. I am really impressed with Munch! —Drew the Slig", "answer": "Drew, You are such a nice Slig. What is wrong with all the other sligs? Why can’t more sligs be more like you? Have I told you lately that I love you? Ooops, sorry, that’s the tea talkin, ma boy. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "hi i am a first player of the oddworld games… i have recently bought munch’s oddyessy and am very pleased with what i see on the xbox, which got me thinking why arent the other games on this platform??? why would u switch consoles? this puzzling question is bigging me, because i wold really like to play the previous two so that i truly know the story of ABE. if u could shed some light onto this question of mine id be very happy ~thanks, Andrew", "answer": "Andrew, I’m so glad that you are enjoying the games! And you want to play the other games on Xbox? This is the most refreshing thing I have heard of since Mango Iced Tea! It would be great to move AO and AE over to Xbox. Of course, that would be enough work for an entire development team and would probably take a few years… If we did it the fans might get angry at us for not moving forward, after all, we are but a tiny little development studio… but if MICROSOFT did it… hmmmmm… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Is there any chance that one day Oddworld will produce a game, in which, there is a time of peace that allows players to further explore the immense environments only partly explored in the previous games? I find myself wanting to know more about Oddworld and would very much like to explore it in depth. This is, of course, just a fan based idea and I know not how well it would sell in the international market. Well, thank-you for your time, congratulations on your amazing concept and I hope to see Abe and the gang again soon. Your devoted, loyal fan; A. Scott", "answer": "I am so pleased to hear how much you enjoy Oddworld and our environments. Peace and exploring, um, sounds like a wonderful idea but seems like it would make for really boring gameplay. However, the powers that be at Oddworld do want you to be able to explore and get to know Oddworld better. What form that exploration takes could be a number of things. A game, or ????? We shall just have to wait and see. In the meantime, it is good to know that true blueish-greenish folk such as yourself are excited about the future of Oddworld! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "1. Did you purposely put contact info there to make it hard to find", "answer": "Ha! If you thought finding the email was hard you should try getting a straight answer from me! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "2:   I’ve heard about the reason that you cut Abe’s finger off, but how did you get that dismal digit off the moon?", "answer": "Fans that ask too many questions. And shovels. Lots and lots of shovels. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "3: Why do the makers of all the facilities in AO and AE put so many pitfalls and traps for their slav- ahem, employees to get killed in.", "answer": "Well, if an employee is already injured or worse, it is much easier for them to “become one with the product” IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN WINK WINK. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, Is true that Abe or Munch is somehow related to the Steef species?", "answer": "Well we’re all brothers and sisters in Odd, right? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I read the opening page (last month) and it sounded as if the company was shutting down or something. Can you let me know if thats what is happening? Maybe I’m just reading it wrong but it sounded like something is wrong. Thanks for your time. —Chris ", "answer": "Chris, Let’s just say that if I read the fan mail the way you read the website, uh, well, actually things wouldn’t be that different. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, I’ve noticed that in Munch’s Oddysee that there are labels for Soul Storm Brew on the vending cans. What’s with that? —The Ultimate Munch Fan, Ann", "answer": "I asked around and even though SS brewery was destroyed the brew was warehoused offsite and is in plentiful supply. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hello again alf! Raven here asking if you could clear up a few questions: Why haven’t we heard/seen/smelt/watever anything about Abe’s mother even though the weirdoes (dead mudokens with bones missing) promised we would know about her when we met munch? They say it when you finish AE with 300 muds saved.", "answer": "I’m sure the Weirdos believed that was true, but she’s nowhere to be found and it’s pretty frustrating for everyone involved. Makes the Weirdos look like a bunch of nut cases, or at least more so than usual. Diversion tactics of a barely lucid and irresponsible mother, in my humble opinion. Poor Abe. As if he hasn’t been through enough already. ", "tags": ["Weirdos", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf I wish to discuss these questions, By the way I’m Stephen! Will there be another game before the Steef guy pops up?(such as Munch’s Exoddus.)", "answer": "Stephen, There shall be nothing but many strong cups of tea and arduous, strenuous, flatulous work before this game “pops up!” ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will Abe and Munch be in the Steef guy’s game?(You can’t have a Oddworld game without Abe and Munch! It would be like Gerbils without hellium!)", "answer": "Sounds to me like one more reason to send them on vacation. I care little for gerbils and less for those who abuse the elements! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What are those new chicken characters called?", "answer": "I know a couple of them characters. Bawhnee Sue McUgly. Unkle TurkeyToes. Kind of an annoying group if you ask me. Whiny. Loud. Always scratchin’ and flappin’ and carryin’ on. And not too bright either. Old Bawhnee Sue sure does make a mean cornbread, though! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Why do Sligs need masks? Bye!", "answer": "To get to the other side! HA! Ooooh, wrong joke. Pass the tea please, no no, the one that smells funny. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "dear alf why did the modokans let the glukkons walk all over them ?.why should they be slaves?. ", "answer": "The mudokons are a peaceful species with simple desires such as brew drinkin’ and the toob watchin’. Unfortunately, addiction and ignorance made them much more susceptible to being taken advantage of. Hence that whole degradation of the species/slavery thing. Besides, what would you do if a tentacle-mouthed freak with mechanical pants and a big gun told you to work? YOU’D WORK, that’s what! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, Couple of questions, Who do you hate most of the glukkons, Dripik, Aslik, Phleg and Lulu? I’d say Lulu. He’s a doof.", "answer": "Lulu is a doof, I agree, but it doesn’t make me hate him. I rather pity him, and his poor sense of fashion. He’s just an empty pawn in the bigger scheme of things. If we’re gonna talk pure loathing, Dripik ranks pretty high on my list. Most chumps I can just laugh at, but Dripik is downright bad. It ain’t even funny. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Who do you like more, Tomahawkers or Murdarchers or Scrubs?", "answer": "Scrubs—they are so down to Oddworld! Hey, this is fun! Let’s do another! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Who do you like more? Bigface (abes oddysee), Weirdos (abes exoddus) or Shaman (Munches oddysee) and why?", "answer": "The Weirdos hold a special place this old muds heart. They have spared life and limb they still find time to drop in and help their buddy Abe. And I love their shiny glowing colors. Reminds me of the time I got lost in that field and had to eat strange bulbs to survive… ", "tags": ["Weirdos", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Who is Crig the slig? ", "answer": "Crig is a legend. He spends his days hangin’ with Sasquatch and swimming with Nessy, and hiding from La Chupra Cabra. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Which slig do you like best? Mollucks assistant Toast, Lulus assistant Valet or the newscaster and why?", "answer": "Newscaster. He’s got style, joie de vive. Is that the last one? I wanna go home now! Mommy! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "HI man! It is so good to email U! ok I’ve a few questions to ask you. In Mo how can you tell which scrab is the alpha scrab?", "answer": "He’s the one with the big red letter “A” on his chest. Oh wait, maybe that means something else.. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "is elum in Mo? I haven’t got that far butt…or is he i the new one?", "answer": "You might see some of the Elum scattered about, in a manner of speaking, but Abe’s Elum has retired. And please don’t use that type of language around here anymore, I mean really. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "is there any cheats ?", "answer": "Yeah, but what do Poker swindling Inhabitants have to do with the game? Eh? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf, (I am russian, sorry about my bad english) I have rescued all the mudokons in first Abe’s game (99) and in second Abe’s game (300). I have a question: why Abe have a sew up mouth, but all the others mudokons have not sew up mouth?", "answer": "When Mudokons were just little hatchlings, they had their mouths sewn up to hush them. It isn’t done anymore, since they are now free, but Abe keeps his as a symbolic reminder of his past. ", "tags": ["Mudokon", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf, Who or What is Steef??? I see people send in email saying good luck with steef… But I am completely in the dark when it comes to this “Steef”. Please help me… Phot", "answer": "Well Phot, I don’t know much about him myself. He’s very strange. I hear he smells like a dickens and has bizarre grooming habits.. but who am I to judge? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi there Alf, could you tell me whether Mudokon ponytails are made of feathers or hair? I thought it was definite they were feathers, but as I’ve discovered, there’s no official word on the matter and the fans seem to be split evenly between the two ideas. Cheerio, And may all the Inhabitants have a very merry Crimbo (if I haven’t actually mistimed this and sent it in the middle of your break…) Max", "answer": "Thanks Max. Right back at ya. Mudokon ponytails, you say? Why, they are made of sugar, spice, and a bit-o-lice! At least that’s what mummy always told us! *scratch scratch* ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "hi alf ElSsAceCon all 4 of us r as odd as ever so we wondered everyone thinks aliens are cats what do you thinnk about that? could an oddworld creature be a cat on earth? we think so we also (regarding someone elses question) believe that there is a portal on earth thanx alf oddly ElSsAceCon xXxXx", "answer": "Sorry to disappoint but I would never want to venture off of this glorious planet we call Oddworld. Not even as a cat. Tempting as that may seem to some… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "hey Alf! How is Soulstorm Brew? Me and my lazy Mud friends have never gotten wasted so we wanna know. And hey, you should go and eat some lone glukkon’s head. He’s got no arms! He can’t defend himself! Anywho, now for a real question, you seem to hate Abe since you’re bitin off his fingers and pushin him into holes, why do ya follow him when he calls? Odd bless you -the Maxokon", "answer": "Firstly, I never bit Abe, so get it straight, bud! And regarding that whole well incident, I was never convicted of anything—I happened to be going in for a pat on the back the moment he jumped. So wha? And finally, the call of Abe is, unfortunately a biological phenomena that no Mudokon can ignore. You might say it’s programmed in. ", "tags": ["Abe", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "I ran into a Alpha Scrab the other day and it seems I misplaced my arm. is there any place i can go to besides Vykkers labs? I don’t want a chunk of aluminum in my head, unless it’s a TV remote. ~ I misplaced my name too.", "answer": "Wow. I hope you have good insurance. It’s really hard to find limb donors these days. Maybe you should just get a new name and call it even. How about Unimud? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Stay odd Alf. That is all for now.", "answer": "Hey there fellow chump, you’re very welcome! Abe isn’t really all that scary. Ever. Even when he’s chanting. The chanting used to come easy to him, back in the day, but now a little spooce sure helps. You know what they say, “Spooce does a body good!” And even though he is pretty fly for a bluish-green guy, I don’t think I’ve ever seen flies on top of his head. ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "Wait I got 1 more questions if you don’t mind. You know how muds have they’re limit with jumping, I understand but the jumps that Abe can’t survive in the first 2 games weren’t that high of a fall and in Munches oddysee the jumps or falls were a higher distance, so how come Abe can’t survive those falls in the first 2 games(no offense to Abe or any mud I just wanna know). Stay odd Alf, that’s all for now.", "answer": "The spooce gives Abe increased elasticity and, uh, sproingability. I can’t believe you didn’t already know that! ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "1) Was Molluck a Big Cheese or a Glockstar?", "answer": "Well it’s sort of hard to say. He may have had some of the credibility and respect of a Glockstar, but his foul odor would lead me to believe was big (however rotten) cheese. Yes, I’ll go with Big Cheese. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "2) At Rupture Farms, the Mudukons were processing huge carcasses, of creatures too large to be scrabs. What where these?", "answer": "Probably Elums and whatever other quasi-meat products they could find lying around. At Rupture Farms, no carcass goes unturned. Waste not want not! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "3) Shrykull is half god, half Mudukon. Does that mean that there is some kind of God out there that vaguely resembles Shrykull? If so, did the ancient Mudokons worship it/him?", "answer": "Yes, a half-god that was worshiped from 9-12, then took the afternoons off to lay around and drink brew. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "4) After the Scrabanian and Paramonian nests, the doors had a large stone sculpture that resembled Big Face’s mask. Are they the same thing?", "answer": "It’s not the actual mask but it is a sculpture of said mask. Darn that Bigface, he’d have his mug all over mudos if he could! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "5) V.P. Aslik’s shoulders are smaller than Dripik’s and Phleg’s. Is he a lower status glukkon? Also, is the Brewmaster Glukkon a lower status?", "answer": "There’s definitely a chain of command, a pecking order so to speak, when it comes to the Glukkon uppity-ups. While Aslik and Brewmaster may not be part of the upper upper echelon, they sure come in handy when blame is in need of a transfer! ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "6) On the back of the Abe’s Exoddus book, there is a picture of a Mudukon spraypainting on a wall. He is also seen in the opening credits of the game. This mudokun is blue, with orange bloodshot eyes. He has no tattoos, so I’m pretty sure he’s not Abe. Yet the other Mudokons are green, with white or yellow eyes. Are blue Mudokons more common than suggested, Albinos, or is this guy just someone who also happens to be a mystical saviour?", "answer": "Well the lighting is pretty bad in that particular area, I mean, how can we really be sure who it was? He didn’t have a fez on, did he? I mean, what difference does it make? Who’s the victim I ask you! Who is the victim! Why is everyone always trying to accuse me? It’s not graffiti, it’s ART! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "7) The Oddworld logo: Does it mean anything, or is it just a cool-looking random thingy.", "answer": "The Oddworld logo is an O, a W and an I. We call it the jewel logo because it looks like, well, a jewel. Sherry likes purple, so that’s pretty much where the color came from. Not too long ago, the logo was revised. A circle with the name of the company spelled out was added to the jewel logo. We use this one in instances where the logo needs to “read” really well. But sometimes we still go back to the jewel, just ‘cuz we think it’s so darn pretty! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi Alf Its Daz. I was wondering if you and your fellow Mudokons have benefited from the Magog cartel or their technology at all? Either using Glukkon suits as carpets, those nice meat drills from Rupture farms as burglar traps, anti-chanting orbs for pratical jokes or least slig pants as a new way of bringing your tea to you without leaving your seat?", "answer": "Well, if by benefited you mean being kept as slaves to mine our own bones and have our lips stitched up then yeah I guess so. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "2. When will the next oddworld game be released? ", "answer": "Alpha scrabs tell regular scrabs what to do and how to do it! And I’m not tellin’ anything about the next game! Not for all the tea in Mudos! You can’t make me! I–will–not–be–broken!!!!! ", "tags": ["Mudos"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf, My name is Robert and I was wondering if you could tell me about the Mudoncho Vaults. I know that it is a temple in Necrum like the Mudanchee and Mudomo Vaults and that it used to be home to many meeches (before they were all extinct). But I was just wondering if you could tell me some more about it? Thanks. ", "answer": "Mudoncho?! Well I know it has been a long time since I was down in Necrum, and I’ve had a lot of brew since then, but I sure don’t remember any Mudoncho Vaults! Maybe you got all hot and flustered from wearing your poncho? Or perhaps you ate a bad batch of nachos while in the mines? I hear the snack carts there are a little less than reputable. Watch it! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey Alf, I have a query regarding something in Munch’s Oddysee. In the Brewery To Be region, there stands a lone windmill. Found on the outside walls on the windmill are a red symbol. This symbol is neither the Mudanchee, nor the Mudomo symbol, yet it is designed in the same manner. Could you tell me what the symbol stands for, or whom it stands for (is it possibly the Mudancho symbol)? Thankyou, Alcar… ", "answer": "Alcar! You’re killin’ me man! Is this a coup? Are you forumers messin’ wit my mind? I hearby decree that from this moment forward, none in my Rehab shall speak of the imposter vault known as Mudoncho! As for the symbol, it is a graphic representation of a Scrab, end of story! Mudancho! Puhleaz. ", "tags": ["Scrab"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf, When I was nine, the Oddworld quintology just started, ever since then, I was addicted. Every mudokon was a wonder to me, and to this very day this question haunts me: Why does Abe have his hair in a tail, instead of being tied up, why are his lips sowed up and why does he have yellow eyes? I’t seems kind of– Odd — don’t ya think? —levihydra10009 ", "answer": "Aw, that is so sweet! I love it when we can turn a mind so young so odd. Really warms the heart. Ok, enough of that emotional stuff, let’s get down to business. Abe’s hair is in a ponytail for a very simple reason. Have you ever seen that show, “When Factory Work Goes Bad?” Trust me, you don’t want your hair getting caught in one of those machines! Always, ALWAYS wear a ponytail! Abe’s lips are sewn up from the old days when no one wanted to listen to him cry. He keeps the stitches as a symbol of his past. As for the yellow eyes, I’m gonna have to go with genetics on that one my friend! ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "1) Abe has his mouth stitched shut to prevent him from praying, I know that, but has it happened to other Mudos, having their mouths stitched, stapled, or (in poor zulags) sellotaped shut? ", "answer": "Hey there buddy! Um, well, I just got finished talking about the stitches. And yes, other Muds have been stitched up, but as far as I know no one has ever been stapled or taped! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "2) Are Fuzzels cuter Fleecehes?", "answer": "Yes, Fuzzles are certifiably cuter than fleeches. But the fact that they are cute is a bit of a paradox, when you take into consideration their other side, what with the gnawing of flesh and all. Fleeches, however, are not cute in any way and don’t have the depth to their personality that fuzzles do. ", "tags": ["Fleech"]},

{"question": "3) How come you are reading, (on your picture) with an electric light, hmm?", "answer": "What are you talking about? My light is powered by adorable little bugs with glowing bums! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Dear Alf What is a meetle? Coz you mentioned one before.", "answer": "A Meetle is a huge, roundish, hard-shelled creature with four deadpan eyes. They sure are cute as larvae, but they grow up to be rather, well, more for function than fashion lets say. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi Alf.It’s Brad.I have a few things to ask you. If Abe and Munch are friends,then how come the fuzles growl at Abe and how come the Muds laugh at Munch?", "answer": "Fuzzles are a lot like little dogs, in that they will choose an individual to bond with. They are capable of bonding with others, but this alpha figure in their lives becomes the primary source of attachment. Since Munch is the one who rescued them, they feel particularly close and downright protective of him. Some who don’t know better may even see Abe as a threat, just because he is different from Munch. ", "tags": ["Abe", "Munch"]},

{"question": " Are muds primitive?", "answer": "There are many different groups of muds. Most of us that you’ve met so far would be considered primitive by definition. Of course, I myself am HIGHLY evolved, but I, of course, am the EXCEPTION due to my tremendous tea making abilities. Now I will impart on you a secret. I have always sensed that there are parts of Mudos that you and I have never been to where muds of all kinds have reached varying heights of civilization! ", "tags": ["Mudos"]},

{"question": "PS: Is there a central diety in the Mudokon faith, or does your race revere nature itself?", "answer": "I think that you will learn much about new species, and a little bit more about the species you have come to know and loathe. This game will give you insight into the hierarchy of the no-good-do-ers. The setting is still in Mudos, but you will see parts of it that you never knew existed. And frankly, I am a bit put off that you have the nerve to attempt a discussion on religion in mixed company! How dare ye! ", "tags": ["Mudos"]},

{"question": "Ever since I finished Oddworld Munch’s Oddysee the second time this question has been bugging me … or couple o’ questions … whatever. Why is Munch’s moon upside down? I mean all Abe has to do is put his hand up to his moon to line it up while Munch has to flop on his stomach and brake his neck to try and match it up if he’s not dead first. What do you have against the little guy? Unless … his foot was on backwards and I just didn’t notice. I guess Munch’s moon makes up for it for being bigger than Abe’s. Sorry if you find this e-mail offensive in anyway even though I may have offened you hundreds of times by now. – Fuzzle", "answer": "Howdy Fuzzle. You’ve never seen this, but when he is feeling frisky, Munch will often lay on his tummy, little flippity foot up in the air, and crane his neck around to see the print line up with the proper appendage. Quite adorable really. And I wasn’t offended until you assumed that I would be! The nerve! ", "tags": ["Munch"]},

{"question": "I recently beat Abe’s Oddysse for the first time (I said I was new). Through a weird computer fluke of some kind, I managed to do it with 100 mudokons. I had been lead to believe that, if I had saved all of them, I would get a special movie with the Shrink in it. Judging by your website, the Shrink looks fairly cool, and I hope he appears in future games. I did not recieve this movie. I got the special movie menu, but no bonus movie. At first, I thought “Maybe if I only save 99, I’ll get it.” That didn’t work either. Could you tell me what I’m doing wrong? Thank you. ", "answer": "What you are doing wrong is looking for the shrink … he’s not in any of the games or movies. The clip you are referring to is a commercial that was never broadcasted. This is what happens when people (or appliances, or whatever) come to the rehab and act all shrinkety-dinkety! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will OWI never create anything but Oddworld Games? Just curious.", "answer": "We only create games from Oddworld. I think. Your wiley verbiage is throwing me off. I can’t be held accountable for other peoples whack-glish. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "I heard there is a Abe’s Exoddus (which I haven’t played yet) movie (something about short movie showing. Nominated for Academy award. I’ve seen movie posters, so I know it exists somewhere. But I have had no luck in tracking it down at all. If you could help me at all, I would be very thankful.", "answer": "Yes, an animated short was submitted for consideration to the Academy Awards, and was shown in a theatre in order to do so. Unfortunately, I cannot help you track it down. As far as I know, the only copy is tucked safely under the cushion of my recliner. I’d lend it to you but it’s all warm and covered in crumbs! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will Munch’s Oddysse ever be for a pc computer? I don’t have an Xbox.", "answer": "Nope! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will Hand of Odd be for Computer?… Please … Well, thank you for your time. Keep on being Odd. —Andrew", "answer": "Neeeooowwwellluhahhaaaaaauhm, we’re not even in production for OHOO. How am I supposed to answer that???? ", "tags": []},

{"question": "In AO and AE, Abe’s eyes are white, but in MO, his eyes are yellow. What happened two him?", "answer": "After all the brew was gone, ol’ Abey switched to lem-odd-aide. He drank gallons and gallons of the stuff. Turned his eyes a freakish shade of yellow! Now he has to use those special strips to try and whiten them again. Well, at least that’s the way I heard it! ", "tags": ["Abe"]},

{"question": "In Abe’s Exoddus at the end, Abe says he would save the green Muds, but We never played as Abe saving them, so has Abe rescued them without us? —levihydra10009", "answer": "Sure. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Did Munch ever handle all those baby Gabbits?", "answer": "I think he is still looking for a can opener. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "At the End of MO, The fuzzles destroy Vykkers Labs. Were the Fuzzles destroyed, and were Tex and Lulu destroyed (Cos I like Tex) —Stay Odd, Nathan.", "answer": "Fuzzles are virtually indestructible, though if necessary they’d certainly give their furry, fangy little lives for the greater good. The problem is, they all kinda look alike, and the fuzzle-to-English translater is still on sabbatical, so we haven’t really been able to ask around and see who made it out yet. As for Tex and Lulu, well, you know the problem with synthetic textiles is that they tend to heat up pretty quick. I doubt they made it. If they did, I bet they’d have permanent sparkle melded to their greedy bodies! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will the Whole quintology be on Mudos? After the quintology is finished, will future quintologies still have stuff to reveal on Mudos or will they move on to the other continents.", "answer": "Yes, I believe so, but Oddworld is a big planet. I don’t know about future quintologies. That is pretty far off yet! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Do you know of any different breeds of slogs?", "answer": "Why yes, there are several. Are you ready? There is the Hot Slog, the Bird Slog, the Muddish Setter, the Hound Slog, and of course the Snoop Sloggy. ", "tags": ["Slog"]},

{"question": "What do BigFace and the Almighty Raisin think of each other?", "answer": "Well I asked them for you. Almighty Raisin thinks Bigface is a little-faced mud-fink. Bigface thinks Raisin is an almighty windbag with a sleeping disorder and a pound of denial in every wrinkle. Bottom line is that respect each other. ", "tags": ["Raisin"]},

{"question": "How much wood could a woodchuck chuck could chuck wood?", "answer": "You mean IF a woodchuck could chuck wood? I think it’s highly unlikely, but FOUR. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Will Crig the slig ever appear in a game? (or has he already?) – From Tomohawk", "answer": "Yes. Crig the Slig appeared in AO and AE. You’d be surprised – he’s awfully shy. He currently is a field reporter for the Daily Deception. ", "tags": ["Slig"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf, i have been a big fan of Oddworld since i discovered Abe’s Oddysee just before Abe’s Exoddus came out. It was one of the many things that led to me becoming a graphic design student. I have gained much inspiration from Oddworld, and was deeply excited when I heard about this Oddworld art book. My question, after all that, is: will the Oddworld art book be available in the UK?", "answer": "Wow! That is awesome. It is always cool to hear that we’ve played some odd part in a person’s life, especially the creative part! Good luck with your design career! As for the book, it will be available for purchase from Ballistic Publishing. Visit their website at www.ballisticpublishing.com and you can sign up for email updates on the status of the book and ordering information. There may be other sponsored links at ordering time, but all points lead to Ballistic. Thanks for asking! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hi alf It’s Me again Eric(that dude with the Executive Glukkons Clan), I’m sorry to bother you again,but if hand of Odd is not on the Production Scedule how come i have 2 videos here where i see Hand of Odd gameplay(believe me I checked it) well I hope you have an answer sorry if I have botherd you. In case you want 2 check visit http://www.depthsofoddworld.com then click videos en page 1 “Tree Chop”,and “Tree Grow”", "answer": "Hey Eric, are you getting feisty with Alf? If so I will have to refer to myself in the third person, and you know Alf hates doing that! Hand of Odd is still not on the production schedule. I have been to The Depths Of Oddworld. I have seen the movies. I have the knowledge! Those movies are pre-Munch. There were several of those—visualizations of concepts for the game where we were looking at trees growing, testing wind (no, not that kind of wind, the fresh smelling one) and changes in seasons, daylight, etc. ", "tags": ["Hand of Odd", "Munch"]},

{"question": "Your Fan, masterdkp", "answer": "Masterdkp, Yes, actually, all the heroes do get a moon. Will Stranger have one? I do not know that yet. Abe and Munch may have been the first and last in that tradition. We’ll just have to play through the next game and see! I think of it as a kind of honor, such as having a bridge or park bench dedicated to you, only on a much grander, cosmic scale. ", "tags": ["Stranger", "Munch", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Hey Alf its Justin.I think it would be awsome if you guys at oddworld would create a oddworld action figure set! please..please……..PLEASE .. consider IT!!!!", "answer": "Yes! Action figures are way cool! Well, not in the sense that you’ll fit in with the cool kids at your school if you carry action figures around with you, but cool as in “I’m the lord of the geeks” kinda cool. And ours would be Odd, too, and that’s something! I would love to have Oddworld action figures, especially a little Alf with tea sipping action! Sip! Sip! ", "tags": []},

{"question": "This is the first time i asked a question so i made it a good one, firstly, which hand is the paramania and scrabania tattoo on, left or right, which is which. Second, is abe gonna be in future games because i would just die if he wasnt in anymore games because he is the main reason i play. third, i want to make an abe costume for a surprise for some friends of mine, any tips on how to make it or could you tell me who could help me, okay thats all?", "answer": "Scrabania on the left, Paramonia on the right. Stand up, sit down, fight fight fight! Yeah, sure, Abe will be back someday. I don’t know when, but someday. Costume: I don’t know, but one word of advice: keep comfort and safety in mind! No toxic paint fumes in the eyes or harsh chemical paints on the skin, ok buddy? ", "tags": ["Scrab", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Now its cool to know that you have a rehab, but thats not what I’m here for. The new game looks thrilling, and the graphics are heart stopping. But why is abe not in this game, and will orginal oddworld creatures be featured in this new game?", "answer": "Abe is on vacation, sipping non-alcoholic, low-carb, extra foam brew on the southern isles right now, and can’t be bothered. There will be some creatures that you’ve come to know and love through the previous games… we are still on Mudos after all, but I wouldn’t say that they are the feature or main focus of the game. There’s breed after breed of all new species for that! ", "tags": ["Mudos", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Yours sincerely, Fish", "answer": "Hi Fish, no, you sent it to the right place! That’s really cool that you’ve been a fan for so long. What has taken you so long to write?!?!?! The GameBoy version of Munch is not the same game that is on Xbox. I guess that’s the best explanation I can give ya. As for the next game, I love the title, “Stranger of the Hand of Odd”. That is great! Unfortunately, it is something drastically more simple. I try to tell the marketing folks, complicated and illogical is the way to go, but they just dismiss my ideas. Foolish hooligans! Anyway, don’t worry, you’ll get to see Stranger soon. ", "tags": ["Stranger", "Munch", "Hand of Odd"]},

{"question": "Hiya alf! I have a couple of questions (1 i was wondering what did you muds do with that blimp abe and his buddys hijacked from vykkers labs? you could start your own tour of mudos. and (2 in MO at the windmill area, there’s a huge skelleton the scrabs have been pickin at, what critter was it? that is way too big to be an elum. – yours oddly deadhead", "answer": "Dearest Deadhead, You are an enterprising young lad, are you not? The blimp has been totally tricked out with dancing teddy bears on the bow and tie-dyed sails. Munch and Abe took it on their vacation. Hm. Skeleton, huh? Bigger than an elum… it could be a beached Sea Rex, or a decomposing Meetle. I’ll have to investigate further. In the meantime, call animal control and get it cleaned up! ", "tags": ["Abe", "Munch"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf Why Is Abe Blue And his friends Are well You Know Not —Your Bud Allbadkids ", "answer": "So. Bud. You think you’re clever, with the “well you know not” thing. Ok, you are. You kinda made me chuckle there a little bit. Not tea spewing hilarity, but made me grin. So I will tell you, Abe is Blue cuz he’s the chosen Mudokon. He’s no ordinary Mud. Sure he looks like it, all chumpy and clumsy like the rest of us, but no, he’s special. Of course, they used to tease him about it when he was little, but not anymore! Ha! Who’s laughin’ now, ya not-blue mudokons!!! ", "tags": ["Mudokon", "Abe"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf(red/alfa/bert) my name is Andrew. I’m a big time fan of Oddworld, and am currently devising a website idea. But I have some questions for you.", "answer": "Ok An(drew/droid/cillary), shoot. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "1.) A very common misconception is that Glukkons have no arms. This is not true. Glucks have long, strong arms, which they walk on (use as leggs and feet), because their real legs are shrivled little worthless…things. I read the official Oddworld Bio for Mollock, and it said, walks on his hands, like all working-class glukkons. What I want to know is: is there a higher class of Glukkons that does not walk on it’s hands? Please explain, and feel free to go into exorbrint detail.", "answer": "Yes, there is a higher class of Glukkon but they still walk with their arms. General Dripik is pretty high up there. Glukkons aren’t wealthy but they have a little money. ", "tags": ["Glukkon"]},

{"question": "2.) As stated in Oddworld: Abe’s Oddysee, all the meeches are currently extinct. does this mean that, had they still existed, Abe would have had to go through Meecharnia, into the bowels of the Meecharnian Temple, even into the Meeche’s nest itself. And wouldn’t they also have had a Vault in Necrum (don’t worry, I won’t mention Mudancho…Shoot!)? Just wondering. I personaly am a little relieved, if there was. I don’t support extinction, but if all this stuff existed, and the meeches were still around, I’d have had to go through the aforementioned areas. As I still have terrible memories of the Scrab’s and Paramite’s respective temple, it is a relief that they are all gone…but don’t get me wrong.", "answer": "Yes. (Note the brief clarity of the answer, how it contrasts with the question.) ", "tags": []},

{"question": "3.) Can you tell me more about the Shrink?", "answer": "Well he once was quite large, and then one day… ", "tags": []},

{"question": "4.) The mudokens in Necrum are supposed to be blind, so they can’t see what their digging up. But I’ve noticed (On the demo anyway), that a large number of mudokens you need to save can see perfectly fine. Please explain.", "answer": "Just cuz they can see doesn’t mean they can leave on their own. Ergo the term “slave”. Not all the Muds in Necrum are blind. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "5.) Why do the mudokens hold Scrabs and Paramites sacred, when on every encounter with them the aforementioned beasts try to kill them?", "answer": "Mudokons are a native species, and therefore revere the power and beauty of the Scrabs and Paramites. They have an understanding of each species place and purpose on the foodchain. ", "tags": ["Mudokon", "Paramite", "Scrab"]},

{"question": "6.) I can’t find Abe’s Exoddus anywhere (goodness knows, I’ve looked…hard). Can you give me a hand here?", "answer": "I get asked that question a lot. The game is darn near a classic, it is so old and hard to come by! Oddworld can’t recommend or endorse retailers, but you should try doing a hearty online search, and you may want to drop by the fan forums, where others might be able to make recommendations. Go to the newly redesigned industrial fan forums at: http://www.oddworldforums.net/ ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Hey alf. Umm.Uhhh.R u abez brother or something? O an y r u mudz skiny? Glukkonmaster. Sorry 4 bad spelling,im jst tird.", "answer": "Hello there. I am Abe’s brother in the sense that all Mudokons are brothers, but we aren’t directly related, if that’s what you mean. Are we skiny? Is this a combo of skinny and shiny? Because the answer is nyos! ", "tags": ["Abe", "Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Well I hope you reply. Thanx ", "answer": "Well, first of all there will be plenty of connections to the old games in Oddworld Stranger’s Wrath. You are definitely going to know that this is an Oddworld game. Just because Abe and Munch are MIA doesn’t mean we aren’t us. Trust me, that makes sense if you think about it! What could be more odd than the stranger I ask you???? Not much. There will be fuzzles, a Vykker, and all of the wonderful ways to smash, bash, slice and dice those arrogant enough to defy the forces of Odd. Yer gonna love it! And Joe, really, you should know by now why Abe’s lips are sewn shut- cuz he asked me too many questions! Har! Just kidding. As for movies and Co-Op play, all I can say is the future is both unknown and inevitable. ", "tags": ["Stranger’s Wrath", "Munch", "Abe", "Vykker"]},

{"question": "Why a western? What is up with that? I’m not really into that hokey cowboy stuff.", "answer": "“Western” is only one of the influences for OSW. Soon you will see more and more of the regions and levels, where much a much different landscape is revealed. The journey of the stranger takes him to all different climates and terrain. Snowcapped mountains, lush forests, riverside junkyards to name a few. He also encounters all sorts of folks along the way, with their own, how shall we say, “quirks.” ", "tags": []},

{"question": "Can you tell me the different ammo types and what they do? ", "answer": "There are too many to list here! But you can check out their feature at Gamespot.  Gamespot also has tons of info, screenshots and video downloads for your viewing pleasure. Check it all out and be the most knowledgeable kind on the block about an obscure quasi-western video game with a bounty hunter in it. I’m sure in some places this is the definition of popularity. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "What are some of the new species we are going to encounter in Oddworld Stranger’s Wrath? ", "answer": "Wow, there are a slew of ’em. There are the Wolvarks, the Outlaws, the Outlaw Minions, the Clakkerz, the Grubbs, Gloktigi and of course all of the live ammos. Wolvarks are kinda like security guards, but they are totally flaky and would rather nap than work. Of course they are meaner than all get out and you should avoid them at all costs. And did I mention that they’re ugly? Cuz they are. Outlaws are, well, just kind of what they sound like. They live outside the law and make the strangers life so difficult, and yet provide him with a career. I guess it’s that whole balance of nature thing. ", "tags": []},

{"question": "How come no one ever writes to you asking about the new game anymore? Are they tired of your meaningless spiels, your bottomless pit answers? You’re utter lack of decency? Have they completely given up on you? Do they not realize the veritable slogs trough of information that you have the potential to be? Shame on them. Shame.", "answer": "Gosh, I just don’t know. With the game coming out next month you’d think people would be dying to know. Seems like the only mail I get these days is those friendly offers to enhance my Mudokon-hood or get a lower interest rate on my rehab payments. Kind offers, really, but not very useful when all I want to do is blabber on about the game! ", "tags": ["Mudokon"]},

{"question": "Dear Alf i have got a question for you. What’s with this pre-order DVD of Oddworld movies?", "answer": "Hi there. I’m glad you asked! If you pre-order Oddworld Stranger’s Wrath “only the Xbox”, you’ll receive and “bonus” DVD right then, well starting Jan.1st. This dvd contains all the cg/fmv movies from past games and OSW too. Yes, there is an “extras” section. The bonus DVD will also be available in Europe. Check out your eagames.com website for more info. ", "tags": ["Stranger’s Wrath"]},

{"question": "Any chance of getting more info and pictures about the new GAME? thanx – Bounty guy. ", "answer": "Yes! Yes! Check out websites like Gamespot, IGN, Gamespy, EAgames and all the game magazines too. Look for features right now! ", "tags": []}]}